{
	"description": "Kanji entries marked as Common in JMdict minus words in the JLPT quizzes n2 or lower, minus words with any frequency rank under 8000 or no frequency rank in the VDRJ (Top60894 V1.1)",
	"deck": [
	{ "question": "あだ名", "answers": [ "あだな" ], "comment": "nickname" },
	{ "question": "按摩", "answers": [ "あんま" ], "comment": "massage, esp. the Anma Japanese type of massage\nmasseur; masseuse; massager\nblind person (as many were traditionally massagers)" },
	{ "question": "お手上げ", "answers": [ "おてあげ" ], "comment": "all over; given in; given up hope; bringing to knees; throwing up one's hands" },
	{ "question": "かき氷", "answers": [ "かきごおり", "カキごおり" ], "comment": "shaved ice (usually served with flavored simple syrup); Italian ice; Sno-cone; snow cone" },
	{ "question": "か弱い", "answers": [ "かよわい" ], "comment": "frail; feeble" },
	{ "question": "くじ引き", "answers": [ "くじびき" ], "comment": "lottery; drawn lot" },
	{ "question": "この間", "answers": [ "このかん", "このあいだ" ], "comment": "the other day; lately; recently; during this period\nmeanwhile; in the meantime" },
	{ "question": "すき焼", "answers": [ "すきやき" ], "comment": "sukiyaki; thin slices of beef, cooked with various vegetables in a table-top cast-iron pan" },
	{ "question": "すき焼き", "answers": [ "すきやき" ], "comment": "sukiyaki; thin slices of beef, cooked with various vegetables in a table-top cast-iron pan" },
	{ "question": "ちり紙", "answers": [ "ちりがみ", "ちりし" ], "comment": "tissue paper; toilet paper" },
	{ "question": "ばい菌", "answers": [ "バイきん", "ばいきん" ], "comment": "germ; germs; bacteria; mold; mould\nsomething harmful; vermin" },
	{ "question": "ひな祭り", "answers": [ "ひなまつり" ], "comment": "Hinamatsuri (March 3rd); Girls' Festival; Dolls' Festival" },
	{ "question": "ぶら下がる", "answers": [ "ぶらさがる" ], "comment": "to hang from; to dangle; to swing" },
	{ "question": "ぶら下げる", "answers": [ "ぶらさげる" ], "comment": "to hang; to suspend; to dangle; to swing; to carry" },
	{ "question": "やり直し", "answers": [ "やりなおし" ], "comment": "redoing" },
	{ "question": "やり過ごす", "answers": [ "やりすごす" ], "comment": "to let something (or somebody) go past\nto do too much" },
	{ "question": "よそ行き", "answers": [ "よそいき", "よそゆき" ], "comment": "going out\none's best (clothes, looks, manners, behaviour, etc.)\nformal behaviour (manners, speech, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "よそ見", "answers": [ "よそみ" ], "comment": "looking away; looking aside" },
	{ "question": "ケ月", "answers": [ "かげつ" ], "comment": "months (period of)" },
	{ "question": "セ氏", "answers": [ "セし" ], "comment": "Centigrade; Celsius" },
	{ "question": "ドラ息子", "answers": [ "どらむすこ", "ドラむすこ" ], "comment": "lazy son; profligate son" },
	{ "question": "バラ色", "answers": [ "ばらいろ", "バラいろ" ], "comment": "rose-colour; rose-color" },
	{ "question": "ビー玉", "answers": [ "ビーだま" ], "comment": "marble; glass marble" },
	{ "question": "ヵ月", "answers": [ "かげつ" ], "comment": "months (period of)" },
	{ "question": "ヶ月", "answers": [ "かげつ" ], "comment": "months (period of)" },
	{ "question": "一丁", "answers": [ "いっちょう" ], "comment": "one sheet; one page; one leaf\none block of tofu; one serving (in a restaurant)\none long and narrow thing (e.g. guns, scissors, spades, hoes, inksticks, palanquins, candles, jinrikishas, shamisen, oars, etc.)\none cho (unit of distance, 109.09 m)\none game; one task\nwell then; come then" },
	{ "question": "一世", "answers": [ "いっせい" ], "comment": "generation; lifetime\nthe age; the day\nthe First\nissei; first-generation Japanese (or Korean, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "一両", "answers": [ "いちりょう" ], "comment": "one vehicle\none ryou (an old coin)" },
	{ "question": "一丸", "answers": [ "いちがん" ], "comment": "lump; (into) one" },
	{ "question": "一人っ子", "answers": [ "ひとりっこ" ], "comment": "(an) only child" },
	{ "question": "一人娘", "answers": [ "ひとりむすめ" ], "comment": "only daughter" },
	{ "question": "一人息子", "answers": [ "ひとりむすこ" ], "comment": "only son" },
	{ "question": "一介", "answers": [ "いっかい" ], "comment": "mere; only a ..." },
	{ "question": "一代", "answers": [ "いちだい" ], "comment": "generation; lifetime; age" },
	{ "question": "一任", "answers": [ "いちにん" ], "comment": "entrusting" },
	{ "question": "一円", "answers": [ "いちえん" ], "comment": "one yen\nthroughout (an area); whole district" },
	{ "question": "一助", "answers": [ "いちじょ" ], "comment": "help; assistance" },
	{ "question": "一向", "answers": [ "いっこう" ], "comment": "completely; absolutely; totally\n(not) at all; (not) a bit; (not) in the least\nearnestly; intently; determinedly\nJōdo Shinshū" },
	{ "question": "一周", "answers": [ "いっしゅう" ], "comment": "a round; a circuit; a revolution; a lap; a turn" },
	{ "question": "一因", "answers": [ "いちいん" ], "comment": "cause" },
	{ "question": "一団", "answers": [ "いちだん" ], "comment": "body; group; party; gang; troupe; troop" },
	{ "question": "一堂", "answers": [ "いちどう" ], "comment": "one building (hall, temple, shrine, room)\nsame room; same place; same building" },
	{ "question": "一塁", "answers": [ "いちるい" ], "comment": "first base\nfirst baseman\none fort" },
	{ "question": "一室", "answers": [ "いっしつ" ], "comment": "one room" },
	{ "question": "一幕", "answers": [ "ひとまく" ], "comment": "one act" },
	{ "question": "一座", "answers": [ "いちざ" ], "comment": "party; those present; troupe\nfirst seat" },
	{ "question": "一式", "answers": [ "いっしき" ], "comment": "complete set; all; everything" },
	{ "question": "一戦", "answers": [ "いっせん" ], "comment": "battle; game; bout" },
	{ "question": "一手", "answers": [ "いって" ], "comment": "move (in game); method; single-handed; monopoly" },
	{ "question": "一打", "answers": [ "いちだ" ], "comment": "stroke; blow" },
	{ "question": "一括", "answers": [ "いっかつ" ], "comment": "all together; batch; one lump; one bundle; summing up" },
	{ "question": "一掃", "answers": [ "いっそう" ], "comment": "clean sweep; purging; doing away with; eradication" },
	{ "question": "一握り", "answers": [ "ひとにぎり" ], "comment": "handful; small handful" },
	{ "question": "一新", "answers": [ "いっしん" ], "comment": "complete change; reform; restoration; remodeling; remodelling; renewal" },
	{ "question": "一昔", "answers": [ "ひとむかし" ], "comment": "ages; long time; decade; the past ten years" },
	{ "question": "一晩", "answers": [ "ひとばん" ], "comment": "one night; one evening\nall night; overnight" },
	{ "question": "一本", "answers": [ "いっぽん" ], "comment": "one long cylindrical thing; one film, TV show, etc.; one goal, home run, etc.; one telephone call\none version\none book; a certain book\nippon; one point; a blow\nexperienced geisha\nsingle-minded focus on ..." },
	{ "question": "一条", "answers": [ "いちじょう" ], "comment": "one long straight object; streak; beam; ray (of light); wisp (of smoke)\none item (in an itemized form); one clause; one passage (in a book)\none matter (affair, event, case, incident)\nthe same logic; the same reason" },
	{ "question": "一派", "answers": [ "いっぱ" ], "comment": "school; sect; party" },
	{ "question": "一石", "answers": [ "いっせき" ], "comment": "one game (of go)" },
	{ "question": "一義", "answers": [ "いちぎ" ], "comment": "reason; principle; meaning\nfirst meaning; first principle; first consideration" },
	{ "question": "一翼", "answers": [ "いちよく" ], "comment": "wing; one wing\nrole; part" },
	{ "question": "一色", "answers": [ "いっしょく", "ひといろ", "いっしき" ], "comment": "one color; one colour; one article; monochrome\nsame tendency; everyone being caught up in the same thing" },
	{ "question": "一足", "answers": [ "いっそく", "ひとあし" ], "comment": "pair (footwear) /\n step\nshort distance; short time" },
	{ "question": "一躍", "answers": [ "いちやく" ], "comment": "suddenly (rising to fame, etc.); instantly; immediately; overnight\none bound; one leap" },
	{ "question": "一身", "answers": [ "いっしん" ], "comment": "oneself; one's own interests; throughout the body" },
	{ "question": "一軍", "answers": [ "いちぐん" ], "comment": "one army; whole army\nfirst string players" },
	{ "question": "一辺倒", "answers": [ "いっぺんとう" ], "comment": "complete devotion to one side" },
	{ "question": "一過", "answers": [ "いっか" ], "comment": "passing away" },
	{ "question": "一重", "answers": [ "ひとえ" ], "comment": "one layer; single; onefold" },
	{ "question": "一門", "answers": [ "いちもん" ], "comment": "family; clan; kin\nsect; school; adherents; followers; disciples\ngroup of related sumo stables" },
	{ "question": "一風", "answers": [ "いっぷう" ], "comment": "oddity; eccentricity; peculiarity" },
	{ "question": "丁重", "answers": [ "ていちょう" ], "comment": "polite; courteous; hospitable" },
	{ "question": "七夕", "answers": [ "しちせき", "たなばた" ], "comment": "Star Festival (held in July or August); Tanabata; Festival of the Weaver" },
	{ "question": "万人", "answers": [ "ばんにん", "ばんじん", "まんにん" ], "comment": "all people; everybody\nten thousand people" },
	{ "question": "万全", "answers": [ "ばんぜん" ], "comment": "perfection; flawlessness" },
	{ "question": "万国", "answers": [ "ばんこく" ], "comment": "all countries; the whole world; universal; all nations" },
	{ "question": "万年", "answers": [ "まんねん" ], "comment": "ten thousand years\neternity" },
	{ "question": "万引", "answers": [ "まんびき" ], "comment": "shoplifting; shoplifter" },
	{ "question": "万引き", "answers": [ "まんびき" ], "comment": "shoplifting; shoplifter" },
	{ "question": "万能", "answers": [ "まんのう", "ばんのう" ], "comment": "all-purpose; utility\nalmighty; omnipotent" },
	{ "question": "万里", "answers": [ "ばんり" ], "comment": "thousands of miles" },
	{ "question": "三塁", "answers": [ "さんるい" ], "comment": "third base" },
	{ "question": "三女", "answers": [ "さんじょ" ], "comment": "third daughter" },
	{ "question": "三振", "answers": [ "さんしん" ], "comment": "strikeout; strike out; fanning out" },
	{ "question": "三権", "answers": [ "さんけん" ], "comment": "the three powers of government (legislative, executive and judicial)" },
	{ "question": "三流", "answers": [ "さんりゅう" ], "comment": "third-rate; third-class" },
	{ "question": "三男", "answers": [ "さんなん" ], "comment": "three sons\nthird son" },
	{ "question": "三省", "answers": [ "さんせい" ], "comment": "frequent reflection (meditation)" },
	{ "question": "三者", "answers": [ "さんしゃ" ], "comment": "three persons; three parties" },
	{ "question": "上々", "answers": [ "じょうじょう" ], "comment": "the very best; excellent; superb" },
	{ "question": "上がったり", "answers": [ "あがったり" ], "comment": "doomed (business, trade, etc.); in a bad state; poor" },
	{ "question": "上げ", "answers": [ "あげ" ], "comment": "tuck (e.g. in a dress)\nrise (e.g. in price)" },
	{ "question": "上乗せ", "answers": [ "うわのせ" ], "comment": "adding; addition; extra" },
	{ "question": "上体", "answers": [ "じょうたい" ], "comment": "upper body" },
	{ "question": "上向き", "answers": [ "うえむき", "うわむき" ], "comment": "pointing up; pointing upward; upturn; uptrend; upward tendency" },
	{ "question": "上告", "answers": [ "じょうこく" ], "comment": "final appeal to the highest court" },
	{ "question": "上唇", "answers": [ "じょうしん", "うわくちびる" ], "comment": "upper lip" },
	{ "question": "上場", "answers": [ "じょうじょう" ], "comment": "listing (on the stock exchange, etc.); taking a company public\npresentation (e.g. of a play, opera); performance" },
	{ "question": "上映", "answers": [ "じょうえい" ], "comment": "screening (a movie); showing\nto screen a movie" },
	{ "question": "上演", "answers": [ "じょうえん" ], "comment": "performance (e.g. music, theatre, opera); staging" },
	{ "question": "上田", "answers": [ "じょうでん" ], "comment": "high rice field; very fertile rice field" },
	{ "question": "上申", "answers": [ "じょうしん" ], "comment": "report to a superior" },
	{ "question": "上積み", "answers": [ "うわづみ" ], "comment": "deck cargo; upper layer of goods\nextra\nto pile on top of" },
	{ "question": "上限", "answers": [ "じょうげん" ], "comment": "upper limit\nsupremum" },
	{ "question": "上院", "answers": [ "じょういん" ], "comment": "Upper House; Senate; Lords" },
	{ "question": "下がり", "answers": [ "さがり" ], "comment": "fall; decline; lowering; hanging down; drooping; slanting (downward)\nstring apron; ornamental cords hanging from the front of a sumo wrestler's belt\nfood offering to the gods; leftovers; hand-me-downs\nleaving (one's master's place for home)\na little after ..." },
	{ "question": "下り坂", "answers": [ "くだりざか" ], "comment": "descent; downhill; decline; waning" },
	{ "question": "下ろす", "answers": [ "おろす" ], "comment": "to take down (e.g. flag); to launch (e.g. boat); to drop; to lower (e.g. ladder); to let (a person) off; to unload; to discharge\nto drop off (a passenger from a vehicle); to let (a person) off\nto withdraw money from an account\nto wear (clothing) for the first time\nto fillet (e.g. a fish)" },
	{ "question": "下値", "answers": [ "したね" ], "comment": "lowest price" },
	{ "question": "下唇", "answers": [ "したくちびる", "かしん" ], "comment": "lower lip" },
	{ "question": "下地", "answers": [ "したじ" ], "comment": "groundwork; foundation\ninclination; aptitude; elementary knowledge of; grounding in\nundercoat; first coat\nsoy sauce" },
	{ "question": "下山", "answers": [ "げざん", "げさん" ], "comment": "descending (mountain)" },
	{ "question": "下敷", "answers": [ "したじき" ], "comment": "desk pad; sheet of plastic (or cardboard, felt, etc.) placed under writing paper; underlay\nbeing pinned under; being caught under; being trapped under; being buried under; being crushed beneath\nmodel; pattern" },
	{ "question": "下敷き", "answers": [ "したじき" ], "comment": "desk pad; sheet of plastic (or cardboard, felt, etc.) placed under writing paper; underlay\nbeing pinned under; being caught under; being trapped under; being buried under; being crushed beneath\nmodel; pattern" },
	{ "question": "下方", "answers": [ "かほう" ], "comment": "lower region; lower part" },
	{ "question": "下期", "answers": [ "しもき" ], "comment": "second half of the fiscal year" },
	{ "question": "下火", "answers": [ "したび" ], "comment": "burning low; waning; declining" },
	{ "question": "下等", "answers": [ "かとう" ], "comment": "inferior; base; vulgar; low grade; lower class" },
	{ "question": "下落", "answers": [ "げらく" ], "comment": "depreciation; decline; fall; slump" },
	{ "question": "下見", "answers": [ "したみ" ], "comment": "preview; preliminary inspection\npreparatory reading; preparation for a lesson; rehearsal\nsiding (on a house); clapboard; weatherboard" },
	{ "question": "下調べ", "answers": [ "したしらべ" ], "comment": "preliminary investigation; preparation" },
	{ "question": "下請け", "answers": [ "したうけ" ], "comment": "subcontract\nsubcontractor (person or company)" },
	{ "question": "下野", "answers": [ "げや" ], "comment": "retirement from public office\ngoing into opposition; losing power" },
	{ "question": "下限", "answers": [ "かげん" ], "comment": "lower limit\ninfimum" },
	{ "question": "下院", "answers": [ "かいん" ], "comment": "lower house; lower (legislative) body" },
	{ "question": "不仲", "answers": [ "ふなか" ], "comment": "discord" },
	{ "question": "不作", "answers": [ "ふさく" ], "comment": "poor crop; crop failure" },
	{ "question": "不備", "answers": [ "ふび" ], "comment": "defect; deficiency; imperfection; inadequacy\nYours in haste" },
	{ "question": "不全", "answers": [ "ふぜん" ], "comment": "partial; incomplete; imperfect" },
	{ "question": "不可侵", "answers": [ "ふかしん" ], "comment": "inviolability; sacredness; nonaggression" },
	{ "question": "不可分", "answers": [ "ふかぶん" ], "comment": "atomic; indivisibility" },
	{ "question": "不可解", "answers": [ "ふかかい" ], "comment": "mystery; baffling; inexplicable; incomprehensible" },
	{ "question": "不可避", "answers": [ "ふかひ" ], "comment": "inevitable; inescapable; unavoidable" },
	{ "question": "不吉", "answers": [ "ふきつ" ], "comment": "ominous; sinister; unlucky; inauspicious" },
	{ "question": "不問", "answers": [ "ふもん" ], "comment": "something not questioned; something not asked about; something not relevant; something of no object" },
	{ "question": "不変", "answers": [ "ふへん" ], "comment": "eternal; everlasting; unchangeable; immutable; immovable; constant; permanent; indestructible" },
	{ "question": "不妊", "answers": [ "ふにん" ], "comment": "infertility; sterility; barrenness" },
	{ "question": "不孝", "answers": [ "ふこう", "ふきょう" ], "comment": "undutifulness to one's parents; lack of filial piety\n(the crime of) cursing one's parents\ndisowning one's child" },
	{ "question": "不定", "answers": [ "ふてい", "ふじょう" ], "comment": "uncertainty; insecurity; inconstancy; indefinite; undecided" },
	{ "question": "不幸せ", "answers": [ "ふしあわせ" ], "comment": "unhappiness; misfortune; ill luck" },
	{ "question": "不慣れ", "answers": [ "ふなれ" ], "comment": "inexperienced; unfamiliar (with); unversed; lacking experience" },
	{ "question": "不慮", "answers": [ "ふりょ" ], "comment": "unforeseen; accidental" },
	{ "question": "不戦", "answers": [ "ふせん" ], "comment": "war renunciation; anti-war\nbout cancelled due to absence of one of the wrestlers" },
	{ "question": "不払い", "answers": [ "ふばらい" ], "comment": "nonpayment; default" },
	{ "question": "不振", "answers": [ "ふしん" ], "comment": "dullness; depression; slump; stagnation" },
	{ "question": "不断", "answers": [ "ふだん" ], "comment": "constant; persistent; unremitting; ceaseless\nindecisiveness" },
	{ "question": "不服", "answers": [ "ふふく" ], "comment": "dissatisfaction; discontent; disapproval; objection; complaint; protest; disagreement" },
	{ "question": "不毛", "answers": [ "ふもう" ], "comment": "sterile; barren; unproductive; sour" },
	{ "question": "不渡り", "answers": [ "ふわたり" ], "comment": "non-payment; dishonouring (bill); dishonoring (bill); bouncing (cheque, check)" },
	{ "question": "不発", "answers": [ "ふはつ" ], "comment": "misfire" },
	{ "question": "不眠", "answers": [ "ふみん" ], "comment": "sleeplessness; insomnia; wakefulness" },
	{ "question": "不確か", "answers": [ "ふたしか" ], "comment": "unreliable; uncertain; indefinite; unclear" },
	{ "question": "不穏", "answers": [ "ふおん" ], "comment": "disquieting; threatening; turbulent; restless; unsettled; disturbing" },
	{ "question": "不純", "answers": [ "ふじゅん" ], "comment": "impurity; adulteration; dishonesty; irregularity" },
	{ "question": "不評", "answers": [ "ふひょう" ], "comment": "bad reputation; disgrace; unpopularity" },
	{ "question": "不詳", "answers": [ "ふしょう" ], "comment": "unknown; unidentified; unspecified" },
	{ "question": "不調", "answers": [ "ふちょう" ], "comment": "bad condition; not to work out (i.e. a deal); disagreement; break-off; disorder; slump; out of form" },
	{ "question": "不順", "answers": [ "ふじゅん" ], "comment": "irregularity; unseasonableness" },
	{ "question": "与党", "answers": [ "よとう" ], "comment": "ruling party; government party; party in power; government" },
	{ "question": "与野党", "answers": [ "よやとう" ], "comment": "ruling and opposition parties; parties in and out of power" },
	{ "question": "世相", "answers": [ "せそう" ], "comment": "phase of life; sign of the times\nworld (social) conditions; society" },
	{ "question": "世襲", "answers": [ "せしゅう" ], "comment": "heredity; heritage" },
	{ "question": "両党", "answers": [ "りょうとう" ], "comment": "both political parties" },
	{ "question": "両岸", "answers": [ "りょうぎし", "りょうがん" ], "comment": "both banks (of a river)" },
	{ "question": "両日", "answers": [ "りょうじつ" ], "comment": "both days; two days" },
	{ "question": "両氏", "answers": [ "りょうし" ], "comment": "both persons" },
	{ "question": "両端", "answers": [ "りょうはし", "りょうはじ", "りょうたん" ], "comment": "both ends; either end; both edges\ndouble-mindedness; sitting on the fence" },
	{ "question": "両腕", "answers": [ "りょううで", "もろうで" ], "comment": "both arms" },
	{ "question": "両論", "answers": [ "りょうろん" ], "comment": "both arguments (theories)" },
	{ "question": "両軍", "answers": [ "りょうぐん" ], "comment": "both armies; both teams" },
	{ "question": "両輪", "answers": [ "りょうりん" ], "comment": "two wheels" },
	{ "question": "両院", "answers": [ "りょういん" ], "comment": "both Houses of Parliament" },
	{ "question": "並び替える", "answers": [ "ならびかえる" ], "comment": "to reorganize; to rearrange; to put (things) in order" },
	{ "question": "並列", "answers": [ "へいれつ" ], "comment": "running in parallel; lined up alongside\nparallel (electronics, computing, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "並立", "answers": [ "へいりつ" ], "comment": "standing abreast" },
	{ "question": "中佐", "answers": [ "ちゅうさ" ], "comment": "lieutenant colonel; commander (navy)" },
	{ "question": "中傷", "answers": [ "ちゅうしょう" ], "comment": "slander; libel; defamation; calumny; smear" },
	{ "question": "中元", "answers": [ "ちゅうげん" ], "comment": "15th day of the 7th lunar month; (last day of) Bon lantern festival\nmid-year gift; summer gift; Bon Festival gifts" },
	{ "question": "中前", "answers": [ "ちゅうぜん" ], "comment": "front of center field; front of centre field" },
	{ "question": "中卒", "answers": [ "ちゅうそつ" ], "comment": "junior high school graduate; middle school graduate" },
	{ "question": "中南米", "answers": [ "ちゅうなんべい" ], "comment": "Central and South America" },
	{ "question": "中和", "answers": [ "ちゅうわ" ], "comment": "neutralizing; neutralising; counteracting\nneutral; unbiased" },
	{ "question": "中型", "answers": [ "ちゅうがた" ], "comment": "medium size" },
	{ "question": "中執", "answers": [ "ちゅうしつ" ], "comment": "Central Executive Committee" },
	{ "question": "中堅", "answers": [ "ちゅうけん" ], "comment": "main body (of troops)\nnucleus; backbone; mainstay; key figure\ncenter field; centre field; center fielder; centre fielder\nathlete competing in the middle-number match in a team competition, i.e. second in 3-on-3, third in 5-on-5 (kendo, judo, etc.)\nmedium-level; mid-level; midsize" },
	{ "question": "中小", "answers": [ "ちゅうしょう" ], "comment": "small to medium" },
	{ "question": "中流", "answers": [ "ちゅうりゅう" ], "comment": "mid-stream; middle course; middle class" },
	{ "question": "中盤", "answers": [ "ちゅうばん" ], "comment": "middle (stage)" },
	{ "question": "中等", "answers": [ "ちゅうとう" ], "comment": "second grade; medium quality; average; middle class; secondary grade" },
	{ "question": "中級", "answers": [ "ちゅうきゅう" ], "comment": "intermediate level" },
	{ "question": "中継ぎ", "answers": [ "なかつぎ" ], "comment": "joining; joint; intermediation; relaying; intermediary; relay; agency; brokerage\nmid-relief pitcher; middle reliever" },
	{ "question": "中腹", "answers": [ "ちゅうふく" ], "comment": "mountain side; halfway up" },
	{ "question": "中軸", "answers": [ "ちゅうじく" ], "comment": "axis; pivot; central figure; key man" },
	{ "question": "中退", "answers": [ "ちゅうたい" ], "comment": "leaving school during a term" },
	{ "question": "中道", "answers": [ "ちゅうどう" ], "comment": "middle of the road; moderation; golden mean\nthe middle (of what one is doing); half-way\nmiddle way; middle path" },
	{ "question": "中部", "answers": [ "ちゅうぶ" ], "comment": "center; centre; middle; heart\nChubu region (incl. Aichi, Nagano, Shizuoka, Niigata, Toyama, Ishikawa, Fukui, Yamanashi and Gifu prefectures)" },
	{ "question": "中隊", "answers": [ "ちゅうたい" ], "comment": "company, battery, troop" },
	{ "question": "中高", "answers": [ "ちゅうこう" ], "comment": "middle and high school\nmedium and high (level)" },
	{ "question": "丸々", "answers": [ "まるまる" ], "comment": "plump; rotund; chubby\nentirely; completely; wholly" },
	{ "question": "丸まる", "answers": [ "まるまる" ], "comment": "to become rounded; to roll into a ball" },
	{ "question": "丸み", "answers": [ "まるみ" ], "comment": "roundness; rotundity\nmellowness; maturity" },
	{ "question": "丸め込む", "answers": [ "まるめこむ" ], "comment": "to coax; to seduce; to win over\nto roll up and put in (to something); to bundle up" },
	{ "question": "丸刈り", "answers": [ "まるがり" ], "comment": "close clipping" },
	{ "question": "丸太", "answers": [ "まるた" ], "comment": "log" },
	{ "question": "丹", "answers": [ "に" ], "comment": "red earth (i.e. containing cinnabar or minium); vermilion" },
	{ "question": "丹念", "answers": [ "たんねん" ], "comment": "painstaking; careful; meticulous; scrupulous; detailed; elaborate" },
	{ "question": "丹誠", "answers": [ "たんせい" ], "comment": "working earnestly; sincerity; diligence; effort; pains" },
	{ "question": "主", "answers": [ "ぬし", "しゅ", "おも", "しゅじん" ], "comment": "chief; main; principal; important\nmain secondary or supporting role (in kyogen) /\n (one's) master\nLord (Christian ref. to Jesus or God)\nthe main thing; the majority; the primary concern /\n head (of a household, etc.); leader; master\nowner; proprietor; proprietress\nsubject (of a rumour, etc.); doer (of a deed)\nguardian spirit (e.g. long-resident beast, usu. with mystical powers); long-time resident (or employee, etc.)\nhusband\nyou /\n head (of a household); proprietor (of a store); proprietress; landlord; landlady\none's husband\n(one's) employer; (one's) master\nhost; hostess" },
	{ "question": "主因", "answers": [ "しゅいん" ], "comment": "primary cause; main factor" },
	{ "question": "主宰", "answers": [ "しゅさい" ], "comment": "supervision; superintendence; chairmanship; chairman" },
	{ "question": "主審", "answers": [ "しゅしん" ], "comment": "chief umpire" },
	{ "question": "主将", "answers": [ "しゅしょう" ], "comment": "commander-in-chief; (team) captain" },
	{ "question": "主席", "answers": [ "しゅせき" ], "comment": "head; chief\nchairman; governor; president\ntop student; head of the class\ntop seat; first desk (in orchestra)" },
	{ "question": "主幹", "answers": [ "しゅかん" ], "comment": "chief editor; managing editor\nmanager; person in charge" },
	{ "question": "主戦", "answers": [ "しゅせん" ], "comment": "advocacy of war" },
	{ "question": "主査", "answers": [ "しゅさ" ], "comment": "chief examiner or investigator" },
	{ "question": "主演", "answers": [ "しゅえん" ], "comment": "starring; playing the leading part" },
	{ "question": "主犯", "answers": [ "しゅはん" ], "comment": "principal offence; principal offense; principal offender" },
	{ "question": "主眼", "answers": [ "しゅがん" ], "comment": "main point" },
	{ "question": "主砲", "answers": [ "しゅほう" ], "comment": "main battery; main armament" },
	{ "question": "主筆", "answers": [ "しゅひつ" ], "comment": "editor-in-chief" },
	{ "question": "主管", "answers": [ "しゅかん" ], "comment": "supervision; management; supervisor; manager" },
	{ "question": "主計", "answers": [ "しゅけい" ], "comment": "paymaster; accountant" },
	{ "question": "主軸", "answers": [ "しゅじく" ], "comment": "main spindle; main shaft\nlinchpin; pivot\nprincipal axis; main axis" },
	{ "question": "主食", "answers": [ "しゅしょく" ], "comment": "staple food" },
	{ "question": "久々", "answers": [ "ひさびさ" ], "comment": "(in a) long time; long time (ago); while (ago); long ago; long while (ago); (in a) long while" },
	{ "question": "乗ずる", "answers": [ "じょうずる" ], "comment": "to take advantage of; to follow blindly\nto multiply" },
	{ "question": "乗っ取り", "answers": [ "のっとり" ], "comment": "capture; takeover; hijack; skyjacking" },
	{ "question": "乗っ取る", "answers": [ "のっとる" ], "comment": "to take over; to capture; to seize; to commandeer; to occupy; to usurp\nto hijack (a vehicle)" },
	{ "question": "乗り回す", "answers": [ "のりまわす" ], "comment": "to drive (a car) around; to ride (a bicycle) around" },
	{ "question": "乗り場", "answers": [ "のりば" ], "comment": "place for boarding vehicles; bus stop; bus terminal; railway platform; taxi stand; jetty; wharf" },
	{ "question": "乗り気", "answers": [ "のりき" ], "comment": "interest; eagerness; enthusiasm" },
	{ "question": "乗り越える", "answers": [ "のりこえる" ], "comment": "to climb over; to get over; to ride across\nto surmount; to overcome\nto surpass; to overtake" },
	{ "question": "乗り越し", "answers": [ "のりこし" ], "comment": "riding past (one's station)" },
	{ "question": "乗り越す", "answers": [ "のりこす" ], "comment": "to ride past (one's stop); to overshoot\nto climb over; to get over\nto overtake (in a vehicle); to pass" },
	{ "question": "乗り遅れる", "answers": [ "のりおくれる" ], "comment": "to miss (train, bus, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "乗り降り", "answers": [ "のりおり" ], "comment": "getting on and off (a vehicle); boarding and alighting" },
	{ "question": "乗員", "answers": [ "じょういん" ], "comment": "crew" },
	{ "question": "乗回す", "answers": [ "のりまわす" ], "comment": "to drive (a car) around; to ride (a bicycle) around" },
	{ "question": "乗場", "answers": [ "のりば" ], "comment": "place for boarding vehicles; bus stop; bus terminal; railway platform; taxi stand; jetty; wharf" },
	{ "question": "乗気", "answers": [ "のりき" ], "comment": "interest; eagerness; enthusiasm" },
	{ "question": "乗越す", "answers": [ "のりこす" ], "comment": "to ride past (one's stop); to overshoot\nto climb over; to get over\nto overtake (in a vehicle); to pass" },
	{ "question": "乗降", "answers": [ "じょうこう" ], "comment": "getting on and off; embarking and disembarking" },
	{ "question": "乗馬", "answers": [ "じょうば" ], "comment": "horse riding\nriding horse; saddle horse" },
	{ "question": "乞食", "answers": [ "こつじき", "こじき" ], "comment": "beggar\nbegging" },
	{ "question": "乱れ", "answers": [ "みだれ" ], "comment": "disorder; disturbance; unrest" },
	{ "question": "乱獲", "answers": [ "らんかく" ], "comment": "excessive fishing; overfishing; overhunting; excessive taking" },
	{ "question": "乱用", "answers": [ "らんよう" ], "comment": "abuse; misuse; misappropriation; using to excess" },
	{ "question": "乱発", "answers": [ "らんぱつ" ], "comment": "random firing; reckless firing; excessive issue" },
	{ "question": "乱立", "answers": [ "らんりつ" ], "comment": "standing together in a disorderly fashion; standing close around; crowding together\nflooding in (applicants, election candidates, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "乱闘", "answers": [ "らんとう" ], "comment": "fray; fighting; brawling; scuffle" },
	{ "question": "乱雑", "answers": [ "らんざつ" ], "comment": "clutter; disorder; promiscuity; affray; confusion; muddle" },
	{ "question": "乳児", "answers": [ "にゅうじ" ], "comment": "infant (below 1 years old); suckling baby" },
	{ "question": "乳幼児", "answers": [ "にゅうようじ" ], "comment": "infants; babies" },
	{ "question": "乾季", "answers": [ "かんき" ], "comment": "dry season" },
	{ "question": "乾期", "answers": [ "かんき" ], "comment": "dry season" },
	{ "question": "乾物", "answers": [ "かんぶつ", "ひもの" ], "comment": "dry provisions; dried food; dried goods; groceries" },
	{ "question": "亀裂", "answers": [ "きれつ" ], "comment": "crack; crevice; fissure; chap; rift" },
	{ "question": "予断", "answers": [ "よだん" ], "comment": "guessing; prediction; conclusion" },
	{ "question": "予知", "answers": [ "よち" ], "comment": "foresight; foreknowledge; intimation; premonition; prediction" },
	{ "question": "予選", "answers": [ "よせん" ], "comment": "preliminary contest; qualifying round; trial; heat; primary" },
	{ "question": "争奪", "answers": [ "そうだつ" ], "comment": "struggle; contest" },
	{ "question": "争点", "answers": [ "そうてん" ], "comment": "point at issue" },
	{ "question": "争議", "answers": [ "そうぎ" ], "comment": "dispute; quarrel; strike" },
	{ "question": "事典", "answers": [ "ことてん", "じてん" ], "comment": "cyclopedia; encyclopedia" },
	{ "question": "事後", "answers": [ "じご" ], "comment": "after-; post-; ex-; after the fact; ex post" },
	{ "question": "二の次", "answers": [ "にのつぎ" ], "comment": "secondary; subordinate" },
	{ "question": "二分", "answers": [ "にぶん" ], "comment": "halving; bisection\nthe two equinoxes (vernal and autumnal)" },
	{ "question": "二塁", "answers": [ "にるい" ], "comment": "second base" },
	{ "question": "二流", "answers": [ "にりゅう" ], "comment": "second-rate; inferior" },
	{ "question": "二院", "answers": [ "にいん" ], "comment": "the two houses of legislature" },
	{ "question": "互い違い", "answers": [ "たがいちがい" ], "comment": "alternate; alternation" },
	{ "question": "互助", "answers": [ "ごじょ" ], "comment": "mutual aid; cooperation; benefit" },
	{ "question": "互換", "answers": [ "ごかん" ], "comment": "interchange\ntransposition\ncompatible (e.g. PC)" },
	{ "question": "互角", "answers": [ "ごかく" ], "comment": "equality; evenness; par; good match" },
	{ "question": "五分", "answers": [ "ごぶ" ], "comment": "half; 50%; tie; evenness\n5 parts; 5%" },
	{ "question": "五月", "answers": [ "ごがつ" ], "comment": "May" },
	{ "question": "五輪", "answers": [ "ごりん" ], "comment": "Olympic rings; Olympics" },
	{ "question": "亜鉛", "answers": [ "あえん" ], "comment": "zinc (Zn)" },
	{ "question": "亡骸", "answers": [ "なきがら" ], "comment": "remains; corpse; (dead) body" },
	{ "question": "交わす", "answers": [ "かわす" ], "comment": "to exchange (messages, greetings, arguments, etc.)\nto intersect; to cross; to interlace\n... with one another; ... to each other" },
	{ "question": "交信", "answers": [ "こうしん" ], "comment": "telecommunications; correspondence" },
	{ "question": "交友", "answers": [ "こうゆう" ], "comment": "friend; companion; acquaintance\nfriendship; companionship" },
	{ "question": "交戦", "answers": [ "こうせん" ], "comment": "war; battle; hostilities" },
	{ "question": "人だかり", "answers": [ "ひとだかり" ], "comment": "crowd; throng" },
	{ "question": "人中", "answers": [ "ひとなか" ], "comment": "society; company; the public; the world" },
	{ "question": "人出", "answers": [ "ひとで" ], "comment": "crowd; turnout" },
	{ "question": "人名", "answers": [ "じんめい" ], "comment": "person's name" },
	{ "question": "人妻", "answers": [ "ひとづま" ], "comment": "married woman\nanother's wife" },
	{ "question": "人心", "answers": [ "ひとごころ", "じんしん" ], "comment": "human nature; human heart; human spirit; kindness; sympathy" },
	{ "question": "人文", "answers": [ "じんぶん", "じんもん" ], "comment": "humanity; civilization; civilisation; culture" },
	{ "question": "人殺し", "answers": [ "ひとごろし" ], "comment": "murder; murderer" },
	{ "question": "人為", "answers": [ "じんい" ], "comment": "human work; human agency; art; artificiality" },
	{ "question": "人相", "answers": [ "にんそう" ], "comment": "looks; countenance; facial features\nphysiognomy" },
	{ "question": "人脈", "answers": [ "じんみゃく" ], "comment": "personal connections" },
	{ "question": "人道", "answers": [ "じんどう", "にんどう" ], "comment": "humanity\nsidewalk; footpath\nhuman realm" },
	{ "question": "人違い", "answers": [ "ひとちがい" ], "comment": "mistaking one person for another; (case of) mistaken identity" },
	{ "question": "人選", "answers": [ "じんせん" ], "comment": "personnel selection" },
	{ "question": "人骨", "answers": [ "じんこつ" ], "comment": "human bones" },
	{ "question": "仁", "answers": [ "にん", "じん" ], "comment": "benevolence (esp. as a virtue of Confucianism); consideration; compassion; humanity; charity\nhuman\nkernel\nnucleolus" },
	{ "question": "今夏", "answers": [ "こんか" ], "comment": "this summer; next summer; last summer" },
	{ "question": "今季", "answers": [ "こんき" ], "comment": "this season" },
	{ "question": "今春", "answers": [ "こんしゅん" ], "comment": "this spring; spring this year" },
	{ "question": "今期", "answers": [ "こんき" ], "comment": "the present term" },
	{ "question": "今秋", "answers": [ "こんしゅう" ], "comment": "this (next, last) autumn (fall)" },
	{ "question": "介助", "answers": [ "かいじょ" ], "comment": "help; assistance; aid\nto assist; to help; to aid" },
	{ "question": "介在", "answers": [ "かいざい" ], "comment": "mediation; interposition; intervention" },
	{ "question": "仏像", "answers": [ "ぶつぞう" ], "comment": "statue of Buddha; image of Buddha; Buddhist statue; Buddhist image" },
	{ "question": "仏壇", "answers": [ "ぶつだん" ], "comment": "Buddhist (household) altar" },
	{ "question": "仏文", "answers": [ "ふつぶん" ], "comment": "French; French writing; French literature" },
	{ "question": "仏語", "answers": [ "ふつご" ], "comment": "French (language)" },
	{ "question": "仕上がり", "answers": [ "しあがり" ], "comment": "finish; end; completion" },
	{ "question": "仕入れ", "answers": [ "しいれ" ], "comment": "stocking; buying up" },
	{ "question": "仕出し", "answers": [ "しだし" ], "comment": "catering; shipment" },
	{ "question": "仕切り", "answers": [ "しきり" ], "comment": "partition; division; boundary; compartment\nsettlement of accounts\npreliminary warm-up ritual; toeing the mark\ndirecting; controlling; managing; taking responsibility for" },
	{ "question": "仕立て", "answers": [ "したて" ], "comment": "tailoring; dressmaking; sewing; making; preparation" },
	{ "question": "仕込み", "answers": [ "しこみ" ], "comment": "training; education; upbringing\nstocking up; laying in\npreparation (e.g. ingredients)\ngirl studying to become a geisha" },
	{ "question": "仕送り", "answers": [ "しおくり" ], "comment": "allowance; remittance; sending (someone) an allowance" },
	{ "question": "他殺", "answers": [ "たさつ" ], "comment": "murder" },
	{ "question": "他派", "answers": [ "たは" ], "comment": "the other group" },
	{ "question": "他面", "answers": [ "ためん" ], "comment": "other side; another side; different angle\non the other hand" },
	{ "question": "付き添い", "answers": [ "つきそい" ], "comment": "attendance on; attendant; escort; chaperon; retinue" },
	{ "question": "付け足す", "answers": [ "つけたす" ], "comment": "to add to" },
	{ "question": "付け込む", "answers": [ "つけこむ" ], "comment": "to take advantage of; to impose on\nto make an entry (in an account book)" },
	{ "question": "付帯", "answers": [ "ふたい" ], "comment": "incidental; ancillary; accessory; secondary; collateral" },
	{ "question": "付添い", "answers": [ "つきそい" ], "comment": "attendance on; attendant; escort; chaperon; retinue" },
	{ "question": "付録", "answers": [ "ふろく" ], "comment": "appendix; supplement; annex; extra (of a newspaper or magazine)" },
	{ "question": "代々", "answers": [ "よよ", "だいだい" ], "comment": "for generations; hereditary; generation after generation" },
	{ "question": "代わる代わる", "answers": [ "かわるがわる" ], "comment": "alternately; by turns" },
	{ "question": "代人", "answers": [ "だいにん" ], "comment": "substitute; deputy; proxy; representative; agent" },
	{ "question": "代官", "answers": [ "だいかん" ], "comment": "Edo-period prefectural governor (magistrate, bailiff)" },
	{ "question": "代弁", "answers": [ "だいべん" ], "comment": "pay by proxy; act for another; speak for another" },
	{ "question": "代役", "answers": [ "だいやく" ], "comment": "substitute (e.g. actor); substitution; stand-in; double" },
	{ "question": "代打", "answers": [ "だいだ" ], "comment": "pinch-hitting" },
	{ "question": "代謝", "answers": [ "たいしゃ" ], "comment": "renewal; regeneration; metabolism" },
	{ "question": "代議", "answers": [ "だいぎ" ], "comment": "representing others in a conference" },
	{ "question": "令状", "answers": [ "れいじょう" ], "comment": "warrant; summons; written order" },
	{ "question": "仮想", "answers": [ "かそう" ], "comment": "imagination; supposition; virtual; potential (enemy)" },
	{ "question": "仮称", "answers": [ "かしょう" ], "comment": "temporary name; provisional name" },
	{ "question": "仮設", "answers": [ "かせつ" ], "comment": "temporary; provisional\nto do something temporarily (esp. build temporary facilities); to do something provisionally" },
	{ "question": "仮題", "answers": [ "かだい" ], "comment": "tentative title" },
	{ "question": "仲人", "answers": [ "ちゅうにん", "なこうど" ], "comment": "matchmaker\ngo-between; intermediary; middleman; mediator; intercessor" },
	{ "question": "仲裁", "answers": [ "ちゅうさい" ], "comment": "arbitration; intercession; mediation" },
	{ "question": "仲買", "answers": [ "なかがい" ], "comment": "brokerage" },
	{ "question": "任期", "answers": [ "にんき" ], "comment": "term of office" },
	{ "question": "企てる", "answers": [ "くわだてる" ], "comment": "to plan; to plot; to propose; to design; to intend; to contemplate\nto attempt (e.g. suicide, murder); to undertake (e.g. business)\nto stand on tip-toes" },
	{ "question": "企み", "answers": [ "たくらみ" ], "comment": "plan; design; artifice; trick; intrigue" },
	{ "question": "伏せる", "answers": [ "ふせる" ], "comment": "to lay something upside down; to turn something over; to lay something face down\nto cover; to lay (pipes); to lay (an ambush); to hide; to conceal" },
	{ "question": "伏兵", "answers": [ "ふくへい" ], "comment": "ambush; troops in ambush" },
	{ "question": "伏線", "answers": [ "ふくせん" ], "comment": "foreshadowing\npreparation; precautionary measures" },
	{ "question": "伐採", "answers": [ "ばっさい" ], "comment": "lumbering; felling; deforestation" },
	{ "question": "休する", "answers": [ "きゅうする" ], "comment": "to come to an end\nto rest" },
	{ "question": "休まる", "answers": [ "やすまる" ], "comment": "to be rested; to feel at ease; to repose; to be relieved" },
	{ "question": "休める", "answers": [ "やすめる" ], "comment": "to rest; to suspend; to give relief" },
	{ "question": "休刊", "answers": [ "きゅうかん" ], "comment": "suspension of publication" },
	{ "question": "休場", "answers": [ "きゅうじょう" ], "comment": "theater closure; theatre closure; stage absence\nwrestler's absence from the tournament" },
	{ "question": "休学", "answers": [ "きゅうがく" ], "comment": "temporary absence from school" },
	{ "question": "休戦", "answers": [ "きゅうせん" ], "comment": "cease-fire; truce; armistice" },
	{ "question": "休校", "answers": [ "きゅうこう" ], "comment": "closing school (temporarily); dropping one's studies" },
	{ "question": "休止", "answers": [ "きゅうし" ], "comment": "pause; cessation; rest" },
	{ "question": "休職", "answers": [ "きゅうしょく" ], "comment": "temporary retirement; suspension from office" },
	{ "question": "休館", "answers": [ "きゅうかん" ], "comment": "closure (of a library, museum, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "会堂", "answers": [ "かいどう" ], "comment": "church; chapel; synagogue; tabernacle" },
	{ "question": "会報", "answers": [ "かいほう" ], "comment": "bulletin; report" },
	{ "question": "会心", "answers": [ "かいしん" ], "comment": "congeniality; satisfaction" },
	{ "question": "会期", "answers": [ "かいき" ], "comment": "session (of a legislature)" },
	{ "question": "会見", "answers": [ "かいけん" ], "comment": "interview; audience" },
	{ "question": "会費", "answers": [ "かいひ" ], "comment": "membership fee" },
	{ "question": "会釈", "answers": [ "えしゃく" ], "comment": "slight bow (as a greeting or sign of gratitude); nod; salutation\nconsideration; thoughtfulness" },
	{ "question": "会頭", "answers": [ "かいとう" ], "comment": "society president" },
	{ "question": "会食", "answers": [ "かいしょく" ], "comment": "dining together; mess" },
	{ "question": "伝う", "answers": [ "つたう" ], "comment": "to go along; to walk along; to follow" },
	{ "question": "伝票", "answers": [ "でんぴょう" ], "comment": "chit; sales slip; voucher" },
	{ "question": "伝言", "answers": [ "でんごん" ], "comment": "verbal message; word" },
	{ "question": "伝送", "answers": [ "でんそう" ], "comment": "transmission; communication; circulation; dissemination; diffusion; propagation; delivery" },
	{ "question": "伝道", "answers": [ "でんどう" ], "comment": "proselytizing; evangelism; missionary work" },
	{ "question": "伴奏", "answers": [ "ばんそう" ], "comment": "(musical) accompaniment" },
	{ "question": "伸し", "answers": [ "のし" ], "comment": "stretching\nsidestroke (in swimming)" },
	{ "question": "伸び", "answers": [ "のび" ], "comment": "growth; development\nstretching (e.g. body when waking up)\nspread; elongation; extension; carry (e.g. of sound); sustain" },
	{ "question": "伸びやか", "answers": [ "のびやか" ], "comment": "comfortable; carefree" },
	{ "question": "伸び悩む", "answers": [ "のびなやむ" ], "comment": "to be sluggish (business); to make little progress; to not grow as much as expected" },
	{ "question": "伸び率", "answers": [ "のびりつ" ], "comment": "growth rate; coefficient of extension" },
	{ "question": "似せる", "answers": [ "にせる" ], "comment": "to copy; to imitate; to counterfeit; to forge" },
	{ "question": "似合い", "answers": [ "にあい" ], "comment": "well-matched; becoming; suitable" },
	{ "question": "似通う", "answers": [ "にかよう" ], "comment": "to resemble closely" },
	{ "question": "似顔", "answers": [ "にがお" ], "comment": "portrait; likeness" },
	{ "question": "佃", "answers": [ "つくだ", "てん" ], "comment": "cultivated rice field" },
	{ "question": "低める", "answers": [ "ひくめる" ], "comment": "to lower; to be lowered" },
	{ "question": "低利", "answers": [ "ていり" ], "comment": "low interest rate" },
	{ "question": "低減", "answers": [ "ていげん" ], "comment": "decrease; reduction; fall; depreciation; mitigation" },
	{ "question": "低温", "answers": [ "ていおん" ], "comment": "low temperature" },
	{ "question": "低落", "answers": [ "ていらく" ], "comment": "fall; decline; slump" },
	{ "question": "低調", "answers": [ "ていちょう" ], "comment": "inactive; slow; sluggish; slack; low tone; undertone; dullness; (market) weakness" },
	{ "question": "低迷", "answers": [ "ていめい" ], "comment": "hanging low (over); hovering around (price level); low hanging (e.g. clouds); sluggish (e.g. economy); slump; recession" },
	{ "question": "低音", "answers": [ "ていおん" ], "comment": "low tone; bass; low voice" },
	{ "question": "住み心地", "answers": [ "すみごこち" ], "comment": "comfort (in living place)" },
	{ "question": "体つき", "answers": [ "からだつき" ], "comment": "body build; figure" },
	{ "question": "体付き", "answers": [ "からだつき" ], "comment": "body build; figure" },
	{ "question": "体勢", "answers": [ "たいせい" ], "comment": "posture; stance" },
	{ "question": "体形", "answers": [ "たいけい" ], "comment": "figure; body shape; build; physique; form\nsomatotype; biotype; habitus; (type of) physique" },
	{ "question": "体得", "answers": [ "たいとく" ], "comment": "mastery; knack; realization; realisation; experience; comprehension" },
	{ "question": "体感", "answers": [ "たいかん" ], "comment": "bodily sensation; sense; experience" },
	{ "question": "体罰", "answers": [ "たいばつ" ], "comment": "corporal punishment" },
	{ "question": "体裁", "answers": [ "たいさい", "ていさい" ], "comment": "(outward) appearance\n(proper) format (e.g. of an essay); form; style\nappearances; decency; show; display\nlip-service; insincere words; glib talk" },
	{ "question": "体長", "answers": [ "たいちょう" ], "comment": "length of an animal (sometimes including and sometimes excluding the tail)" },
	{ "question": "何とぞ", "answers": [ "なにとぞ" ], "comment": "please; kindly; I beg of you; if it pleases you\nby all means; without fail" },
	{ "question": "何人", "answers": [ "なにびと", "なんびと", "なんぴと" ], "comment": "everyone; every person; all; anyone" },
	{ "question": "何度", "answers": [ "なんど" ], "comment": "how many times?; how often?" },
	{ "question": "余す", "answers": [ "あます" ], "comment": "to save; to leave over; to spare" },
	{ "question": "余人", "answers": [ "よじん", "よにん" ], "comment": "others; other people" },
	{ "question": "余剰", "answers": [ "よじょう" ], "comment": "redundant; surplus; residue; balance" },
	{ "question": "余力", "answers": [ "よりょく" ], "comment": "spare energy, time or money; remaining strength; reserve power; money to spare" },
	{ "question": "余命", "answers": [ "よめい" ], "comment": "remainder of one's life; one's remaining years" },
	{ "question": "余念", "answers": [ "よねん" ], "comment": "another idea" },
	{ "question": "余暇", "answers": [ "よか" ], "comment": "leisure; leisure time; spare time" },
	{ "question": "余波", "answers": [ "よは", "なごり" ], "comment": "waves that remain after the wind has subsided\nafter-effect; aftermath" },
	{ "question": "余談", "answers": [ "よだん" ], "comment": "digression; sequel (of a story)" },
	{ "question": "余震", "answers": [ "よしん" ], "comment": "aftershock" },
	{ "question": "余韻", "answers": [ "よいん" ], "comment": "reverberation; swelling (of a hymn); trailing note\nlingering memory; aftertaste\nsuggestiveness (of a book, poem, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "作り笑い", "answers": [ "つくりわらい" ], "comment": "forced laugh; forced smile" },
	{ "question": "作り話", "answers": [ "つくりばなし" ], "comment": "fiction; made-up story; fable; fabrication; myth" },
	{ "question": "作付け", "answers": [ "さくつけ", "さくづけ" ], "comment": "planting" },
	{ "question": "作柄", "answers": [ "さくがら" ], "comment": "crop conditions\nquality (of art)" },
	{ "question": "作詞", "answers": [ "さくし" ], "comment": "(writing) song lyrics" },
	{ "question": "作風", "answers": [ "さくふう" ], "comment": "literary style" },
	{ "question": "佳作", "answers": [ "かさく" ], "comment": "good piece of work\nhonourable mention (honorable)" },
	{ "question": "併合", "answers": [ "へいごう" ], "comment": "merger; joining into one; melding; merging; annexation; absorption" },
	{ "question": "併殺", "answers": [ "へいさつ" ], "comment": "double play" },
	{ "question": "併用", "answers": [ "へいよう" ], "comment": "using together (jointly); used at the same time" },
	{ "question": "併設", "answers": [ "へいせつ" ], "comment": "joint establishment (esp. schools of different levels or different courses of study); establishment as an annex (e.g. of a school); juxtaposition; placing side by side" },
	{ "question": "使い分け", "answers": [ "つかいわけ" ], "comment": "proper use; using (different things) for different purposes" },
	{ "question": "使い捨て", "answers": [ "つかいずて", "つかいすて" ], "comment": "throwaway; disposable" },
	{ "question": "使い道", "answers": [ "つかいみち" ], "comment": "purpose; utility; objective\nway to use something" },
	{ "question": "使途", "answers": [ "しと" ], "comment": "purpose for which money is spent; the way money is spent; how goods are used" },
	{ "question": "例え", "answers": [ "たとえ" ], "comment": "example\nsimile; metaphor; allegory; fable; parable" },
	{ "question": "例会", "answers": [ "れいかい" ], "comment": "regular meeting" },
	{ "question": "例年", "answers": [ "れいねん" ], "comment": "average (normal, ordinary) year\nevery year; annually" },
	{ "question": "例文", "answers": [ "れいぶん" ], "comment": "example sentence; illustrative sentence; model sentence" },
	{ "question": "例題", "answers": [ "れいだい" ], "comment": "example; exercise (for the reader)" },
	{ "question": "侍従", "answers": [ "じじゅう" ], "comment": "chamberlain" },
	{ "question": "供与", "answers": [ "きょうよ" ], "comment": "giving; provision; furnishing" },
	{ "question": "供述", "answers": [ "きょうじゅつ" ], "comment": "affidavit; deposition; testimony" },
	{ "question": "供養", "answers": [ "くよう" ], "comment": "memorial service for the dead; holding a service" },
	{ "question": "侮る", "answers": [ "あなどる", "あなずる" ], "comment": "to disdain; to look down on; to make light of; to hold in contempt; to scorn; to despise" },
	{ "question": "侮蔑", "answers": [ "ぶべつ" ], "comment": "scorn; disdain; contempt; slight" },
	{ "question": "侮辱", "answers": [ "ぶじょく" ], "comment": "insult; affront; slight; contempt (e.g. of court)" },
	{ "question": "侵す", "answers": [ "おかす" ], "comment": "to invade; to raid; to violate (airspace, etc.); to intrude; to trespass\nto infringe; to encroach\nto harm; to afflict; to affect" },
	{ "question": "侵攻", "answers": [ "しんこう" ], "comment": "invasion" },
	{ "question": "侵犯", "answers": [ "しんぱん" ], "comment": "violation; invasion; infringement; trespass" },
	{ "question": "便乗", "answers": [ "びんじょう" ], "comment": "taking advantage of a ride or an opportunity; taking a ship" },
	{ "question": "係争", "answers": [ "けいそう" ], "comment": "contention; dispute; conflict; controversy" },
	{ "question": "係員", "answers": [ "かかりいん" ], "comment": "official (e.g. customs); clerk in charge" },
	{ "question": "係官", "answers": [ "かかりかん" ], "comment": "official in charge" },
	{ "question": "係長", "answers": [ "かかりちょう" ], "comment": "chief clerk" },
	{ "question": "促成", "answers": [ "そくせい" ], "comment": "promotion of growth" },
	{ "question": "俄雨", "answers": [ "にわかあめ" ], "comment": "rain shower" },
	{ "question": "俊足", "answers": [ "しゅんそく" ], "comment": "fast runner\nswift horse; fleet steed\ntalented person; brilliant person" },
	{ "question": "俎板", "answers": [ "まないた" ], "comment": "chopping board" },
	{ "question": "俗語", "answers": [ "ぞくご" ], "comment": "colloquialism; colloquial language; slang" },
	{ "question": "保する", "answers": [ "ほする" ], "comment": "to guarantee" },
	{ "question": "保母", "answers": [ "ほぼ" ], "comment": "day-care worker in a kindergarten, nursery school, etc." },
	{ "question": "保温", "answers": [ "ほおん" ], "comment": "retaining warmth; keeping heat in; heat insulation" },
	{ "question": "保留", "answers": [ "ほりゅう" ], "comment": "reserve; putting on hold; deferment\nhold (e.g. telephone button); pending" },
	{ "question": "保釈", "answers": [ "ほしゃく" ], "comment": "bail; releasing on bail" },
	{ "question": "保革", "answers": [ "ほかく" ], "comment": "conservatism and progressivism; conservatives and reformists" },
	{ "question": "保養", "answers": [ "ほよう" ], "comment": "health preservation; recuperation; recreation" },
	{ "question": "信", "answers": [ "しん" ], "comment": "honesty; fidelity\ntrust; reliance\n(religious) faith\ncounter for received messages" },
	{ "question": "信任", "answers": [ "しんにん" ], "comment": "trust; confidence; credence" },
	{ "question": "信徒", "answers": [ "しんと" ], "comment": "layman; believer; adherent; follower; laity" },
	{ "question": "信条", "answers": [ "しんじょう" ], "comment": "creed; belief; conviction; article of faith" },
	{ "question": "信義", "answers": [ "しんぎ" ], "comment": "faith; fidelity; loyalty" },
	{ "question": "信金", "answers": [ "しんきん" ], "comment": "credit union (guild)" },
	{ "question": "修める", "answers": [ "おさめる" ], "comment": "to study; to complete (a course); to cultivate; to master\nto order (one's life)\nto repair (a fault one has committed)" },
	{ "question": "修了", "answers": [ "しゅうりょう" ], "comment": "completion (of a course)" },
	{ "question": "修士", "answers": [ "しゅうし" ], "comment": "master's (academic degree)" },
	{ "question": "修業", "answers": [ "しゅうぎょう", "しゅぎょう" ], "comment": "pursuit of knowledge; studying; learning; training; completing a course" },
	{ "question": "俳人", "answers": [ "はいじん" ], "comment": "haiku poet" },
	{ "question": "俵", "answers": [ "たわら", "ひょう" ], "comment": "straw bag; bale; sack\ncounter for sacks; counter for bales; counter for bags" },
	{ "question": "倉", "answers": [ "くら" ], "comment": "warehouse; storehouse; cellar; magazine; granary; godown; depository; treasury; elevator" },
	{ "question": "倉敷", "answers": [ "くらしき" ], "comment": "storage charges" },
	{ "question": "個展", "answers": [ "こてん" ], "comment": "solo exhibition; one-man exhibition; one-woman exhibition" },
	{ "question": "倍増", "answers": [ "ばいぞう" ], "comment": "double" },
	{ "question": "倍率", "answers": [ "ばいりつ" ], "comment": "magnification; leverage; amplification; scaling factor; scale factor\nacceptance rate; pass rate (of an exam, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "倒れ", "answers": [ "たおれ" ], "comment": "bad debt\ncollapse (esp. pref.)" },
	{ "question": "倒置", "answers": [ "とうち" ], "comment": "turning upside down; placing nonessentials before essentials" },
	{ "question": "倒閣", "answers": [ "とうかく" ], "comment": "overthrow of government" },
	{ "question": "借り", "answers": [ "かり" ], "comment": "borrowing; debt; loan" },
	{ "question": "借り入れ", "answers": [ "かりいれ" ], "comment": "debt" },
	{ "question": "借地", "answers": [ "しゃくち" ], "comment": "leased land" },
	{ "question": "借家", "answers": [ "かりいえ", "しゃっか", "かりや", "しゃくや" ], "comment": "house for rent; rented house; renting a house" },
	{ "question": "借款", "answers": [ "しゃっかん" ], "comment": "(international) loan" },
	{ "question": "値上がり", "answers": [ "ねあがり" ], "comment": "price advance; increase in value" },
	{ "question": "値上げ", "answers": [ "ねあげ" ], "comment": "price hike; mark-up" },
	{ "question": "値下がり", "answers": [ "ねさがり" ], "comment": "price decline; fall in price" },
	{ "question": "値下げ", "answers": [ "ねさげ" ], "comment": "cut in price" },
	{ "question": "値切る", "answers": [ "ねぎる" ], "comment": "to drive a bargain; to beat down the price; to haggle" },
	{ "question": "値引き", "answers": [ "ねびき" ], "comment": "price reduction; discount" },
	{ "question": "値打ち", "answers": [ "ねうち" ], "comment": "value; worth; price; dignity" },
	{ "question": "倹約", "answers": [ "けんやく" ], "comment": "thrift; economy; frugality" },
	{ "question": "偉人", "answers": [ "いじん" ], "comment": "great man" },
	{ "question": "偉業", "answers": [ "いぎょう" ], "comment": "great enterprise; exploits" },
	{ "question": "偏り", "answers": [ "かたより" ], "comment": "deviation; inclination; offset; bias; prejudice\npolarization; polarisation" },
	{ "question": "偏重", "answers": [ "へんちょう" ], "comment": "preponderance; making too much of; overestimation; overemphasis; attaching too much importance to" },
	{ "question": "停学", "answers": [ "ていがく" ], "comment": "suspension from school" },
	{ "question": "停戦", "answers": [ "ていせん" ], "comment": "armistice; ceasefire" },
	{ "question": "停泊", "answers": [ "ていはく" ], "comment": "anchorage; moorings" },
	{ "question": "停滞", "answers": [ "ていたい" ], "comment": "stagnation; tie-up; congestion; retention; accumulation; falling into arrears" },
	{ "question": "健やか", "answers": [ "すこやか" ], "comment": "vigorous; healthy; sound" },
	{ "question": "健保", "answers": [ "けんぽ" ], "comment": "health insurance" },
	{ "question": "健気", "answers": [ "けなげ" ], "comment": "admirable; commendable; praiseworthy; laudable; brave; heroic; noble; courageous" },
	{ "question": "健診", "answers": [ "けんしん" ], "comment": "physical examination; medical examination; health checkup; health screening" },
	{ "question": "健闘", "answers": [ "けんとう" ], "comment": "fighting bravely; strenuous efforts" },
	{ "question": "側近", "answers": [ "そっきん" ], "comment": "close associate; close aide; brains-truster" },
	{ "question": "偵察", "answers": [ "ていさつ" ], "comment": "scout out; reconnaissance" },
	{ "question": "偶像", "answers": [ "ぐうぞう" ], "comment": "image; idol; statue" },
	{ "question": "偶発", "answers": [ "ぐうはつ" ], "comment": "sudden outbreak; accidental; incidental" },
	{ "question": "偽物", "answers": [ "ぎぶつ", "にせもの" ], "comment": "spurious article; forgery; counterfeit; imitation; sham" },
	{ "question": "偽装", "answers": [ "ぎそう" ], "comment": "camouflage; disguise\npretense; feigning; masquerade" },
	{ "question": "偽証", "answers": [ "ぎしょう" ], "comment": "false evidence; perjury; false testimony" },
	{ "question": "偽造", "answers": [ "ぎぞう" ], "comment": "forgery; falsification; fabrication; counterfeiting" },
	{ "question": "傍聴", "answers": [ "ぼうちょう" ], "comment": "hearing; listening; attendance; auditing" },
	{ "question": "傍観", "answers": [ "ぼうかん" ], "comment": "looking on; remaining a spectator" },
	{ "question": "傘下", "answers": [ "さんか" ], "comment": "affiliated with; under jurisdiction of; under the umbrella" },
	{ "question": "備え", "answers": [ "そなえ" ], "comment": "preparation; provision; guarding" },
	{ "question": "備え付ける", "answers": [ "そなえつける" ], "comment": "to provide; to furnish; to equip; to install" },
	{ "question": "備わる", "answers": [ "そなわる" ], "comment": "to be furnished with; to be provided with; to be equipped with\nto be possessed of; to be endowed with; to be gifted with\nto be among; to be one of" },
	{ "question": "備考", "answers": [ "びこう" ], "comment": "note (for reference); remarks; N.B." },
	{ "question": "備蓄", "answers": [ "びちく" ], "comment": "stockpile; reserves; storing; stocking up; laying in (supplies)" },
	{ "question": "催涙", "answers": [ "さいるい" ], "comment": "lacrimator; dacryagogue; tear-inducing agent" },
	{ "question": "債", "answers": [ "さい" ], "comment": "debt; loan" },
	{ "question": "債券", "answers": [ "さいけん" ], "comment": "bond; debenture" },
	{ "question": "傷む", "answers": [ "いたむ" ], "comment": "to hurt; to ache; to feel a pain\nto be injured; to be spoiled (e.g. food); to be damaged" },
	{ "question": "傷害", "answers": [ "しょうがい" ], "comment": "wound; injury; accident; casualty\nassault; inflicting bodily injury" },
	{ "question": "傷者", "answers": [ "しょうしゃ" ], "comment": "wounded person; casualty; injured person" },
	{ "question": "傷跡", "answers": [ "きずあと", "しょうこん" ], "comment": "scar; cicatrix" },
	{ "question": "傾注", "answers": [ "けいちゅう" ], "comment": "devotion; concentration" },
	{ "question": "働き盛り", "answers": [ "はたらきざかり" ], "comment": "prime of one's working life" },
	{ "question": "僻み", "answers": [ "ひがみ" ], "comment": "prejudice; bias; warped view; jealousy; inferiority complex" },
	{ "question": "償い", "answers": [ "つぐない" ], "comment": "recompense; indemnity; atonement" },
	{ "question": "償う", "answers": [ "つぐなう", "つぐのう" ], "comment": "to make up for; to compensate for; to indemnify; to recompense; to redeem (e.g. a fault); to atone for" },
	{ "question": "償却", "answers": [ "しょうきゃく" ], "comment": "repayment; redemption\ndepreciation\namortization; amortisation" },
	{ "question": "償還", "answers": [ "しょうかん" ], "comment": "repayment; redemption; amortization; amortisation" },
	{ "question": "優勢", "answers": [ "ゆうせい" ], "comment": "superiority; superior power; predominance; preponderance" },
	{ "question": "優美", "answers": [ "ゆうび" ], "comment": "grace; refinement; elegance; daintiness" },
	{ "question": "優良", "answers": [ "ゆうりょう" ], "comment": "superior; excellent; fine" },
	{ "question": "儲け", "answers": [ "もうけ" ], "comment": "profit; earnings" },
	{ "question": "元凶", "answers": [ "げんきょう" ], "comment": "ringleader; main culprit\nmain cause; source" },
	{ "question": "元号", "answers": [ "げんごう" ], "comment": "era name" },
	{ "question": "元帥", "answers": [ "げんすい" ], "comment": "(field) marshal; (fleet) admiral; general of the army" },
	{ "question": "元日", "answers": [ "がんにち", "がんじつ" ], "comment": "New Year's Day" },
	{ "question": "元旦", "answers": [ "がんたん" ], "comment": "New Year's Day\nNew Year's morning; morning of New Year's Day" },
	{ "question": "元本", "answers": [ "げんぽん", "がんぽん" ], "comment": "principal (invest.); capital" },
	{ "question": "元祖", "answers": [ "がんそ" ], "comment": "originator; founder; pioneer; inventor" },
	{ "question": "元素", "answers": [ "げんそ" ], "comment": "chemical element" },
	{ "question": "元首", "answers": [ "げんしゅ" ], "comment": "ruler; sovereign" },
	{ "question": "充当", "answers": [ "じゅうとう" ], "comment": "allocation; appropriation" },
	{ "question": "充満", "answers": [ "じゅうまん" ], "comment": "being filled with; being full of; permeation" },
	{ "question": "兆し", "answers": [ "きざし" ], "comment": "signs; omen; symptoms" },
	{ "question": "先々", "answers": [ "さきざき" ], "comment": "distant future; inevitable future\nplaces one goes to" },
	{ "question": "先だって", "answers": [ "せんだって", "さきだって" ], "comment": "recently; the other day" },
	{ "question": "先人", "answers": [ "せんじん" ], "comment": "predecessor; pioneer; ancestor" },
	{ "question": "先代", "answers": [ "せんだい" ], "comment": "family predecessor; previous age; previous generation" },
	{ "question": "先例", "answers": [ "せんれい" ], "comment": "precedent" },
	{ "question": "先制", "answers": [ "せんせい" ], "comment": "head start; initiative; preemption" },
	{ "question": "先取", "answers": [ "せんしゅ" ], "comment": "earning the first (runs); preoccupation" },
	{ "question": "先取り", "answers": [ "さきどり" ], "comment": "receiving in advance; taking before others\nprefetch\nanticipatory completion; finishing another person's sentence in anticipation of what likely to be said next" },
	{ "question": "先導", "answers": [ "せんどう" ], "comment": "guidance; leadership" },
	{ "question": "先手", "answers": [ "せんて" ], "comment": "first move (in go, shogi, etc.); moving first; person with the first move\nforestalling; (seizing the) initiative" },
	{ "question": "先決", "answers": [ "せんけつ" ], "comment": "previous decision; predetermination; deciding in advance; first priority" },
	{ "question": "先物", "answers": [ "さきもの" ], "comment": "futures" },
	{ "question": "先発", "answers": [ "せんぱつ" ], "comment": "starting in advance; starting first; going first; going ahead\nstarting (in team sports)" },
	{ "question": "先着", "answers": [ "せんちゃく" ], "comment": "arriving first" },
	{ "question": "先行き", "answers": [ "さきゆき", "さきいき" ], "comment": "the future; future prospects" },
	{ "question": "先見", "answers": [ "せんけん" ], "comment": "foresight; anticipation" },
	{ "question": "先送り", "answers": [ "さきおくり" ], "comment": "postpone" },
	{ "question": "先遣", "answers": [ "せんけん" ], "comment": "sending ahead" },
	{ "question": "先陣", "answers": [ "せんじん" ], "comment": "vanguard; advance guard" },
	{ "question": "先頃", "answers": [ "せんころ", "さきごろ" ], "comment": "recently; the other day" },
	{ "question": "先駆け", "answers": [ "さきがけ" ], "comment": "charging ahead of others; the first to charge; pioneer; forerunner; harbinger" },
	{ "question": "先駆ける", "answers": [ "さきがける" ], "comment": "to be the first" },
	{ "question": "光学", "answers": [ "こうがく" ], "comment": "optics" },
	{ "question": "光明", "answers": [ "こうみょう", "こうめい" ], "comment": "bright light\nhope; bright future\nlight emanating from a buddha or bodhisattva, symbolizing their wisdom and compassion" },
	{ "question": "光栄", "answers": [ "こうえい" ], "comment": "honour; honor; glory; privilege" },
	{ "question": "光沢", "answers": [ "こうたく" ], "comment": "brilliance; polish; lustre; luster; glossy finish (of photographs)" },
	{ "question": "克己", "answers": [ "こっき" ], "comment": "self denial; self control" },
	{ "question": "克明", "answers": [ "こくめい" ], "comment": "detailed; elaborate; faithful (copy); accurate\nscrupulous; diligent; conscientious" },
	{ "question": "免職", "answers": [ "めんしょく" ], "comment": "dismissal; sacking; discharge" },
	{ "question": "免責", "answers": [ "めんせき" ], "comment": "exemption from responsibility; disclaimer" },
	{ "question": "党内", "answers": [ "とうない" ], "comment": "party-internal" },
	{ "question": "党利", "answers": [ "とうり" ], "comment": "party interests" },
	{ "question": "党勢", "answers": [ "とうせい" ], "comment": "strength of a party" },
	{ "question": "党員", "answers": [ "とういん" ], "comment": "party member" },
	{ "question": "党派", "answers": [ "とうは" ], "comment": "faction" },
	{ "question": "党略", "answers": [ "とうりゃく" ], "comment": "party politics (tactics)" },
	{ "question": "党籍", "answers": [ "とうせき" ], "comment": "party register; membership in a party" },
	{ "question": "党議", "answers": [ "とうぎ" ], "comment": "party council; party conference" },
	{ "question": "党首", "answers": [ "とうしゅ" ], "comment": "party leader" },
	{ "question": "兜", "answers": [ "かぶと" ], "comment": "helmet (of armor, armour); headpiece" },
	{ "question": "入れ墨", "answers": [ "げい", "ぶんしん", "いれずみ", "しせい" ], "comment": "tattoo" },
	{ "question": "入れ替え", "answers": [ "いれかえ" ], "comment": "replacement; substitution; change\nshunting (rail); switching" },
	{ "question": "入れ歯", "answers": [ "いれば" ], "comment": "false tooth; denture" },
	{ "question": "入党", "answers": [ "にゅうとう" ], "comment": "joining a political party" },
	{ "question": "入団", "answers": [ "にゅうだん" ], "comment": "enrollment; enrolment" },
	{ "question": "入園", "answers": [ "にゅうえん" ], "comment": "enrollment in kindergarten; enrolment in kindergarten\nentering a park, garden, zoo, etc." },
	{ "question": "入室", "answers": [ "にゅうしつ", "にっしつ" ], "comment": "entering a room\nstudying under a Buddhist teacher" },
	{ "question": "入幕", "answers": [ "にゅうまく" ], "comment": "advancing to the first grade" },
	{ "question": "入念", "answers": [ "にゅうねん" ], "comment": "careful; elaborate; scrupulous" },
	{ "question": "入所", "answers": [ "にゅうしょ" ], "comment": "admission (e.g. to a training institution, research establishment, social welfare facility, etc.); entrance\nimprisonment; internment; confinement" },
	{ "question": "入梅", "answers": [ "つゆいり", "にゅうばい" ], "comment": "entering the rainy season; beginning of the rainy season" },
	{ "question": "入植", "answers": [ "にゅうしょく" ], "comment": "settlement; immigration" },
	{ "question": "入港", "answers": [ "にゅうこう" ], "comment": "entry into port" },
	{ "question": "入籍", "answers": [ "にゅうせき" ], "comment": "entry in family register" },
	{ "question": "入荷", "answers": [ "にゅうか" ], "comment": "arrival of goods; goods received" },
	{ "question": "入試", "answers": [ "にゅうし" ], "comment": "entrance examination" },
	{ "question": "入賞", "answers": [ "にゅうしょう" ], "comment": "winning a prize or place (in a contest)" },
	{ "question": "入選", "answers": [ "にゅうせん" ], "comment": "chosen (in a competition)" },
	{ "question": "入閣", "answers": [ "にゅうかく" ], "comment": "joining the cabinet" },
	{ "question": "全人", "answers": [ "ぜんじん" ], "comment": "saint; person well-balanced morally and intellectually" },
	{ "question": "全会", "answers": [ "ぜんかい" ], "comment": "whole assembly" },
	{ "question": "全勝", "answers": [ "ぜんしょう" ], "comment": "complete victory\nwinning a tournament with no losses" },
	{ "question": "全域", "answers": [ "ぜんいき" ], "comment": "the whole area" },
	{ "question": "全学", "answers": [ "ぜんがく" ], "comment": "whole college" },
	{ "question": "全容", "answers": [ "ぜんよう" ], "comment": "full portrait; whole aspect; full story" },
	{ "question": "全廃", "answers": [ "ぜんぱい" ], "comment": "total abolition; full phase-out; total repeal" },
	{ "question": "全快", "answers": [ "ぜんかい" ], "comment": "complete recovery of health" },
	{ "question": "全文", "answers": [ "ぜんぶん" ], "comment": "whole passage; full text; whole sentence; full paragraph" },
	{ "question": "全日", "answers": [ "ぜんじつ" ], "comment": "all days" },
	{ "question": "全曲", "answers": [ "ぜんきょく" ], "comment": "all compositions; the entire composition" },
	{ "question": "全校", "answers": [ "ぜんこう" ], "comment": "the whole school" },
	{ "question": "全権", "answers": [ "ぜんけん" ], "comment": "plenipotentiary powers; full authority" },
	{ "question": "全治", "answers": [ "ぜんじ", "ぜんち" ], "comment": "complete recovery; healing" },
	{ "question": "全滅", "answers": [ "ぜんめつ" ], "comment": "annihilation; total destruction; complete destruction; crushing defeat" },
	{ "question": "全盛", "answers": [ "ぜんせい" ], "comment": "height of prosperity" },
	{ "question": "全社", "answers": [ "ぜんしゃ" ], "comment": "whole company; all the companies" },
	{ "question": "全米", "answers": [ "ぜんべい" ], "comment": "all-America; pan-American; all of America" },
	{ "question": "全線", "answers": [ "ぜんせん" ], "comment": "the whole line; all lines; the whole ship" },
	{ "question": "全量", "answers": [ "ぜんりょう" ], "comment": "the whole quantity" },
	{ "question": "全長", "answers": [ "ぜんちょう" ], "comment": "over-all length; span" },
	{ "question": "八つ当たり", "answers": [ "やつあたり" ], "comment": "outburst of anger; venting one's anger" },
	{ "question": "八丁", "answers": [ "はっちょう" ], "comment": "skillfulness" },
	{ "question": "八幡", "answers": [ "はちまん" ], "comment": "Hachiman (God of War)\nHachiman shrine\ncertainly" },
	{ "question": "八方", "answers": [ "はっぽう" ], "comment": "all sides; the four cardinal directions and the four ordinal directions\nlarge hanging lantern" },
	{ "question": "八重", "answers": [ "やえ" ], "comment": "multilayered; doubled" },
	{ "question": "公人", "answers": [ "こうじん" ], "comment": "public character" },
	{ "question": "公使", "answers": [ "こうし" ], "comment": "envoy; diplomat below the rank of ambassador (e.g. deputy chief of mission, charge d'affaires); minister (of legation)" },
	{ "question": "公債", "answers": [ "こうさい" ], "comment": "public debt; public bond or securities" },
	{ "question": "公判", "answers": [ "こうはん" ], "comment": "public hearing; trial" },
	{ "question": "公募", "answers": [ "こうぼ" ], "comment": "public appeal (e.g. for contributions); public offering (of securities); public advertisement (of a post); open recruitment" },
	{ "question": "公取委", "answers": [ "こうとりい" ], "comment": "Fair Trade Commission" },
	{ "question": "公司", "answers": [ "こうし", "コンス" ], "comment": "company; firm (in China)" },
	{ "question": "公営", "answers": [ "こうえい" ], "comment": "public management" },
	{ "question": "公報", "answers": [ "こうほう" ], "comment": "official bulletin; communique" },
	{ "question": "公子", "answers": [ "こうし" ], "comment": "young nobleman" },
	{ "question": "公安", "answers": [ "こうあん" ], "comment": "public safety; public welfare" },
	{ "question": "公定", "answers": [ "こうてい" ], "comment": "official (rate, price, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "公布", "answers": [ "こうふ" ], "comment": "official proclamation; announcement; promulgation (e.g. of regulations)" },
	{ "question": "公庫", "answers": [ "こうこ" ], "comment": "finance corporation" },
	{ "question": "公文", "answers": [ "こうぶん" ], "comment": "official document; archives" },
	{ "question": "公明", "answers": [ "こうめい" ], "comment": "fairness; justice" },
	{ "question": "公有", "answers": [ "こうゆう" ], "comment": "public ownership" },
	{ "question": "公民", "answers": [ "こうみん" ], "comment": "citizen; freemen" },
	{ "question": "公海", "answers": [ "こうかい" ], "comment": "high seas; international waters" },
	{ "question": "公用", "answers": [ "こうよう" ], "comment": "government business; official business\npublic; official; governmental" },
	{ "question": "公益", "answers": [ "こうえき" ], "comment": "public interest; public benefit; public good" },
	{ "question": "公示", "answers": [ "こうし", "こうじ" ], "comment": "edict; public announcement" },
	{ "question": "公社", "answers": [ "こうしゃ" ], "comment": "public corporation" },
	{ "question": "公社債", "answers": [ "こうしゃさい" ], "comment": "public bonds" },
	{ "question": "公私", "answers": [ "こうし" ], "comment": "public and private; official and personal; government and people" },
	{ "question": "公称", "answers": [ "こうしょう" ], "comment": "public name; announcing publicly\nnominal" },
	{ "question": "公算", "answers": [ "こうさん" ], "comment": "probability; likelihood" },
	{ "question": "公約", "answers": [ "こうやく" ], "comment": "public commitment; public promise; campaign pledge; official vow" },
	{ "question": "公職", "answers": [ "こうしょく" ], "comment": "public office" },
	{ "question": "公言", "answers": [ "こうげん" ], "comment": "declaration; profession" },
	{ "question": "公設", "answers": [ "こうせつ" ], "comment": "public (institution)" },
	{ "question": "公訴", "answers": [ "こうそ" ], "comment": "accusation; prosecution" },
	{ "question": "公論", "answers": [ "こうろん" ], "comment": "public opinion; unbiased criticism; unbiassed criticism" },
	{ "question": "公費", "answers": [ "こうひ" ], "comment": "public expense; public funds; public money; public expenditure" },
	{ "question": "公選", "answers": [ "こうせん" ], "comment": "public election" },
	{ "question": "公邸", "answers": [ "こうてい" ], "comment": "official residence" },
	{ "question": "公金", "answers": [ "こうきん" ], "comment": "public funds" },
	{ "question": "公館", "answers": [ "こうかん" ], "comment": "official residence" },
	{ "question": "共々", "answers": [ "ともども" ], "comment": "together; in company" },
	{ "question": "共催", "answers": [ "きょうさい" ], "comment": "joint sponsorship" },
	{ "question": "共働き", "answers": [ "ともばたらき" ], "comment": "(husband and wife) both working; dual income" },
	{ "question": "共学", "answers": [ "きょうがく" ], "comment": "coeducation" },
	{ "question": "共栄", "answers": [ "きょうえい" ], "comment": "mutual prosperity" },
	{ "question": "共演", "answers": [ "きょうえん" ], "comment": "appearing together; co-acting; co-starring" },
	{ "question": "共犯", "answers": [ "きょうはん" ], "comment": "complicity" },
	{ "question": "共生", "answers": [ "きょうせい", "ともいき" ], "comment": "symbiosis; paragenesis; union" },
	{ "question": "共用", "answers": [ "きょうよう" ], "comment": "common use; communal use; sharing" },
	{ "question": "共稼ぎ", "answers": [ "ともかせぎ" ], "comment": "working together; (husband and wife) earning a living together" },
	{ "question": "共立", "answers": [ "きょうりつ" ], "comment": "joint; common" },
	{ "question": "共著", "answers": [ "きょうちょ" ], "comment": "collaboration; co-authorship" },
	{ "question": "共謀", "answers": [ "きょうぼう" ], "comment": "conspiracy; collusion; complicity; being in cahoots" },
	{ "question": "共闘", "answers": [ "きょうとう" ], "comment": "joint struggle; common (united) front" },
	{ "question": "共鳴", "answers": [ "きょうめい" ], "comment": "resonance; sympathetic (sound); (being in) sympathy" },
	{ "question": "兵員", "answers": [ "へいいん" ], "comment": "military strength; military personnel" },
	{ "question": "兵役", "answers": [ "へいえき" ], "comment": "military service; conscription" },
	{ "question": "兵舎", "answers": [ "へいしゃ" ], "comment": "barracks" },
	{ "question": "具わる", "answers": [ "そなわる" ], "comment": "to be furnished with; to be provided with; to be equipped with\nto be possessed of; to be endowed with; to be gifted with\nto be among; to be one of" },
	{ "question": "具象", "answers": [ "ぐしょう" ], "comment": "embodying; expressing concretely" },
	{ "question": "兼ね備える", "answers": [ "かねそなえる" ], "comment": "to have both; to possess both; to combine with" },
	{ "question": "兼ね合い", "answers": [ "かねあい" ], "comment": "equilibrium; good balance; poise" },
	{ "question": "兼任", "answers": [ "けんにん" ], "comment": "concurrent post\nto hold two posts concurrently" },
	{ "question": "兼務", "answers": [ "けんむ" ], "comment": "holding two posts concurrently" },
	{ "question": "内々", "answers": [ "うちうち", "ないない" ], "comment": "family circle; the inside; private; informal; secret; confidential" },
	{ "question": "内乱", "answers": [ "ないらん" ], "comment": "civil war; insurrection; rebellion; domestic conflict" },
	{ "question": "内包", "answers": [ "ないほう" ], "comment": "connotation; comprehension; intension\ninclusion; containment within" },
	{ "question": "内向", "answers": [ "ないこう" ], "comment": "introvert" },
	{ "question": "内定", "answers": [ "ないてい" ], "comment": "unofficial offer (esp. job offer); tentative decision" },
	{ "question": "内実", "answers": [ "ないじつ" ], "comment": "the facts" },
	{ "question": "内幕", "answers": [ "ないまく", "うちまく" ], "comment": "lowdown; inside curtain; inside information; hidden circumstances; inside facts; inner workings; undisclosed circumstances" },
	{ "question": "内情", "answers": [ "ないじょう" ], "comment": "internal conditions; true state of affairs" },
	{ "question": "内戦", "answers": [ "ないせん" ], "comment": "civil war" },
	{ "question": "内政", "answers": [ "ないせい" ], "comment": "domestic affairs; internal administration" },
	{ "question": "内気", "answers": [ "うちき" ], "comment": "bashfulness; shyness; reserve; timidity" },
	{ "question": "内申", "answers": [ "ないしん" ], "comment": "unofficial report; confidential report" },
	{ "question": "内示", "answers": [ "ないじ" ], "comment": "unofficial announcement" },
	{ "question": "内職", "answers": [ "ないしょく" ], "comment": "side job (at home); home industry; side line" },
	{ "question": "内蔵", "answers": [ "ないぞう" ], "comment": "internal (e.g. disk); built-in; equipped (with)" },
	{ "question": "内装", "answers": [ "ないそう" ], "comment": "interior design; interior; upholstery" },
	{ "question": "内規", "answers": [ "ないき" ], "comment": "private regulations; bylaws; internal rules; tradition" },
	{ "question": "内角", "answers": [ "ないかく" ], "comment": "interior angle; internal angle\ninside corner" },
	{ "question": "内訳", "answers": [ "うちわけ" ], "comment": "itemization (of expenses); the items; breakdown; classification" },
	{ "question": "内輪", "answers": [ "うちわ" ], "comment": "moderate; private matter; family circle; the inside\nconservative\npigeon-toed" },
	{ "question": "内野", "answers": [ "ないや" ], "comment": "infield; diamond" },
	{ "question": "内需", "answers": [ "ないじゅ" ], "comment": "domestic demand" },
	{ "question": "円卓", "answers": [ "えんたく" ], "comment": "round table" },
	{ "question": "円安", "answers": [ "えんやす" ], "comment": "cheap yen" },
	{ "question": "円建て", "answers": [ "えんだて" ], "comment": "denominated in yen; yen-denominated; yen base" },
	{ "question": "円満", "answers": [ "えんまん" ], "comment": "perfection; harmony; peace; smoothness; completeness; satisfaction; integrity" },
	{ "question": "円盤", "answers": [ "えんばん" ], "comment": "disk; discus; platter\nflying saucer\ndisc media (CD, DVD, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "円筒", "answers": [ "えんとう" ], "comment": "cylinder" },
	{ "question": "円高", "answers": [ "えんだか" ], "comment": "appreciation of the yen; strong yen; strengthening of the yen; high-valued yen; exchange in favor of the yen (favour)" },
	{ "question": "冊子", "answers": [ "さっし" ], "comment": "book; booklet; story book; pamphlet; notebook" },
	{ "question": "再任", "answers": [ "さいにん" ], "comment": "reappointment" },
	{ "question": "再審", "answers": [ "さいしん" ], "comment": "retrial; reopening of a case\nreview; reexamination" },
	{ "question": "再来", "answers": [ "さいらい" ], "comment": "return; coming back\nsecond coming (e.g. of Christ); second advent; reincarnation" },
	{ "question": "再演", "answers": [ "さいえん" ], "comment": "another showing (of a play)\nrecapitulation" },
	{ "question": "再燃", "answers": [ "さいねん" ], "comment": "recurrence; revival; resuscitation" },
	{ "question": "再発", "answers": [ "さいはつ" ], "comment": "return; relapse; reoccurrence" },
	{ "question": "再編", "answers": [ "さいへん" ], "comment": "reorganization; reorganisation; reshuffle" },
	{ "question": "再考", "answers": [ "さいこう" ], "comment": "reconsideration" },
	{ "question": "再販", "answers": [ "さいはん" ], "comment": "resale" },
	{ "question": "再起", "answers": [ "さいき" ], "comment": "comeback; recovery; restoration; rally; reflexive (in grammar)" },
	{ "question": "再選", "answers": [ "さいせん" ], "comment": "re-election" },
	{ "question": "冬休み", "answers": [ "ふゆやすみ" ], "comment": "winter vacation" },
	{ "question": "冬場", "answers": [ "ふゆば" ], "comment": "the winter season" },
	{ "question": "冬季", "answers": [ "とうき" ], "comment": "(season of) winter" },
	{ "question": "冬期", "answers": [ "とうき" ], "comment": "winter; wintertime; winter term" },
	{ "question": "冬眠", "answers": [ "とうみん" ], "comment": "hibernation; winter sleep" },
	{ "question": "冬至", "answers": [ "とうじ" ], "comment": "winter solstice" },
	{ "question": "冷え", "answers": [ "ひえ" ], "comment": "chilliness; coldness" },
	{ "question": "冷え性", "answers": [ "ひえしょう" ], "comment": "sensitivity to cold" },
	{ "question": "冷え込む", "answers": [ "ひえこむ" ], "comment": "to get colder; to get chilled" },
	{ "question": "冷やかす", "answers": [ "ひやかす" ], "comment": "to banter; to make fun of; to jeer at\nto cool; to refrigerate\nto window-shop; to look at without buying" },
	{ "question": "冷ややか", "answers": [ "ひややか" ], "comment": "cold; chilly; cool\nindifferent; cold-hearted; surly; curt; composed" },
	{ "question": "冷や汗", "answers": [ "ひやあせ", "れいかん" ], "comment": "cold sweat" },
	{ "question": "冷却", "answers": [ "れいきゃく" ], "comment": "cooling; refrigeration" },
	{ "question": "冷夏", "answers": [ "れいか" ], "comment": "cool summer; cold summer; cooler-than-normal summer" },
	{ "question": "冷害", "answers": [ "れいがい" ], "comment": "cold-weather damage" },
	{ "question": "冷暖房", "answers": [ "れいだんぼう" ], "comment": "air-conditioning; heating and cooling" },
	{ "question": "冷水", "answers": [ "れいすい" ], "comment": "cold water" },
	{ "question": "冷汗", "answers": [ "ひやあせ", "れいかん" ], "comment": "cold sweat" },
	{ "question": "冷淡", "answers": [ "れいたん" ], "comment": "coolness; indifference" },
	{ "question": "冷酷", "answers": [ "れいこく" ], "comment": "cruelty; coldheartedness; relentless; ruthless" },
	{ "question": "凝固", "answers": [ "ぎょうこ" ], "comment": "coagulation; freezing; solidification" },
	{ "question": "凝縮", "answers": [ "ぎょうしゅく" ], "comment": "condensation (of ideas, emotions, etc.)\ncondensation (of a vapour or gas)" },
	{ "question": "几帳面", "answers": [ "きちょうめん" ], "comment": "methodical; punctual; steady" },
	{ "question": "凡人", "answers": [ "ぼんじん", "ぼんにん" ], "comment": "ordinary person; average person; mediocre" },
	{ "question": "処遇", "answers": [ "しょぐう" ], "comment": "treatment (of a person); dealing with" },
	{ "question": "凧", "answers": [ "いかのぼり", "はた", "たこ", "いか" ], "comment": "kite" },
	{ "question": "凶作", "answers": [ "きょうさく" ], "comment": "bad harvest; poor crop" },
	{ "question": "凶器", "answers": [ "きょうき" ], "comment": "dangerous weapon; lethal weapon; deadly weapon; murder weapon" },
	{ "question": "凶悪", "answers": [ "きょうあく" ], "comment": "atrocious; fiendish; brutal; villainous" },
	{ "question": "凹み", "answers": [ "へこみ", "くぼみ" ], "comment": "hollow; cavity; dent; depression" },
	{ "question": "出入", "answers": [ "しゅつにゅう" ], "comment": "in and out; income and expenses; free associations; run of the house" },
	{ "question": "出前", "answers": [ "でまえ" ], "comment": "catering; meal delivery service" },
	{ "question": "出動", "answers": [ "しゅつどう" ], "comment": "sailing; marching; going out; dispatch" },
	{ "question": "出向", "answers": [ "しゅっこう" ], "comment": "secondment; temporary transfer\nproceeding; leaving for" },
	{ "question": "出国", "answers": [ "しゅっこく" ], "comment": "departure from a country" },
	{ "question": "出場", "answers": [ "しゅつじょう" ], "comment": "(stage) appearance; performance\nparticipation (e.g. in a tournament)" },
	{ "question": "出塁", "answers": [ "しゅつるい" ], "comment": "on base" },
	{ "question": "出展", "answers": [ "しゅってん" ], "comment": "exhibit; display" },
	{ "question": "出店", "answers": [ "でみせ" ], "comment": "food stand; food stall\nbranch store" },
	{ "question": "出撃", "answers": [ "しゅつげき" ], "comment": "sortie; sally" },
	{ "question": "出方", "answers": [ "でかた" ], "comment": "attitude; approach; move\ntheater usher; theatre usher" },
	{ "question": "出来高", "answers": [ "できだか" ], "comment": "yield; crop; production; volume; piecework" },
	{ "question": "出欠", "answers": [ "しゅっけつ" ], "comment": "presence or absence; attendance (e.g. when taking a rollcall)" },
	{ "question": "出港", "answers": [ "しゅっこう" ], "comment": "departure; clearance (of a ship)" },
	{ "question": "出火", "answers": [ "しゅっか" ], "comment": "outbreak of fire" },
	{ "question": "出番", "answers": [ "でばん" ], "comment": "one's turn; one's shift\none's turn on stage; screen time; screentime" },
	{ "question": "出直し", "answers": [ "でなおし" ], "comment": "adjustment; touch up" },
	{ "question": "出稼ぎ", "answers": [ "でかせぎ" ], "comment": "working away from home" },
	{ "question": "出納", "answers": [ "すいとう" ], "comment": "receipts and expenditure (disbursements)" },
	{ "question": "出荷", "answers": [ "しゅっか" ], "comment": "shipping; outgoing freight; forwarding" },
	{ "question": "出走", "answers": [ "しゅっそう" ], "comment": "entry in a race" },
	{ "question": "出足", "answers": [ "であし" ], "comment": "turnout (of people)\nstart (e.g. race, campaign, term of office)\nconstant forward movement; initial charge; dash" },
	{ "question": "出金", "answers": [ "しゅっきん" ], "comment": "withdrawal (of money); payment; contribution; investment; financing" },
	{ "question": "出陣", "answers": [ "しゅつじん" ], "comment": "departure for the front" },
	{ "question": "出頭", "answers": [ "しゅっとう" ], "comment": "appearance; presence; attendance\nsurrender (e.g. to the police); turning oneself in (e.g. to the police)" },
	{ "question": "出題", "answers": [ "しゅつだい" ], "comment": "setting a question (for an exam)\nsetting a theme (for composition of poetry)" },
	{ "question": "出馬", "answers": [ "しゅつば" ], "comment": "running (for election); coming forward as a candidate\ngoing on horseback\ngoing in person\nletting out a horse; taking out a horse" },
	{ "question": "刃渡り", "answers": [ "はわたり" ], "comment": "length of a blade (sword, knife, etc.)\nwalking on the edge of a sword" },
	{ "question": "刃物", "answers": [ "はもの" ], "comment": "edged tool; cutlery" },
	{ "question": "分かち", "answers": [ "わかち" ], "comment": "distinction; differentiation; discrimination" },
	{ "question": "分かつ", "answers": [ "わかつ" ], "comment": "to divide; to separate\nto share; to distribute\nto distinguish" },
	{ "question": "分かれ目", "answers": [ "わかれめ" ], "comment": "fork; junction; parting of the ways\nturning point" },
	{ "question": "分け", "answers": [ "わけ" ], "comment": "sharing; division\ndraw; tie" },
	{ "question": "分乗", "answers": [ "ぶんじょう" ], "comment": "riding separately" },
	{ "question": "分校", "answers": [ "ぶんこう" ], "comment": "branch school" },
	{ "question": "分業", "answers": [ "ぶんぎょう" ], "comment": "division of labor; division of labour; specialization; specialisation; assembly-line production" },
	{ "question": "分権", "answers": [ "ぶんけん" ], "comment": "decentralization of authority; decentralisation of authority" },
	{ "question": "分母", "answers": [ "ぶんぼ" ], "comment": "denominator" },
	{ "question": "分泌", "answers": [ "ぶんぴ", "ぶんぴつ" ], "comment": "secretion" },
	{ "question": "分立", "answers": [ "ぶんりつ" ], "comment": "segregation; separation; independence" },
	{ "question": "分譲", "answers": [ "ぶんじょう" ], "comment": "selling (real-estate) lots" },
	{ "question": "分身", "answers": [ "ぶんしん" ], "comment": "parturition; delivery; one's child; branch; offshoot; one's other self" },
	{ "question": "切らす", "answers": [ "きらす" ], "comment": "to be out of; to run out of; to be short of; to be out of stock" },
	{ "question": "切り下げ", "answers": [ "きりさげ" ], "comment": "devaluation (e.g. of currency); markdown; write-down; undercutting" },
	{ "question": "切り口", "answers": [ "きりくち" ], "comment": "cut end; section; opening; slit\npoint of view; (different) perspective; new approach" },
	{ "question": "切り抜き", "answers": [ "きりぬき" ], "comment": "clipping (of newspaper article, etc.); cutting; scrap (for a scrapbook)\ncut-out (picture, coloured paper, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "切り捨て", "answers": [ "きりすて" ], "comment": "cutting a person down (without a second thought); sacrificing; throwing to the wolves; treating as sword fodder\nomission; rounding down (e.g. fractions); truncation" },
	{ "question": "切り替え", "answers": [ "きりかえ" ], "comment": "exchange; conversion; replacement; switching (to); switchover" },
	{ "question": "切り札", "answers": [ "きりふだ" ], "comment": "trump card\nace up one's sleeve; secret weapon" },
	{ "question": "切れ味", "answers": [ "きれあじ" ], "comment": "sharpness; cutting ability\nquickness (of wit); incisiveness; technical proficiency; skill\npeppiness (of a ball)" },
	{ "question": "切れ目", "answers": [ "きれめ" ], "comment": "break; pause; gap; end; rift; interruption; cut; section; notch; incision; end (of a task)" },
	{ "question": "切実", "answers": [ "せつじつ" ], "comment": "earnest; sincere; acute; keen; fervent\npressing; urgent; serious; severe\npertinent; appropriate" },
	{ "question": "切望", "answers": [ "せつぼう" ], "comment": "longing for; earnest desire; desperate desire; hope; yearning; hankering" },
	{ "question": "刈り込む", "answers": [ "かりこむ" ], "comment": "to cut; to dress; to prune; to trim; to clip" },
	{ "question": "刑法", "answers": [ "けいほう" ], "comment": "criminal law; penal code" },
	{ "question": "刑罰", "answers": [ "けいばつ" ], "comment": "judgement; judgment; penalty; punishment" },
	{ "question": "列挙", "answers": [ "れっきょ" ], "comment": "enumeration; list" },
	{ "question": "初", "answers": [ "はつ", "うい" ], "comment": "first; new" },
	{ "question": "初出", "answers": [ "しょしゅつ" ], "comment": "first appearance" },
	{ "question": "初回", "answers": [ "しょかい" ], "comment": "first time; first innings; initial attempt\nfirst; initial" },
	{ "question": "初夏", "answers": [ "はつなつ", "しょか" ], "comment": "early summer\nfourth month of the lunar calendar" },
	{ "question": "初夢", "answers": [ "はつゆめ" ], "comment": "year's first dream" },
	{ "question": "初年", "answers": [ "しょねん" ], "comment": "first year; early years (of a reign or era)" },
	{ "question": "初恋", "answers": [ "はつこい" ], "comment": "first love; puppy love" },
	{ "question": "初戦", "answers": [ "しょせん" ], "comment": "first match (in a series)" },
	{ "question": "初演", "answers": [ "しょえん" ], "comment": "first performance" },
	{ "question": "初版", "answers": [ "しょはん" ], "comment": "first edition" },
	{ "question": "初球", "answers": [ "しょきゅう" ], "comment": "pitcher's first pitch (to batter)" },
	{ "question": "初老", "answers": [ "しょろう" ], "comment": "past middle-aged; aging; ageing; elderly\nage 40" },
	{ "question": "初詣", "answers": [ "はつもうで" ], "comment": "first shrine visit of New Year" },
	{ "question": "初詣で", "answers": [ "はつもうで" ], "comment": "first shrine visit of New Year" },
	{ "question": "初陣", "answers": [ "ういじん" ], "comment": "first campaign; one's first battle" },
	{ "question": "初雪", "answers": [ "はつゆき" ], "comment": "first snow (of season)" },
	{ "question": "別個", "answers": [ "べっこ" ], "comment": "another; different; separate; discrete" },
	{ "question": "別冊", "answers": [ "べっさつ" ], "comment": "separate volume; extra issue; supplement; additional volume; supplementary volume" },
	{ "question": "別名", "answers": [ "べつみょう", "べつめい" ], "comment": "alias; pseudonym; pen name; nom de plume; different name; other name" },
	{ "question": "別室", "answers": [ "べっしつ" ], "comment": "separate room; another room\nspecial room\nconcubine (of a noble)" },
	{ "question": "別表", "answers": [ "べっぴょう" ], "comment": "annexed (statistical) table" },
	{ "question": "別院", "answers": [ "べついん" ], "comment": "branch temple" },
	{ "question": "別館", "answers": [ "べっかん" ], "comment": "(hotel) annexe (annex)" },
	{ "question": "利上げ", "answers": [ "りあげ" ], "comment": "increase in interest rates" },
	{ "question": "利便", "answers": [ "りべん" ], "comment": "convenience" },
	{ "question": "利回り", "answers": [ "りまわり" ], "comment": "interest; (investment) yield; profits" },
	{ "question": "利払い", "answers": [ "りばらい" ], "comment": "interest payment" },
	{ "question": "利権", "answers": [ "りけん" ], "comment": "interest; rights; concession" },
	{ "question": "利潤", "answers": [ "りじゅん" ], "comment": "profit; returns" },
	{ "question": "利率", "answers": [ "りりつ" ], "comment": "interest rate" },
	{ "question": "制する", "answers": [ "せいする" ], "comment": "to hold back (e.g. emotions); to rein in (e.g. a horse, unruly people); to bridle\nto get the better of\nto control; to command" },
	{ "question": "制圧", "answers": [ "せいあつ" ], "comment": "gaining total control (of people or counties); suppression; oppression; control; mastery; ascendancy; supremacy" },
	{ "question": "制止", "answers": [ "せいし" ], "comment": "control; check; restraint; inhibition" },
	{ "question": "制裁", "answers": [ "せいさい" ], "comment": "restraint; sanctions; punishment" },
	{ "question": "制覇", "answers": [ "せいは" ], "comment": "conquest; domination; mastery" },
	{ "question": "刷新", "answers": [ "さっしん" ], "comment": "reform; renovation" },
	{ "question": "刺し", "answers": [ "さし" ], "comment": "grain thief; sharpened tube for testing rice in bags\nsashimi (sliced raw fish)\nstabbing; piercing; pricking" },
	{ "question": "刺繍", "answers": [ "ししゅう" ], "comment": "embroidery" },
	{ "question": "刻", "answers": [ "こく" ], "comment": "archaic period of time (usu. a period of approx. two hours corresponding to one of the signs of the Chinese zodiac)\ncarving; engraving; cutting; mincing\nvictory\nstrictness; cruelty" },
	{ "question": "刻々", "answers": [ "こくこく", "こっこく" ], "comment": "moment by moment; hour by hour" },
	{ "question": "刻み", "answers": [ "きざみ" ], "comment": "shredded tobacco; notch; nick" },
	{ "question": "削り節", "answers": [ "けずりぶし" ], "comment": "flaked bonito" },
	{ "question": "前々", "answers": [ "まえまえ" ], "comment": "beforehand; for a long time" },
	{ "question": "前例", "answers": [ "ぜんれい" ], "comment": "precedent" },
	{ "question": "前倒し", "answers": [ "まえだおし" ], "comment": "moving forward (e.g. plans); acceleration (e.g. of payment schedule); front-loading" },
	{ "question": "前借り", "answers": [ "まえがり" ], "comment": "getting an advance (on one's salary)" },
	{ "question": "前兆", "answers": [ "ぜんちょう" ], "comment": "omen; portent; sign; premonition; harbinger" },
	{ "question": "前売り", "answers": [ "まえうり" ], "comment": "advance sale; booking" },
	{ "question": "前払い", "answers": [ "まえばらい" ], "comment": "payment in advance; prepayment" },
	{ "question": "前文", "answers": [ "ぜんぶん" ], "comment": "preamble\nthe above statement" },
	{ "question": "前書き", "answers": [ "まえがき" ], "comment": "preface; preamble; prolog" },
	{ "question": "前略", "answers": [ "ぜんりゃく" ], "comment": "Forgive me for dispensing with the preliminaries, but I hasten to inform you that...\nomitting the beginning" },
	{ "question": "前置き", "answers": [ "まえおき" ], "comment": "preface; introduction" },
	{ "question": "前衛", "answers": [ "ぜんえい" ], "comment": "advance guard; vanguard\navant-garde (e.g. music)" },
	{ "question": "前触れ", "answers": [ "まえぶれ" ], "comment": "advance warning; previous notice; announcement\nherald; harbinger; forerunner; portent; omen" },
	{ "question": "前身", "answers": [ "ぜんしん" ], "comment": "antecedents; ancestor; previous position; previous existence; predecessor organization; predecessor organisation" },
	{ "question": "前途", "answers": [ "ぜんと" ], "comment": "future prospects; outlook; the journey ahead" },
	{ "question": "前週", "answers": [ "ぜんしゅう" ], "comment": "last week; the week before" },
	{ "question": "前部", "answers": [ "ぜんぶ" ], "comment": "front part; fore; front" },
	{ "question": "前頭", "answers": [ "まえがしら" ], "comment": "rank-and-file wrestlers in the highest division" },
	{ "question": "剣士", "answers": [ "けんし" ], "comment": "swordsman; swordswoman; fencer" },
	{ "question": "剣道", "answers": [ "けんどう" ], "comment": "kendo; swordmanship; fencing; way of the sword" },
	{ "question": "剥ぐ", "answers": [ "へぐ", "はぐ" ], "comment": "to tear off; to peel off; to rip off; to strip off; to skin; to flay; to bark; to disrobe\nto strip of (e.g. clothes, rank); to deprive of; to divest" },
	{ "question": "副", "answers": [ "ふく" ], "comment": "assistant; associate; vice-; sub-; deputy; substitute; auxiliary; supplementary; additional; collateral\nduplicate; copy\nadverb" },
	{ "question": "副賞", "answers": [ "ふくしょう" ], "comment": "extra prize" },
	{ "question": "副題", "answers": [ "ふくだい" ], "comment": "subtitle; subheading" },
	{ "question": "割り出す", "answers": [ "わりだす" ], "comment": "to calculate; to compute; to infer" },
	{ "question": "割り引く", "answers": [ "わりびく" ], "comment": "to discount" },
	{ "question": "割り当て", "answers": [ "かっとう", "わりあて" ], "comment": "allotment; assignment; allocation; quota; rationing\nallocation" },
	{ "question": "割り当てる", "answers": [ "わりあてる" ], "comment": "to assign; to allot; to allocate; to divide among; to distribute; to prorate; to apportion" },
	{ "question": "割り箸", "answers": [ "わりばし" ], "comment": "splittable (wood) chopsticks" },
	{ "question": "割れ目", "answers": [ "われめ" ], "comment": "chasm; interstice; crevice; crack; cleft; split; rift; fissure\nvulva; slit; cunt; vagina; twat" },
	{ "question": "割出す", "answers": [ "わりだす" ], "comment": "to calculate; to compute; to infer" },
	{ "question": "割安", "answers": [ "わりやす" ], "comment": "economical; comparatively cheap" },
	{ "question": "割引く", "answers": [ "わりびく" ], "comment": "to discount" },
	{ "question": "割当てる", "answers": [ "わりあてる" ], "comment": "to assign; to allot; to allocate; to divide among; to distribute; to prorate; to apportion" },
	{ "question": "割高", "answers": [ "わりだか" ], "comment": "comparatively high; fairly expensive" },
	{ "question": "創始", "answers": [ "そうし" ], "comment": "creation; founding; initiating" },
	{ "question": "創意", "answers": [ "そうい" ], "comment": "original idea; originality" },
	{ "question": "劇作", "answers": [ "げきさく" ], "comment": "play writing" },
	{ "question": "劇団", "answers": [ "げきだん" ], "comment": "troupe; theatrical company" },
	{ "question": "劇画", "answers": [ "げきが" ], "comment": "comic strip with dramatic story" },
	{ "question": "力む", "answers": [ "りきむ" ], "comment": "to strain; to bear up; to exert one's strength\nto swagger; to bluff; to boast" },
	{ "question": "力作", "answers": [ "りきさく" ], "comment": "tour de force; painstaking piece of work; achievement" },
	{ "question": "力士", "answers": [ "りきし" ], "comment": "sumo wrestler; rikishi\nstrong man" },
	{ "question": "力学", "answers": [ "りきがく" ], "comment": "mechanics; dynamics" },
	{ "question": "力持ち", "answers": [ "ちからもち" ], "comment": "muscleman; strong man" },
	{ "question": "力点", "answers": [ "りきてん" ], "comment": "leverage; emphasis; importance" },
	{ "question": "力説", "answers": [ "りきせつ" ], "comment": "insistence; (major) emphasis; stress" },
	{ "question": "力量", "answers": [ "りきりょう" ], "comment": "ability; capacity; capability; talent\nphysical strength" },
	{ "question": "功労", "answers": [ "こうろう" ], "comment": "meritorious deed; services" },
	{ "question": "加味", "answers": [ "かみ" ], "comment": "seasoning; flavoring; flavouring\naddition; inclusion; taking into account" },
	{ "question": "加圧", "answers": [ "かあつ" ], "comment": "increasing pressure" },
	{ "question": "加担", "answers": [ "かたん" ], "comment": "support; participation; assistance; complicity; conspiracy" },
	{ "question": "加点", "answers": [ "かてん" ], "comment": "addition of points; scoring" },
	{ "question": "加重", "answers": [ "かじゅう", "かちょう" ], "comment": "weighting (in averaging); aggravation" },
	{ "question": "劣勢", "answers": [ "れっせい" ], "comment": "inferiority (e.g. numerical); inferior position; disadvantage; unfavorable situation; unfavourable situation" },
	{ "question": "劣化", "answers": [ "れっか" ], "comment": "deterioration; degradation; drop in quality" },
	{ "question": "劣悪", "answers": [ "れつあく" ], "comment": "inferiority; coarseness" },
	{ "question": "助け合い", "answers": [ "たすけあい" ], "comment": "cooperation; mutual aid (help)" },
	{ "question": "助っ人", "answers": [ "すけっと" ], "comment": "helper; supporter; second; backer" },
	{ "question": "助役", "answers": [ "じょやく" ], "comment": "assistant official" },
	{ "question": "助成", "answers": [ "じょせい" ], "comment": "assisting; assistance; fostering; aiding" },
	{ "question": "助演", "answers": [ "じょえん" ], "comment": "co-star" },
	{ "question": "助詞", "answers": [ "じょし" ], "comment": "particle; postposition" },
	{ "question": "励まし", "answers": [ "はげまし" ], "comment": "encouragement (as an abstract concept); stimulation" },
	{ "question": "励み", "answers": [ "はげみ" ], "comment": "(act of) encouragement; stimulus; incentive" },
	{ "question": "労作", "answers": [ "ろうさく" ], "comment": "toil; labor; labour; laborious task" },
	{ "question": "労使", "answers": [ "ろうし" ], "comment": "labour and management; labor and management" },
	{ "question": "労力", "answers": [ "ろうりょく" ], "comment": "labour; labor; effort; toil; trouble" },
	{ "question": "労務", "answers": [ "ろうむ" ], "comment": "labor; labour; work; service" },
	{ "question": "労災", "answers": [ "ろうさい" ], "comment": "work-related injury; work-related illness; work-related death; on-the-job accident\nworkers' compensation insurance" },
	{ "question": "労相", "answers": [ "ろうしょう" ], "comment": "Labor Minister" },
	{ "question": "労組", "answers": [ "ろうそ", "ろうくみ" ], "comment": "labor union; labour union; trade union" },
	{ "question": "労連", "answers": [ "ろうれん" ], "comment": "labour union; labor union" },
	{ "question": "効き目", "answers": [ "ききめ" ], "comment": "effect; virtue; efficacy; impression" },
	{ "question": "効能", "answers": [ "こうのう" ], "comment": "effect; efficacy; virtue; benefit" },
	{ "question": "勃起", "answers": [ "ぼっき" ], "comment": "erection (usu. penis); standing erect; stiffening" },
	{ "question": "勅", "answers": [ "ちょく", "みことのり" ], "comment": "imperial decree; imperial edict" },
	{ "question": "勇敢", "answers": [ "ゆうかん" ], "comment": "brave; heroic; gallant" },
	{ "question": "勇退", "answers": [ "ゆうたい" ], "comment": "bowing out; retiring voluntarily" },
	{ "question": "勉学", "answers": [ "べんがく" ], "comment": "study; pursuit of knowledge" },
	{ "question": "動乱", "answers": [ "どうらん" ], "comment": "disturbance; agitation; commotion; upheaval; riot" },
	{ "question": "動力", "answers": [ "どうりょく" ], "comment": "power; motive power; dynamic force\nthree-phase electricity" },
	{ "question": "動態", "answers": [ "どうたい" ], "comment": "movement; dynamic state" },
	{ "question": "動植物", "answers": [ "どうしょくぶつ" ], "comment": "plants and animals; flora and fauna" },
	{ "question": "動脈", "answers": [ "どうみゃく" ], "comment": "artery" },
	{ "question": "動議", "answers": [ "どうぎ" ], "comment": "motion (i.e. proposal to a committee, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "動静", "answers": [ "どうせい" ], "comment": "state (of affairs); condition; developments; movements" },
	{ "question": "勘案", "answers": [ "かんあん" ], "comment": "taking into consideration; giving consideration (to); thinking" },
	{ "question": "勝ち星", "answers": [ "かちぼし" ], "comment": "(mark indicating) a win" },
	{ "question": "勝ち負け", "answers": [ "かちまけ" ], "comment": "victory or defeat" },
	{ "question": "勝因", "answers": [ "しょういん" ], "comment": "cause of victory" },
	{ "question": "勝率", "answers": [ "しょうりつ" ], "comment": "winning percentage" },
	{ "question": "勝者", "answers": [ "しょうしゃ" ], "comment": "winner; victor" },
	{ "question": "勝訴", "answers": [ "しょうそ" ], "comment": "winning a lawsuit" },
	{ "question": "募金", "answers": [ "ぼきん" ], "comment": "fund-raising; collection of funds" },
	{ "question": "勤め先", "answers": [ "つとめさき" ], "comment": "place of work" },
	{ "question": "勤勉", "answers": [ "きんべん" ], "comment": "diligent; industrious" },
	{ "question": "勤続", "answers": [ "きんぞく" ], "comment": "continuous service" },
	{ "question": "勧奨", "answers": [ "かんしょう" ], "comment": "encouragement; stimulation" },
	{ "question": "勲章", "answers": [ "くんしょう" ], "comment": "decoration; order; medal" },
	{ "question": "勾配", "answers": [ "こうばい" ], "comment": "slope; incline; gradient; grade; pitch\nslope (of a linear function)\ngradient (vector calculus)" },
	{ "question": "包み紙", "answers": [ "つつみがみ" ], "comment": "wrapping paper" },
	{ "question": "包囲", "answers": [ "ほうい" ], "comment": "siege; encirclement; envelopment; surrounding; besiegement" },
	{ "question": "化合", "answers": [ "かごう" ], "comment": "chemical combination" },
	{ "question": "化成", "answers": [ "かせい" ], "comment": "change; transformation" },
	{ "question": "化石", "answers": [ "かせき" ], "comment": "fossil; petrifaction; fossilization; fossilisation" },
	{ "question": "化繊", "answers": [ "かせん" ], "comment": "synthetic fibres; synthetic fibers" },
	{ "question": "北上", "answers": [ "ほくじょう" ], "comment": "going north" },
	{ "question": "北口", "answers": [ "きたぐち" ], "comment": "north entrance" },
	{ "question": "北国", "answers": [ "ほっこく", "きたぐに" ], "comment": "northern provinces; northern countries" },
	{ "question": "北東", "answers": [ "きたひがし", "ほくとう" ], "comment": "northeast" },
	{ "question": "北欧", "answers": [ "ほくおう" ], "comment": "Northern Europe; land of the Norsemen; Scandinavia" },
	{ "question": "北海", "answers": [ "ほっかい" ], "comment": "northern sea; North Sea" },
	{ "question": "北端", "answers": [ "ほくたん" ], "comment": "northern extremity" },
	{ "question": "北緯", "answers": [ "ほくい" ], "comment": "north latitude" },
	{ "question": "北西", "answers": [ "ほくせい" ], "comment": "northwest" },
	{ "question": "北風", "answers": [ "きたかぜ", "ほくふう" ], "comment": "north wind" },
	{ "question": "匹", "answers": [ "ひき", "き" ], "comment": "counter for small animals\ncounter for rolls of cloth (two han in size)\ncounter for horses\nroll of cloth" },
	{ "question": "区切り", "answers": [ "くぎり" ], "comment": "punctuation; pause; juncture\nend; (place to) stop" },
	{ "question": "区民", "answers": [ "くみん" ], "comment": "ward residents" },
	{ "question": "区議", "answers": [ "くぎ" ], "comment": "ward assemblyman" },
	{ "question": "区長", "answers": [ "くちょう" ], "comment": "head of a ward; mayor of a ward; chief administrator of a ward" },
	{ "question": "区間", "answers": [ "くかん" ], "comment": "section (of track, etc.); segment; dimension\ninterval" },
	{ "question": "医大", "answers": [ "いだい" ], "comment": "medical university; medical school; med school" },
	{ "question": "医局", "answers": [ "いきょく" ], "comment": "medical office; dispensary" },
	{ "question": "医科", "answers": [ "いか" ], "comment": "medical science; medical department" },
	{ "question": "医薬", "answers": [ "いやく" ], "comment": "medicine\nPharmaceutical and Food Safety Bureau" },
	{ "question": "医長", "answers": [ "いちょう" ], "comment": "medical director; chief physician" },
	{ "question": "匿名", "answers": [ "とくめい" ], "comment": "anonymity; using an assumed name" },
	{ "question": "十両", "answers": [ "じゅうりょう" ], "comment": "second highest division; wrestlers of the second highest division" },
	{ "question": "十二分", "answers": [ "じゅうにぶん" ], "comment": "more than enough; more than ample; exhaustive" },
	{ "question": "十八番", "answers": [ "じゅうはちばん", "おはこ" ], "comment": "one's favourite party trick (favorite); one's specialty; one's forte\nNo. 18; eighteenth\nrepertoire of 18 kabuki plays" },
	{ "question": "千代", "answers": [ "ちよ", "せんだい" ], "comment": "thousand years\nvery long period; forever" },
	{ "question": "午", "answers": [ "うま" ], "comment": "seventh sign of Chinese zodiac (The Horse, 11am-1pm, south, May)" },
	{ "question": "半々", "answers": [ "はんはん" ], "comment": "half and half; fifty-fifty" },
	{ "question": "半値", "answers": [ "はんね" ], "comment": "half price" },
	{ "question": "半期", "answers": [ "はんき" ], "comment": "half-term; half-time; half period" },
	{ "question": "半減", "answers": [ "はんげん" ], "comment": "reduction by half; halve" },
	{ "question": "半生", "answers": [ "はんせい" ], "comment": "half a lifetime" },
	{ "question": "半袖", "answers": [ "はんそで" ], "comment": "short sleeves" },
	{ "question": "半面", "answers": [ "はんめん" ], "comment": "half the face; one side; half; the other side; the reverse; the contrary" },
	{ "question": "半額", "answers": [ "はんがく" ], "comment": "half; half amount; half price; half fare" },
	{ "question": "卑しい", "answers": [ "いやしい" ], "comment": "lowborn; humble; lowly\nvulgar; coarse; crude; mean; base; vile\nshabby\ngreedy; gluttonous; avaricious" },
	{ "question": "卑劣", "answers": [ "ひれつ" ], "comment": "mean; foul play; cowardly; base" },
	{ "question": "卑怯", "answers": [ "ひきょう" ], "comment": "cowardice; meanness; unfairness" },
	{ "question": "卓", "answers": [ "たく", "しょく" ], "comment": "table; desk\ncounter for tables, desks, etc.\noffering table before an altar (sometimes used in tea ceremony)\ntabletop incense burner" },
	{ "question": "卓球", "answers": [ "たっきゅう" ], "comment": "table tennis; ping-pong" },
	{ "question": "卓越", "answers": [ "たくえつ" ], "comment": "preeminence; excellence; superiority; transcendence" },
	{ "question": "協和", "answers": [ "きょうわ" ], "comment": "concord; harmony; concert" },
	{ "question": "協議", "answers": [ "きょうぎ" ], "comment": "conference; consultation; discussion; negotiation" },
	{ "question": "協賛", "answers": [ "きょうさん" ], "comment": "support; mutual aid; cooperation; approval; authorization; authorisation" },
	{ "question": "南口", "answers": [ "みなみぐち" ], "comment": "south entrance" },
	{ "question": "南国", "answers": [ "なんごく", "なんこく" ], "comment": "southern countries" },
	{ "question": "南東", "answers": [ "みなみひがし", "なんとう" ], "comment": "southeast" },
	{ "question": "南海", "answers": [ "なんかい" ], "comment": "southern sea" },
	{ "question": "単価", "answers": [ "たんか" ], "comment": "unit price; unit cost" },
	{ "question": "単調", "answers": [ "たんちょう" ], "comment": "monotony; monotone; dullness\nmonotone; monotonic" },
	{ "question": "博", "answers": [ "はく", "ばく" ], "comment": "doctor; PhD\nexposition; fair; exhibition" },
	{ "question": "博学", "answers": [ "はくがく" ], "comment": "erudition; extensive learning" },
	{ "question": "博愛", "answers": [ "はくあい" ], "comment": "charity; benevolence; philanthropy; (love for) humanity; fraternity; brotherhood; brotherly love; love of fellow man" },
	{ "question": "占い", "answers": [ "うらない" ], "comment": "fortune-telling; divination" },
	{ "question": "占拠", "answers": [ "せんきょ" ], "comment": "occupation (e.g. of territory); exclusive possession" },
	{ "question": "印紙", "answers": [ "いんし" ], "comment": "(revenue) stamp" },
	{ "question": "危ぶむ", "answers": [ "あやぶむ" ], "comment": "to fear; to have misgivings; to be doubtful; to mistrust" },
	{ "question": "危害", "answers": [ "きがい" ], "comment": "injury; harm; danger" },
	{ "question": "危機", "answers": [ "きき" ], "comment": "crisis; danger; risk" },
	{ "question": "危篤", "answers": [ "きとく" ], "comment": "critical condition; being on the verge of death" },
	{ "question": "即位", "answers": [ "そくい" ], "comment": "enthronement" },
	{ "question": "即刻", "answers": [ "そっこく" ], "comment": "immediately; at once; instantly" },
	{ "question": "即効", "answers": [ "そっこう" ], "comment": "immediate effect; instant effect" },
	{ "question": "即売", "answers": [ "そくばい" ], "comment": "sale on the spot" },
	{ "question": "即席", "answers": [ "そくせき" ], "comment": "extempore; impromptu; improvised; ad-lib; off-the-cuff; instant" },
	{ "question": "即日", "answers": [ "そくじつ" ], "comment": "same day" },
	{ "question": "即時", "answers": [ "そくじ" ], "comment": "prompt; immediate; in real time" },
	{ "question": "即死", "answers": [ "そくし" ], "comment": "instant death" },
	{ "question": "即興", "answers": [ "そっきょう" ], "comment": "improvisation; impromptu; off the cuff; without a score" },
	{ "question": "卵子", "answers": [ "らんし" ], "comment": "ovum; ovule; egg cell" },
	{ "question": "卵巣", "answers": [ "らんそう" ], "comment": "ovary" },
	{ "question": "卵形", "answers": [ "らんけい", "たまごがた" ], "comment": "oval; egg-shaped" },
	{ "question": "卸", "answers": [ "おろし" ], "comment": "wholesale" },
	{ "question": "卸売", "answers": [ "おろしうり" ], "comment": "wholesale" },
	{ "question": "卸売り", "answers": [ "おろしうり" ], "comment": "wholesale" },
	{ "question": "厘", "answers": [ "りん" ], "comment": "one-hundredth; 0.3 mm (one-hundredth of a sun); 0.1 percent (one-hundredth of a wari); 0.0375 grams (one-hundredth of a monme)\nold monetary unit (0.001 yen)" },
	{ "question": "厚み", "answers": [ "あつみ" ], "comment": "thickness; profound" },
	{ "question": "厚意", "answers": [ "こうい" ], "comment": "kindness; favor; favour" },
	{ "question": "厚相", "answers": [ "こうしょう" ], "comment": "Welfare Minister" },
	{ "question": "厚着", "answers": [ "あつぎ" ], "comment": "wearing thick clothes; dressing warmly" },
	{ "question": "原っぱ", "answers": [ "はらっぱ" ], "comment": "open field; empty lot; plain" },
	{ "question": "原人", "answers": [ "げんじん" ], "comment": "primitive man" },
	{ "question": "原価", "answers": [ "げんか" ], "comment": "cost price" },
	{ "question": "原告", "answers": [ "げんこく" ], "comment": "plaintiff; accuser; prosecutor" },
	{ "question": "原子", "answers": [ "げんし" ], "comment": "atom" },
	{ "question": "原形", "answers": [ "げんけい" ], "comment": "original form; base form" },
	{ "question": "原書", "answers": [ "げんしょ" ], "comment": "original document (not a copy or adaptation); book in its original language (esp. a European language)" },
	{ "question": "原本", "answers": [ "げんぽん" ], "comment": "the original; original copy; script" },
	{ "question": "原案", "answers": [ "げんあん" ], "comment": "original plan; original bill; motion; draft; draught" },
	{ "question": "原水爆", "answers": [ "げんすいばく" ], "comment": "atomic and hydrogen bombs; nuclear and thermonuclear bombs" },
	{ "question": "原油", "answers": [ "げんゆ" ], "comment": "crude oil" },
	{ "question": "原潜", "answers": [ "げんせん" ], "comment": "nuclear submarine" },
	{ "question": "原生", "answers": [ "げんせい" ], "comment": "primeval; primordial; primitive; pristine" },
	{ "question": "原画", "answers": [ "げんが" ], "comment": "original picture\nkey frame; key animation" },
	{ "question": "原発", "answers": [ "げんぱつ" ], "comment": "nuclear power plant; nuclear power generation\nprimary (e.g. primary immunodeficiency syndrome)" },
	{ "question": "原義", "answers": [ "げんぎ" ], "comment": "original meaning" },
	{ "question": "原資", "answers": [ "げんし" ], "comment": "capital; principal" },
	{ "question": "原野", "answers": [ "げんや" ], "comment": "waste land; wilderness; moor; field; plain" },
	{ "question": "厨房", "answers": [ "ちゅうぼう" ], "comment": "kitchen; galley\n(Internet) troll" },
	{ "question": "厳か", "answers": [ "おごそか" ], "comment": "solemn (ceremony, atmosphere, etc.); austere; grave; majestic; dignified; stately; impressive" },
	{ "question": "厳守", "answers": [ "げんしゅ" ], "comment": "strict observance; adherence; scrupulous compliance" },
	{ "question": "厳粛", "answers": [ "げんしゅく" ], "comment": "gravity; solemnity; severity; seriousness; dignity; rigor; rigour; austerity" },
	{ "question": "去就", "answers": [ "きょしゅう" ], "comment": "(one's) course of action; (one's) position; (one's) attitude" },
	{ "question": "参与", "answers": [ "さんよ" ], "comment": "participation; taking part\nconsultant; councillor; adviser" },
	{ "question": "参事", "answers": [ "さんじ" ], "comment": "secretary; councillor; councilor" },
	{ "question": "参列", "answers": [ "さんれつ" ], "comment": "attendance; participation; presence" },
	{ "question": "参戦", "answers": [ "さんせん" ], "comment": "participation in a war; going to war\ntaking part in a competition or contest" },
	{ "question": "参観", "answers": [ "さんかん" ], "comment": "visit; inspection" },
	{ "question": "参道", "answers": [ "さんどう" ], "comment": "road approaching a shrine" },
	{ "question": "参院", "answers": [ "さんいん" ], "comment": "House of Councillors" },
	{ "question": "友愛", "answers": [ "ゆうあい" ], "comment": "fraternity; friendship" },
	{ "question": "双葉", "answers": [ "ふたば" ], "comment": "bud; sprout" },
	{ "question": "反共", "answers": [ "はんきょう" ], "comment": "anticommunist" },
	{ "question": "反則", "answers": [ "はんそく" ], "comment": "foul play (sport); breaking the rules; infringement; irregularity" },
	{ "question": "反感", "answers": [ "はんかん" ], "comment": "antipathy; antagonism; animosity; revulsion; ill feeling" },
	{ "question": "反戦", "answers": [ "はんせん" ], "comment": "anti-war" },
	{ "question": "反旗", "answers": [ "はんき" ], "comment": "standard of revolt; banner of revolution" },
	{ "question": "反日", "answers": [ "はんにち" ], "comment": "anti-Japanese" },
	{ "question": "反米", "answers": [ "はんべい" ], "comment": "anti-American" },
	{ "question": "反落", "answers": [ "はんらく" ], "comment": "reactionary fall (e.g. in stock prices)" },
	{ "question": "反逆", "answers": [ "はんぎゃく" ], "comment": "treason; treachery; mutiny; rebellion; insurrection" },
	{ "question": "収まり", "answers": [ "おさまり" ], "comment": "conclusion; end; settlement" },
	{ "question": "収まる", "answers": [ "おさまる" ], "comment": "to be in one's place; to be installed; to settle into\nto be delivered; to be obtained; to be paid\nto be settled; to be sorted out\nto lessen (e.g. of storms, pain); to calm down\nto be fit tightly into (e.g. a frame); to be sheathed (in a scabbard)" },
	{ "question": "収拾", "answers": [ "しゅうしゅう" ], "comment": "control; bringing under control; settling (a matter); putting in order" },
	{ "question": "収支", "answers": [ "しゅうし" ], "comment": "income and expenditure" },
	{ "question": "収用", "answers": [ "しゅうよう" ], "comment": "expropriation; seizure" },
	{ "question": "収納", "answers": [ "しゅうのう" ], "comment": "storage; putting or stowing away\nreceipt (of funds, payment, etc.)\nharvesting" },
	{ "question": "収縮", "answers": [ "しゅうしゅく" ], "comment": "deflation; contraction; shrinking; constriction" },
	{ "question": "収賄", "answers": [ "しゅうわい" ], "comment": "accepting bribes; corruption; graft" },
	{ "question": "収量", "answers": [ "しゅうりょう" ], "comment": "yield; size of harvest" },
	{ "question": "収集", "answers": [ "しゅうしゅう" ], "comment": "gathering up; collection; accumulation" },
	{ "question": "叔母", "answers": [ "はくぼ", "おば", "しゅくぼ" ], "comment": "aunt" },
	{ "question": "取っ手", "answers": [ "はしゅ", "とって" ], "comment": "handle; grip; knob" },
	{ "question": "取りまとめる", "answers": [ "とりまとめる" ], "comment": "to collect; to gather; to compile; to assemble\nto arrange; to settle" },
	{ "question": "取り下げ", "answers": [ "とりさげ" ], "comment": "withdrawal" },
	{ "question": "取り口", "answers": [ "とりくち" ], "comment": "technique; techniques" },
	{ "question": "取り壊し", "answers": [ "とりこわし" ], "comment": "demolition; pulling down; destruction; dismantling" },
	{ "question": "取り外す", "answers": [ "とりはずす" ], "comment": "to dismantle; to demount; to take something away; to detach" },
	{ "question": "取り寄せる", "answers": [ "とりよせる" ], "comment": "to order; to send away for\nto pull something closer" },
	{ "question": "取り柄", "answers": [ "とりえ" ], "comment": "worth; redeeming feature; merit; gain; profit" },
	{ "question": "取り次ぐ", "answers": [ "とりつぐ" ], "comment": "to act as an agent for; to intermediate\nto announce (someone's arrival); to answer (the door, the phone); to receive (a guest at reception); to usher in (a guest)\nto convey (a message)" },
	{ "question": "取り決め", "answers": [ "とりきめ" ], "comment": "decision; agreement" },
	{ "question": "取り決める", "answers": [ "とりきめる" ], "comment": "to agree; to decide upon; to enter into (a contract)" },
	{ "question": "取り立て", "answers": [ "とりたて" ], "comment": "collection (of a debt)\npatronage; promotion\nfresh (e.g. freshly picked)" },
	{ "question": "取り締まる", "answers": [ "とりしまる" ], "comment": "to manage; to control; to supervise; to crack down on" },
	{ "question": "取り計らい", "answers": [ "とりはからい" ], "comment": "arrangement" },
	{ "question": "取り込み", "answers": [ "とりこみ" ], "comment": "taking in; bringing in\ncapturing (e.g. customers); attracting; winning over; pleasing\nconfusion; bustle; misfortune; disorder\nimporting (e.g. data); capturing (e.g. image)" },
	{ "question": "取り返す", "answers": [ "とりかえす" ], "comment": "to regain; to recover; to get back" },
	{ "question": "取得", "answers": [ "しゅとく" ], "comment": "acquisition; obtaining; gaining possession; purchase" },
	{ "question": "取次", "answers": [ "とりつぎ" ], "comment": "agency; commission; distributor; intermediation\nreception (of guests)\nconveyance (of messages)" },
	{ "question": "取水", "answers": [ "しゅすい" ], "comment": "drawing water from river or lake; water intake" },
	{ "question": "取決め", "answers": [ "とりきめ" ], "comment": "decision; agreement" },
	{ "question": "受かる", "answers": [ "うかる" ], "comment": "to pass (examination)" },
	{ "question": "受け入れ", "answers": [ "うけいれ" ], "comment": "receiving; acceptance; reception" },
	{ "question": "受け持ち", "answers": [ "うけもち" ], "comment": "charge (of something); matter in one's charge" },
	{ "question": "受け渡し", "answers": [ "うけわたし" ], "comment": "delivery" },
	{ "question": "受け皿", "answers": [ "うけざら" ], "comment": "saucer\nperson (group, institution, etc.) to take over a position or matter; receptacle (e.g. of funds); receiver" },
	{ "question": "受け身", "answers": [ "うけみ" ], "comment": "the defensive\npassive attitude; passivity; passiveness\nthe passive; passive voice\nukemi (the art of falling safely)" },
	{ "question": "受像", "answers": [ "じゅぞう" ], "comment": "(television) reception" },
	{ "question": "受刑", "answers": [ "じゅけい" ], "comment": "punishment" },
	{ "question": "受注", "answers": [ "じゅちゅう" ], "comment": "accepting an order; receiving an order; orders received" },
	{ "question": "受理", "answers": [ "じゅり" ], "comment": "acceptance" },
	{ "question": "受益", "answers": [ "じゅえき" ], "comment": "benefitting by; benefiting by" },
	{ "question": "受章", "answers": [ "じゅしょう" ], "comment": "reception of a decoration; reception of an order" },
	{ "question": "受精", "answers": [ "じゅせい" ], "comment": "fertilization; fertilisation; impregnation; pollination" },
	{ "question": "受託", "answers": [ "じゅたく" ], "comment": "being entrusted with; taking charge of" },
	{ "question": "受諾", "answers": [ "じゅだく" ], "comment": "acceptance" },
	{ "question": "受講", "answers": [ "じゅこう" ], "comment": "taking (attending) lectures" },
	{ "question": "受身", "answers": [ "うけみ" ], "comment": "the defensive\npassive attitude; passivity; passiveness\nthe passive; passive voice\nukemi (the art of falling safely)" },
	{ "question": "受難", "answers": [ "じゅなん" ], "comment": "suffering; agony; passion" },
	{ "question": "受領", "answers": [ "じゅりょう" ], "comment": "receipt (of letter); acknowledgement; acceptance" },
	{ "question": "叙勲", "answers": [ "じょくん" ], "comment": "conferring of decorations" },
	{ "question": "叙情", "answers": [ "じょじょう" ], "comment": "lyricism; description or expression of one's feelings" },
	{ "question": "口々", "answers": [ "くちぐち" ], "comment": "each entrance; every mouth" },
	{ "question": "口ごもる", "answers": [ "くちごもる" ], "comment": "to hesitate to say; to mumble; to hem and haw; to falter" },
	{ "question": "口ぶり", "answers": [ "くちぶり" ], "comment": "way of speaking\nintimation" },
	{ "question": "口コミ", "answers": [ "くちコミ" ], "comment": "word of mouth\ncomment on an Internet forum or web page" },
	{ "question": "口上", "answers": [ "こうじょう" ], "comment": "vocal message; speech; statement\nprologue at the start of a kabuki performance" },
	{ "question": "口先", "answers": [ "くちさき" ], "comment": "lip service; mere words; professions\nlips; mouth; snout; proboscis" },
	{ "question": "口出し", "answers": [ "くちだし" ], "comment": "interference; meddling; butting in" },
	{ "question": "口利き", "answers": [ "くちきき" ], "comment": "mediation; good offices; intervention; mediator; middleman\ninfluential person; person of influence\neloquence; eloquent person\nway of speaking" },
	{ "question": "口径", "answers": [ "こうけい" ], "comment": "aperture; bore; calibre; caliber" },
	{ "question": "口数", "answers": [ "くちかず", "くちすう" ], "comment": "number of words a person speaks\nnumber of dependents (words, shares, accounts)" },
	{ "question": "口止め", "answers": [ "くちどめ" ], "comment": "forbidding to speak; muzzling (a person); bribing into secrecy\nhush money" },
	{ "question": "口火", "answers": [ "くちび" ], "comment": "fuse; pilot light\ncause (of a war, argument, revolt, etc.); origin; trigger" },
	{ "question": "口癖", "answers": [ "くちぐせ" ], "comment": "way of saying; favorite phrase; favourite phrase" },
	{ "question": "口笛", "answers": [ "くちぶえ" ], "comment": "whistle (sound made with the lips)" },
	{ "question": "口答え", "answers": [ "くちごたえ" ], "comment": "retort; back talk" },
	{ "question": "口語", "answers": [ "こうご" ], "comment": "spoken language; colloquial speech\nliterary style based on (modern) spoken language" },
	{ "question": "口論", "answers": [ "こうろん" ], "comment": "dispute; quarrel; argument" },
	{ "question": "口頭", "answers": [ "こうとう" ], "comment": "oral; verbal; parol" },
	{ "question": "古今", "answers": [ "ここん" ], "comment": "ancient and modern times; all ages; past and present" },
	{ "question": "古参", "answers": [ "こさん" ], "comment": "seniority; long service" },
	{ "question": "古墳", "answers": [ "こふん" ], "comment": "ancient burial mound; barrow; tumulus" },
	{ "question": "古巣", "answers": [ "ふるす" ], "comment": "old haunts; former homes" },
	{ "question": "古書", "answers": [ "こしょ" ], "comment": "old book; rare book\nsecondhand book; used book" },
	{ "question": "古本", "answers": [ "ふるほん", "こほん", "ふるぼん" ], "comment": "secondhand book\nancient book; antiquarian books" },
	{ "question": "古着", "answers": [ "ふるぎ" ], "comment": "old clothes; secondhand clothing" },
	{ "question": "古紙", "answers": [ "こし" ], "comment": "used paper; paper for recycling" },
	{ "question": "古都", "answers": [ "こと" ], "comment": "ancient city; former capital" },
	{ "question": "句集", "answers": [ "くしゅう" ], "comment": "collection of haiku poems" },
	{ "question": "叩き", "answers": [ "たたき" ], "comment": "mince (minced meat or fish)\nseared skipjack tuna\nrobbery; extortion\nhard-packed dirt (clay, gravel, etc.) floor; concrete floor\nwhipping; lashing; bashing; beating; flaming" },
	{ "question": "召集", "answers": [ "しょうしゅう" ], "comment": "convening; calling together (e.g. parliament)" },
	{ "question": "可否", "answers": [ "かひ" ], "comment": "propriety; right and wrong; advisability; possibility\npro and con; ayes and noes" },
	{ "question": "台地", "answers": [ "だいち" ], "comment": "plateau; tableland; eminence" },
	{ "question": "台帳", "answers": [ "だいちょう" ], "comment": "account book; ledger; register" },
	{ "question": "台本", "answers": [ "だいほん" ], "comment": "script; libretto; scenario" },
	{ "question": "台無し", "answers": [ "だいなし" ], "comment": "mess; spoiled; spoilt; (come to) nothing; ruin" },
	{ "question": "台車", "answers": [ "だいしゃ" ], "comment": "platform truck; hand truck; trolley; dolly; cart\n(railway) truck; bogie; flatcar; wagon; waggon" },
	{ "question": "史上", "answers": [ "しじょう" ], "comment": "in history; ever; historical" },
	{ "question": "史学", "answers": [ "しがく" ], "comment": "study of history" },
	{ "question": "史実", "answers": [ "しじつ" ], "comment": "historical fact" },
	{ "question": "史家", "answers": [ "しか" ], "comment": "historian" },
	{ "question": "史跡", "answers": [ "しせき" ], "comment": "historic landmark; historic site; historic remains" },
	{ "question": "右派", "answers": [ "うは" ], "comment": "right wing" },
	{ "question": "右腕", "answers": [ "みぎうで", "うわん" ], "comment": "right arm\nright-hand man; right hand; right-hand person\nright-handed pitcher" },
	{ "question": "号", "answers": [ "ごう" ], "comment": "number; edition; make; model; issue; part of that group\nsobriquet; pen-name\nsuffix attached to names of ships, trains, airplanes, etc." },
	{ "question": "号令", "answers": [ "ごうれい" ], "comment": "order; command" },
	{ "question": "司る", "answers": [ "つかさどる" ], "comment": "to rule; to govern; to administer" },
	{ "question": "各", "answers": [ "かく" ], "comment": "each; every; all" },
	{ "question": "各位", "answers": [ "かくい" ], "comment": "everyone; each and every one (of you); ladies and gentlemen" },
	{ "question": "合わす", "answers": [ "あわす" ], "comment": "to match (rhythm, speed, etc.)\nto join together; to unite; to combine; to add up\nto face; to be opposite (someone)\nto compare; to check with\nto cause to meet (e.g. an unpleasant fate)\nto place together; to connect; to overlap\nto mix; to combine\nto put blade to blade; to fight" },
	{ "question": "合作", "answers": [ "がっさく" ], "comment": "collaboration; joint work" },
	{ "question": "合力", "answers": [ "ごうりょく", "こうりょく", "ごうりき" ], "comment": "resultant force\nassistance; help\ndonation; alms; almsgiving" },
	{ "question": "合否", "answers": [ "ごうひ" ], "comment": "success or failure; result" },
	{ "question": "合奏", "answers": [ "がっそう" ], "comment": "ensemble (e.g. orchestra, chamber group, etc.); concert" },
	{ "question": "合宿", "answers": [ "がっしゅく" ], "comment": "lodging together; training camp; boarding house" },
	{ "question": "合弁", "answers": [ "ごうべん" ], "comment": "joint management; pool" },
	{ "question": "合憲", "answers": [ "ごうけん" ], "comment": "constitutionality" },
	{ "question": "合板", "answers": [ "ごうはん", "ごうばん" ], "comment": "veneer board; plywood\njoint publication" },
	{ "question": "合繊", "answers": [ "ごうせん" ], "comment": "synthetic fiber; synthetic fibre" },
	{ "question": "合言葉", "answers": [ "あいことば" ], "comment": "password; watchword\nmotto; slogan" },
	{ "question": "合議", "answers": [ "ごうぎ" ], "comment": "consultation; conference" },
	{ "question": "合金", "answers": [ "ごうきん" ], "comment": "alloy" },
	{ "question": "同上", "answers": [ "どうじょう" ], "comment": "same as above; ditto; ibid." },
	{ "question": "同乗", "answers": [ "どうじょう" ], "comment": "riding together; riding with" },
	{ "question": "同伴", "answers": [ "どうはん" ], "comment": "to accompany; to go with\ncompany; companion" },
	{ "question": "同党", "answers": [ "どうとう" ], "comment": "the same political party" },
	{ "question": "同列", "answers": [ "どうれつ" ], "comment": "same rank or file; company; attendance" },
	{ "question": "同名", "answers": [ "どうめい", "どうみょう" ], "comment": "same name\nhomonym" },
	{ "question": "同国", "answers": [ "どうこく" ], "comment": "the same country; the same province; the said country" },
	{ "question": "同地", "answers": [ "どうち" ], "comment": "the same place; that place" },
	{ "question": "同夜", "answers": [ "どうや" ], "comment": "the same night; that night" },
	{ "question": "同好", "answers": [ "どうこう" ], "comment": "similar tastes" },
	{ "question": "同姓", "answers": [ "どうせい" ], "comment": "same surname" },
	{ "question": "同室", "answers": [ "どうしつ" ], "comment": "the same room" },
	{ "question": "同封", "answers": [ "どうふう" ], "comment": "enclosing (e.g. with a letter)" },
	{ "question": "同局", "answers": [ "どうきょく" ], "comment": "the said bureau; the same bureau" },
	{ "question": "同市", "answers": [ "どうし" ], "comment": "same city" },
	{ "question": "同席", "answers": [ "どうせき" ], "comment": "presence; sitting with; being with" },
	{ "question": "同店", "answers": [ "どうてん" ], "comment": "the same store; the same shop" },
	{ "question": "同数", "answers": [ "どうすう" ], "comment": "same number" },
	{ "question": "同日", "answers": [ "どうじつ" ], "comment": "the same day" },
	{ "question": "同月", "answers": [ "どうげつ" ], "comment": "the same month" },
	{ "question": "同校", "answers": [ "どうこう" ], "comment": "same school" },
	{ "question": "同業", "answers": [ "どうぎょう" ], "comment": "same trade; same business" },
	{ "question": "同氏", "answers": [ "どうし" ], "comment": "the said person; he; she; same person" },
	{ "question": "同点", "answers": [ "どうてん" ], "comment": "deadlock; tie; draw" },
	{ "question": "同率", "answers": [ "どうりつ" ], "comment": "the same ratio or percentage" },
	{ "question": "同町", "answers": [ "どうちょう" ], "comment": "the same town; that town" },
	{ "question": "同病", "answers": [ "どうびょう" ], "comment": "the same sickness" },
	{ "question": "同省", "answers": [ "どうしょう" ], "comment": "the said ministry; the same ministry" },
	{ "question": "同県", "answers": [ "どうけん" ], "comment": "the same prefecture" },
	{ "question": "同社", "answers": [ "どうしゃ" ], "comment": "the same firm" },
	{ "question": "同種", "answers": [ "どうしゅ" ], "comment": "same kind (race); homogeneousness" },
	{ "question": "同窓", "answers": [ "どうそう" ], "comment": "the same school" },
	{ "question": "同胞", "answers": [ "はらから", "どうぼう", "どうほう" ], "comment": "brethren; brothers; fellow countrymen; fellowman; compatriot" },
	{ "question": "同船", "answers": [ "どうせん" ], "comment": "the same ship; taking the same ship" },
	{ "question": "同行", "answers": [ "どうこう" ], "comment": "accompanying; travelling together; traveling together\nsame bank" },
	{ "question": "同郷", "answers": [ "どうきょう" ], "comment": "same village; same town; same province" },
	{ "question": "同音", "answers": [ "どうおん" ], "comment": "homophony; same pronunciation; same sound\nunison; same pitch\n(in) one voice; (speaking in) unison" },
	{ "question": "同類", "answers": [ "どうるい" ], "comment": "the same kind; accomplice; partner" },
	{ "question": "名乗り", "answers": [ "なのり" ], "comment": "giving one's name (or rank, etc.); self-introduction\nname readings of kanji" },
	{ "question": "名乗り出る", "answers": [ "なのりでる" ], "comment": "to introduce oneself; to announce oneself (e.g. as the person sought); to come forward (e.g. as a witness, with a claim, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "名優", "answers": [ "めいゆう" ], "comment": "great or famous actor; star" },
	{ "question": "名声", "answers": [ "めいせい" ], "comment": "fame; reputation; renown" },
	{ "question": "名実", "answers": [ "めいじつ" ], "comment": "in name and in reality; nominally and virtually; form and contents" },
	{ "question": "名手", "answers": [ "めいしゅ" ], "comment": "master; expert\nexpert board game player (chess, go, shogi, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "名指し", "answers": [ "なざし" ], "comment": "nomination; calling names" },
	{ "question": "名曲", "answers": [ "めいきょく" ], "comment": "famous music" },
	{ "question": "名月", "answers": [ "めいげつ" ], "comment": "harvest moon\nbright moon; full moon" },
	{ "question": "名札", "answers": [ "なふだ" ], "comment": "name plate; name tag; label" },
	{ "question": "名案", "answers": [ "めいあん" ], "comment": "good idea" },
	{ "question": "名残惜しい", "answers": [ "なごりおしい" ], "comment": "reluctant (to part)" },
	{ "question": "名画", "answers": [ "めいが" ], "comment": "famous picture; masterpiece\nfilm classic" },
	{ "question": "名著", "answers": [ "めいちょ" ], "comment": "famous book; masterpiece (literary work)" },
	{ "question": "名高い", "answers": [ "なだかい" ], "comment": "famous; celebrated; well-known" },
	{ "question": "吐露", "answers": [ "とろ" ], "comment": "expressing one's mind; speaking out" },
	{ "question": "君子", "answers": [ "くんし" ], "comment": "man of virtue; person of high rank; wise man" },
	{ "question": "君臨", "answers": [ "くんりん" ], "comment": "reigning; controlling\nto reign; to dictate; to control" },
	{ "question": "否決", "answers": [ "ひけつ" ], "comment": "rejection; negation; voting down" },
	{ "question": "否認", "answers": [ "ひにん" ], "comment": "denial; negation; repudiation; disapproval" },
	{ "question": "含み", "answers": [ "ふくみ" ], "comment": "implication; hidden meaning; latitude; atmosphere; tone; sentiment; inclusion" },
	{ "question": "含有", "answers": [ "がんゆう" ], "comment": "contain; include" },
	{ "question": "吸い殻", "answers": [ "すいがら" ], "comment": "cigarette end; cigarette butt; tobacco ashes" },
	{ "question": "吹き溜まり", "answers": [ "ふきだまり" ], "comment": "drift of snow or leaves\nhangout for drifters" },
	{ "question": "吹き込む", "answers": [ "ふきこむ" ], "comment": "to blow into; to breathe into\nto inspire; to indoctrinate\nto record (music, video, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "呉服", "answers": [ "ごふく" ], "comment": "cloth (for Japanese clothes); textile; drapery; dry goods; piece goods\nsilk fabrics" },
	{ "question": "告別", "answers": [ "こくべつ" ], "comment": "farewell; leave-taking" },
	{ "question": "告示", "answers": [ "こくじ" ], "comment": "notice; bulletin" },
	{ "question": "告訴", "answers": [ "こくそ" ], "comment": "accusation; complaint; charge; legal action" },
	{ "question": "周到", "answers": [ "しゅうとう" ], "comment": "scrupulous; meticulous; careful" },
	{ "question": "呪う", "answers": [ "のろう" ], "comment": "to curse; to put a curse on; to detest intensely" },
	{ "question": "味わい", "answers": [ "あじわい" ], "comment": "flavour; flavor\nmeaning; significance" },
	{ "question": "味気ない", "answers": [ "あじけない", "あじきない" ], "comment": "wearisome; insipid; dull; irksome; wretched; vain" },
	{ "question": "味覚", "answers": [ "みかく" ], "comment": "taste; palate; sense of taste" },
	{ "question": "呼びかけ", "answers": [ "よびかけ" ], "comment": "call; appeal" },
	{ "question": "呼び出し", "answers": [ "よびだし" ], "comment": "call; summons; paging; curtain call\nusher who calls the names of wrestlers, sweeps the ring, etc.\ntelephone number at which a person without a telephone can be reached\nbox-shaped area containing clean water for rinsing oneself (in an Edo-period bathhouse)\nhigh-ranking prostitute in the Yoshiwara district (Edo period)\nunlicensed prostitute in the Fukagawa red-light district (Edo period)" },
	{ "question": "呼び捨て", "answers": [ "よびすて" ], "comment": "addressing someone without an honorific such as \"san\"" },
	{ "question": "呼び掛け", "answers": [ "よびかけ" ], "comment": "call; appeal" },
	{ "question": "呼び水", "answers": [ "よびみず" ], "comment": "pump-priming; rousing; stimulation" },
	{ "question": "命中", "answers": [ "めいちゅう" ], "comment": "a hit; hitting something that was aimed at" },
	{ "question": "命日", "answers": [ "めいにち" ], "comment": "death anniversary" },
	{ "question": "命運", "answers": [ "めいうん" ], "comment": "fate; doom" },
	{ "question": "和む", "answers": [ "なごむ" ], "comment": "to be softened; to calm down" },
	{ "question": "和やか", "answers": [ "なごやか" ], "comment": "mild; calm; gentle; quiet; harmonious" },
	{ "question": "和らぐ", "answers": [ "やわらぐ" ], "comment": "to soften; to calm down; to be mitigated" },
	{ "question": "和室", "answers": [ "わしつ" ], "comment": "Japanese-style room" },
	{ "question": "和平", "answers": [ "わへい" ], "comment": "peace" },
	{ "question": "和式", "answers": [ "わしき" ], "comment": "Japanese style" },
	{ "question": "和歌", "answers": [ "わか" ], "comment": "waka; classic Japanese poem, esp. a tanka, often 31 morae" },
	{ "question": "和牛", "answers": [ "わぎゅう" ], "comment": "Wagyu beef; Japanese beef" },
	{ "question": "和紙", "answers": [ "わし" ], "comment": "washi; Japanese paper" },
	{ "question": "和語", "answers": [ "わご" ], "comment": "native Japanese words (especially as opposed to Chinese and other foreign loanwords)" },
	{ "question": "和議", "answers": [ "わぎ" ], "comment": "peace conference; peace negotiations" },
	{ "question": "和風", "answers": [ "わふう" ], "comment": "Japanese style\nlight wind; moderate breeze" },
	{ "question": "和食", "answers": [ "わしょく" ], "comment": "Japanese food; Japanese-style meal; Japanese cuisine" },
	{ "question": "哀れむ", "answers": [ "あわれむ" ], "comment": "to commiserate; to pity; to have mercy on; to sympathize with; to sympathise with\nto enjoy the beauty of; to appreciate (e.g. the moon, flowers)" },
	{ "question": "哀悼", "answers": [ "あいとう" ], "comment": "condolence; regret; tribute; sorrow; sympathy; lament" },
	{ "question": "哀愁", "answers": [ "あいしゅう" ], "comment": "pathos; sorrow; grief" },
	{ "question": "品位", "answers": [ "ひんい" ], "comment": "dignity; grace; nobility\ngrade; quality; fineness; carat; karat" },
	{ "question": "品切れ", "answers": [ "しなぎれ" ], "comment": "out of stock; sold out" },
	{ "question": "品名", "answers": [ "ひんめい" ], "comment": "name of product" },
	{ "question": "品性", "answers": [ "ひんせい" ], "comment": "character" },
	{ "question": "品格", "answers": [ "ひんかく" ], "comment": "dignity; quality of character" },
	{ "question": "品目", "answers": [ "ひんもく", "しなめ" ], "comment": "item; commodity; list of articles" },
	{ "question": "品詞", "answers": [ "ひんし" ], "comment": "part of speech" },
	{ "question": "員数", "answers": [ "いんず", "いんずう" ], "comment": "numbers of members (things, people)" },
	{ "question": "唐突", "answers": [ "とうとつ" ], "comment": "abrupt; sudden" },
	{ "question": "唐辛子", "answers": [ "とんがらし", "とうがらし", "ばんしょう" ], "comment": "capsicum (Capsicum annuum, esp. the cultivated chili peppers); chili pepper (chile, chilli); cayenne; red pepper\nshichimi pepper" },
	{ "question": "商い", "answers": [ "あきない" ], "comment": "trade; business; trading; dealing" },
	{ "question": "商会", "answers": [ "しょうかい" ], "comment": "firm; company" },
	{ "question": "商務", "answers": [ "しょうむ" ], "comment": "commercial affairs" },
	{ "question": "商学", "answers": [ "しょうがく" ], "comment": "commercial science" },
	{ "question": "商工", "answers": [ "しょうこう" ], "comment": "commerce and industry" },
	{ "question": "商戦", "answers": [ "しょうせん" ], "comment": "sales war" },
	{ "question": "商標", "answers": [ "しょうひょう" ], "comment": "trademark" },
	{ "question": "商用", "answers": [ "しょうよう" ], "comment": "on business; for business; business purpose" },
	{ "question": "商談", "answers": [ "しょうだん" ], "comment": "business discussion; negotiation" },
	{ "question": "問", "answers": [ "もん" ], "comment": "counter for questions" },
	{ "question": "問責", "answers": [ "もんせき" ], "comment": "blame; censure; reproof; reprimand; rebuke" },
	{ "question": "啓発", "answers": [ "けいはつ" ], "comment": "enlightenment; development; edification; public awareness; illumination; education; inspiration" },
	{ "question": "善し悪し", "answers": [ "よしわるし", "よしあし" ], "comment": "right or wrong; good or bad; merits or demerits; quality; suitability" },
	{ "question": "善悪", "answers": [ "ぜんあく" ], "comment": "good and evil" },
	{ "question": "善戦", "answers": [ "ぜんせん" ], "comment": "fighting a good fight; putting up a good fight; fighting bravely" },
	{ "question": "善隣", "answers": [ "ぜんりん" ], "comment": "good neighbour; good neighbor" },
	{ "question": "喚問", "answers": [ "かんもん" ], "comment": "summons" },
	{ "question": "喚起", "answers": [ "かんき" ], "comment": "arousal; excitation; awakening; evocation" },
	{ "question": "喜ばしい", "answers": [ "よろこばしい" ], "comment": "delightful; joyous; happy" },
	{ "question": "喜ばす", "answers": [ "よろこばす" ], "comment": "to delight; to give pleasure" },
	{ "question": "喜劇", "answers": [ "きげき" ], "comment": "comedy; funny show" },
	{ "question": "喪主", "answers": [ "もしゅ" ], "comment": "chief mourner" },
	{ "question": "喫する", "answers": [ "きっする" ], "comment": "to eat; to drink; to smoke; to take\nto suffer (e.g. defeat); to receive a blow" },
	{ "question": "営利", "answers": [ "えいり" ], "comment": "money-making; commercialized; commercialised" },
	{ "question": "営団", "answers": [ "えいだん" ], "comment": "corporation; foundation" },
	{ "question": "営農", "answers": [ "えいのう" ], "comment": "farming; agriculture" },
	{ "question": "嘆き", "answers": [ "なげき" ], "comment": "grief; lamentation" },
	{ "question": "嘘つき", "answers": [ "うそつき", "ウソつき" ], "comment": "liar (sometimes said with not much seriousness); fibber" },
	{ "question": "嘱託", "answers": [ "しょくたく" ], "comment": "commission; charge (person with); entrusting with\npart-time (employee)" },
	{ "question": "嘲る", "answers": [ "あざける" ], "comment": "to scoff; to laugh at; to make fun of; to ridicule; to jeer at" },
	{ "question": "噛み付く", "answers": [ "かみつく" ], "comment": "to bite (at); to snap at; to snarl at" },
	{ "question": "器官", "answers": [ "きかん" ], "comment": "organ (of body, plant, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "器材", "answers": [ "きざい" ], "comment": "tools and materials; equipment and materials" },
	{ "question": "器物", "answers": [ "うつわもの", "きぶつ" ], "comment": "container; receptacle\nutensil; implement; furniture\ncalibre; talent; ability\npersonal property" },
	{ "question": "噴出", "answers": [ "ふんしゅつ" ], "comment": "spewing; gushing; spouting; eruption; effusion" },
	{ "question": "噴射", "answers": [ "ふんしゃ" ], "comment": "jet; spray; injection; jet propulsion" },
	{ "question": "噴煙", "answers": [ "ふんえん" ], "comment": "(eruption of) smoke" },
	{ "question": "四球", "answers": [ "しきゅう" ], "comment": "four balls; base on balls; a walk" },
	{ "question": "回し", "answers": [ "まわし" ], "comment": "mawashi; belt; loincloth\nmantle; cape\ngang rape" },
	{ "question": "回廊", "answers": [ "かいろう" ], "comment": "corridor; gallery; hallway; cloister (i.e. covered walk typically circling a building or garden, esp. in a palace or place of worship)" },
	{ "question": "回忌", "answers": [ "かいき" ], "comment": "death anniversary" },
	{ "question": "回生", "answers": [ "かいせい" ], "comment": "resurrection; resuscitation; regeneration\nuniversity student in ... year" },
	{ "question": "回顧", "answers": [ "かいこ" ], "comment": "recollecting; reminiscing; looking back; retrospection; review" },
	{ "question": "因子", "answers": [ "いんし" ], "comment": "factor; divisor; element" },
	{ "question": "因縁", "answers": [ "いんえん", "いんねん" ], "comment": "fate; destiny\nconnection; tie; bond; origin\npretext; justification\nhetu and prataya (direct causes and indirect conditions, which underlie the actions of all things)" },
	{ "question": "団員", "answers": [ "だんいん" ], "comment": "group member" },
	{ "question": "団塊", "answers": [ "だんかい" ], "comment": "mass; lump\nbaby boom generation (of 1947-1949); babyboomer (born between 1947-1949)" },
	{ "question": "団長", "answers": [ "だんちょう" ], "comment": "leader of a delegation (body, party)" },
	{ "question": "囲い", "answers": [ "かこい" ], "comment": "enclosure; paling; storage\ncastle; strong defensive position" },
	{ "question": "囲う", "answers": [ "かこう" ], "comment": "to enclose; to surround; to encircle; to fence; to wall in\nto shelter (e.g. a criminal); to shield; to hide; to protect\nto keep (e.g. a mistress)\nto store (vegetables, fruit, etc.); to preserve\nto protect" },
	{ "question": "囲み", "answers": [ "かこみ" ], "comment": "enclosure; box\nsiege" },
	{ "question": "囲碁", "answers": [ "いご" ], "comment": "go; board game of capturing territory" },
	{ "question": "図々しい", "answers": [ "ずうずうしい" ], "comment": "impudent; shameless" },
	{ "question": "図柄", "answers": [ "ずがら" ], "comment": "design; pattern" },
	{ "question": "図版", "answers": [ "ずはん" ], "comment": "plate; illustration; figure" },
	{ "question": "図示", "answers": [ "ずし" ], "comment": "illustration; showing in graphic form or by diagram" },
	{ "question": "図解", "answers": [ "ずかい" ], "comment": "schematic; schema; illustration; explanatory diagram" },
	{ "question": "固め", "answers": [ "かため" ], "comment": "hardening; fortifying\npledge; vow\ndefense; defence; guarding" },
	{ "question": "固体", "answers": [ "こたい" ], "comment": "solid (body); solid matter; solid-state" },
	{ "question": "固執", "answers": [ "こしつ", "こしゅう" ], "comment": "adherence (e.g. to ideas, beliefs, a pet theory) (negative nuance); persistence; insistence; stubbornness" },
	{ "question": "固定", "answers": [ "こてい" ], "comment": "fixation; fixing (e.g. salary, capital)\nfixed handle" },
	{ "question": "固形", "answers": [ "こけい" ], "comment": "solid (body)" },
	{ "question": "国交", "answers": [ "こっこう" ], "comment": "diplomatic relations" },
	{ "question": "国人", "answers": [ "こくじん", "こくにん", "くにゅうど", "くにうど", "くにびと" ], "comment": "indigenous person; inhabitant of a country\nlocal; native\nlocal lords and samurai\ndaimyo who did not leave his domains to meet the shogun in Kyoto (during the Muromachi period)" },
	{ "question": "国体", "answers": [ "こくたい" ], "comment": "national polity\nNational Athletic Meet" },
	{ "question": "国債", "answers": [ "こくさい" ], "comment": "national debt; national securities; government bonds; government securities" },
	{ "question": "国力", "answers": [ "こくりょく" ], "comment": "national power" },
	{ "question": "国務", "answers": [ "こくむ" ], "comment": "affairs of state" },
	{ "question": "国勢", "answers": [ "こくせい" ], "comment": "state (condition, strength) of a country" },
	{ "question": "国名", "answers": [ "こくめい" ], "comment": "country name" },
	{ "question": "国営", "answers": [ "こくえい" ], "comment": "government management; state management" },
	{ "question": "国士", "answers": [ "こくし" ], "comment": "distinguished citizen; patriot" },
	{ "question": "国外", "answers": [ "こくがい" ], "comment": "outside the country" },
	{ "question": "国大", "answers": [ "こくだい" ], "comment": "national university" },
	{ "question": "国学", "answers": [ "こくがく" ], "comment": "study of (ancient) Japanese literature and culture\nprovincial school (under Japan's ritsuryo system and pre-Sui Chinese law)" },
	{ "question": "国宝", "answers": [ "こくほう" ], "comment": "national treasure" },
	{ "question": "国対", "answers": [ "こくたい" ], "comment": "Committee of the National Diet" },
	{ "question": "国庫", "answers": [ "こっこ" ], "comment": "national treasury" },
	{ "question": "国情", "answers": [ "こくじょう" ], "comment": "conditions of a country" },
	{ "question": "国技", "answers": [ "こくぎ" ], "comment": "national sport (e.g. sumo)" },
	{ "question": "国政", "answers": [ "こくせい" ], "comment": "national politics; political situation; statecraft; body politic" },
	{ "question": "国旗", "answers": [ "こっき" ], "comment": "national flag" },
	{ "question": "国是", "answers": [ "こくぜ" ], "comment": "national policy" },
	{ "question": "国有", "answers": [ "こくゆう" ], "comment": "national ownership" },
	{ "question": "国柄", "answers": [ "くにがら" ], "comment": "national character; regional character" },
	{ "question": "国権", "answers": [ "こっけん" ], "comment": "power of the state; national sovereignty; sovereign rights" },
	{ "question": "国歌", "answers": [ "こっか" ], "comment": "national anthem" },
	{ "question": "国益", "answers": [ "こくえき" ], "comment": "national interest" },
	{ "question": "国税", "answers": [ "こくぜい" ], "comment": "national tax" },
	{ "question": "国策", "answers": [ "こくさく" ], "comment": "national policy" },
	{ "question": "国論", "answers": [ "こくろん" ], "comment": "public opinion" },
	{ "question": "国費", "answers": [ "こくひ" ], "comment": "national expenditures" },
	{ "question": "国賓", "answers": [ "こくひん" ], "comment": "state guest" },
	{ "question": "国軍", "answers": [ "こくぐん" ], "comment": "national armed forces" },
	{ "question": "圏内", "answers": [ "けんない" ], "comment": "(being) within range (radio, commuting, etc.); (being) within the sphere (e.g. of influence)" },
	{ "question": "園児", "answers": [ "えんじ" ], "comment": "kindergarten pupil; kindergartener" },
	{ "question": "園内", "answers": [ "えんない" ], "comment": "inside the garden (park)" },
	{ "question": "園長", "answers": [ "えんちょう" ], "comment": "head of a garden; kindergarten principal; nursery school principal; park director (botanical garden); zoo director (zoological garden); head of a plantation" },
	{ "question": "土俵", "answers": [ "どひょう" ], "comment": "(wrestling) ring\nforum (e.g. for discussion)\nsandbag; gabion" },
	{ "question": "土器", "answers": [ "かわらけ", "どき" ], "comment": "earthenware\nunglazed (bisque-fired) earthenware" },
	{ "question": "土壇場", "answers": [ "どたんば" ], "comment": "last moment; eleventh hour\nplatform made of dirt used to perform executions (decapitations) in the Edo period" },
	{ "question": "土日", "answers": [ "どにち" ], "comment": "weekend; Saturday and Sunday" },
	{ "question": "土星", "answers": [ "どせい" ], "comment": "Saturn (planet)" },
	{ "question": "土石", "answers": [ "どせき" ], "comment": "earth and stones" },
	{ "question": "土砂", "answers": [ "どしゃ" ], "comment": "sediment; earth and sand" },
	{ "question": "土足", "answers": [ "どそく" ], "comment": "shod feet\nmuddy feet; dirty feet" },
	{ "question": "土間", "answers": [ "どま" ], "comment": "dirt floor; room with dirt floor\npit (theater seating); parterre" },
	{ "question": "圧勝", "answers": [ "あっしょう" ], "comment": "complete victory" },
	{ "question": "圧巻", "answers": [ "あっかん" ], "comment": "highlight; best part\nstunning; incredible; superb" },
	{ "question": "在京", "answers": [ "ざいきょう" ], "comment": "being in the capital (i.e. Tokyo, or formerly Kyoto)" },
	{ "question": "在任", "answers": [ "ざいにん" ], "comment": "being in office" },
	{ "question": "在外", "answers": [ "ざいがい" ], "comment": "overseas; abroad" },
	{ "question": "在庫", "answers": [ "ざいこ" ], "comment": "inventory; stock; stockpile" },
	{ "question": "在来", "answers": [ "ざいらい" ], "comment": "pre-existing; already there; conventional" },
	{ "question": "在留", "answers": [ "ざいりゅう" ], "comment": "residing (esp. abroad); staying; living" },
	{ "question": "在籍", "answers": [ "ざいせき" ], "comment": "enrollment; enrolment" },
	{ "question": "在米", "answers": [ "ざいべい" ], "comment": "being in the USA" },
	{ "question": "在職", "answers": [ "ざいしょく" ], "comment": "being in office" },
	{ "question": "在野", "answers": [ "ざいや" ], "comment": "out of office; out of power; in opposition\nunaffiliated (e.g. researcher, scientist); in private practice" },
	{ "question": "地価", "answers": [ "ちか" ], "comment": "the price of land" },
	{ "question": "地力", "answers": [ "じりき" ], "comment": "one's own potential; real ability; one's own strength" },
	{ "question": "地合い", "answers": [ "じあい" ], "comment": "texture (cloth, fabric, paper)\nmarket tone; undertone\nbalance between the position of white and black stones (in go)" },
	{ "question": "地層", "answers": [ "ちそう" ], "comment": "stratum; geological formation; layer; bed (coal, gravel, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "地検", "answers": [ "ちけん" ], "comment": "District Public Prosecutor's Office" },
	{ "question": "地蔵", "answers": [ "じぞう" ], "comment": "Kshitigarbha (bodhisattva who looks over children, travellers and the underworld) (travelers); Ksitigarbha; Jizo" },
	{ "question": "地表", "answers": [ "ちひょう" ], "comment": "surface of the earth; ground surface" },
	{ "question": "地裁", "answers": [ "ちさい" ], "comment": "district court" },
	{ "question": "地道", "answers": [ "じみち" ], "comment": "steady; honest; sober; straightforward" },
	{ "question": "地雷", "answers": [ "じらい" ], "comment": "land mine; booby trap\ntopic that sets one off (esp. based on previous experience); sensitive topic; taboo topic" },
	{ "question": "均一", "answers": [ "きんいつ", "きんいち" ], "comment": "uniformity; equality" },
	{ "question": "均整", "answers": [ "きんせい" ], "comment": "symmetry; balance; proportion; uniformity" },
	{ "question": "垂れ幕", "answers": [ "たれまく" ], "comment": "hanging banner; hanging screen; curtain" },
	{ "question": "型式", "answers": [ "かたしき", "けいしき" ], "comment": "model (e.g. of a vehicle); type" },
	{ "question": "垢", "answers": [ "あか" ], "comment": "dirt; filth; grime\naccount (e.g. online service)" },
	{ "question": "垣", "answers": [ "かき" ], "comment": "fence; hedge; barrier; wall; railing" },
	{ "question": "埋め立て", "answers": [ "うめたて" ], "comment": "land reclamation" },
	{ "question": "埋葬", "answers": [ "まいそう" ], "comment": "burial" },
	{ "question": "埋蔵", "answers": [ "まいぞう" ], "comment": "burying in the ground\nhaving underground deposits" },
	{ "question": "城内", "answers": [ "じょうない" ], "comment": "inside of a castle\narea surrounded by castle walls" },
	{ "question": "域内", "answers": [ "いきない" ], "comment": "inside the area" },
	{ "question": "域外", "answers": [ "いきがい" ], "comment": "outside the area" },
	{ "question": "執務", "answers": [ "しつむ" ], "comment": "performance of one's official duties" },
	{ "question": "執念", "answers": [ "しゅうねん" ], "comment": "tenacity; persistence; obsession; implacability" },
	{ "question": "基幹", "answers": [ "きかん" ], "comment": "mainstay; nucleus; key" },
	{ "question": "基調", "answers": [ "きちょう" ], "comment": "basic tone; underlying tone; basic theme; basis; keynote\ntrend\nkeynote" },
	{ "question": "基軸", "answers": [ "きじく" ], "comment": "key; yardstick; criterion; standard" },
	{ "question": "堀川", "answers": [ "ほりかわ" ], "comment": "canal" },
	{ "question": "堅実", "answers": [ "けんじつ" ], "comment": "steady; sound; reliable; solid" },
	{ "question": "堅持", "answers": [ "けんじ" ], "comment": "holding on to; sticking to" },
	{ "question": "堅調", "answers": [ "けんちょう" ], "comment": "bullish; firm (market)" },
	{ "question": "堆積", "answers": [ "たいせき" ], "comment": "accumulation; pile; heap\nsedimentation" },
	{ "question": "堕落", "answers": [ "だらく" ], "comment": "depravity; corruption; degradation" },
	{ "question": "堤", "answers": [ "つつみ" ], "comment": "bank; embankment; dike" },
	{ "question": "堤防", "answers": [ "ていぼう" ], "comment": "bank; weir; embankment; levee" },
	{ "question": "堪能", "answers": [ "たんのう" ], "comment": "proficient; skillful\nenjoying; satisfaction; satiation; having one's fill (of)" },
	{ "question": "堰", "answers": [ "いせき", "せき" ], "comment": "dam; weir; barrier; sluice" },
	{ "question": "報いる", "answers": [ "むくいる" ], "comment": "to reward; to recompense; to repay\nto retaliate; to get revenge" },
	{ "question": "報う", "answers": [ "むくう" ], "comment": "to reward; to recompense; to repay" },
	{ "question": "場内", "answers": [ "じょうない" ], "comment": "in-house; (on) the grounds; (in) the premises; hall; theatre; theater" },
	{ "question": "場外", "answers": [ "じょうがい" ], "comment": "outside the hall (or stadium, market, etc.); off the grounds; off the premises; off-track" },
	{ "question": "場違い", "answers": [ "ばちがい" ], "comment": "out-of-place; inappropriate; sticking out like a sore thumb" },
	{ "question": "塁", "answers": [ "るい" ], "comment": "base; bag; sack\nfortress; stronghold" },
	{ "question": "塗り替える", "answers": [ "ぬりかえる" ], "comment": "to repaint; to paint again\nto break (a record); to rewrite; to remake" },
	{ "question": "塗る", "answers": [ "ぬる" ], "comment": "to paint; to plaster; to lacquer; to varnish; to spread; to smear; to put up (wallpaper)" },
	{ "question": "塗料", "answers": [ "とりょう" ], "comment": "paints; painting material" },
	{ "question": "塗装", "answers": [ "とそう" ], "comment": "coating; painting" },
	{ "question": "塩分", "answers": [ "えんぶん" ], "comment": "salt; salt content" },
	{ "question": "塩化", "answers": [ "えんか" ], "comment": "chloride" },
	{ "question": "塩味", "answers": [ "しおあじ" ], "comment": "salty taste; saltiness" },
	{ "question": "塩基", "answers": [ "えんき" ], "comment": "base" },
	{ "question": "塩梅", "answers": [ "あんばい" ], "comment": "seasoning; flavour; flavor\ncondition; state; situation\narrangement; assignment; adjustment" },
	{ "question": "塩水", "answers": [ "しおみず", "えんすい" ], "comment": "salt water; brine" },
	{ "question": "塩田", "answers": [ "えんでん" ], "comment": "saltpan; field for drying salt" },
	{ "question": "塩素", "answers": [ "えんそ" ], "comment": "chlorine (Cl)" },
	{ "question": "塾長", "answers": [ "じゅくちょう" ], "comment": "principal of a private school" },
	{ "question": "境地", "answers": [ "きょうち" ], "comment": "state (of mind); mental state; emotional condition\nfield (of activity)\none's lot; circumstance; situation in life\nplace; region; area; land" },
	{ "question": "墓参", "answers": [ "ぼさん", "はかまいり" ], "comment": "visit to a grave" },
	{ "question": "墓石", "answers": [ "はかいし", "ぼせき" ], "comment": "tombstone; gravestone" },
	{ "question": "増収", "answers": [ "ぞうしゅう" ], "comment": "increase in yield" },
	{ "question": "増員", "answers": [ "ぞういん" ], "comment": "increase the number of personnel" },
	{ "question": "増強", "answers": [ "ぞうきょう" ], "comment": "augment; reinforce; increase" },
	{ "question": "増水", "answers": [ "ぞうすい" ], "comment": "rising water (of river, lake, etc.); swelling water; increased water; high water" },
	{ "question": "増産", "answers": [ "ぞうさん" ], "comment": "production increase" },
	{ "question": "増発", "answers": [ "ぞうはつ" ], "comment": "increase the number of trains in operation; increase bond issues" },
	{ "question": "増益", "answers": [ "ぞうえき" ], "comment": "increased (profit)" },
	{ "question": "増税", "answers": [ "ぞうぜい" ], "comment": "tax increase" },
	{ "question": "増設", "answers": [ "ぞうせつ" ], "comment": "extension; expansion; adding (equipment, facilities, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "増資", "answers": [ "ぞうし" ], "comment": "increase of capital" },
	{ "question": "増進", "answers": [ "ぞうしん" ], "comment": "promoting; increase; advance" },
	{ "question": "増額", "answers": [ "ぞうがく" ], "comment": "increased amount" },
	{ "question": "墜落", "answers": [ "ついらく" ], "comment": "falling; crashing" },
	{ "question": "墨付き", "answers": [ "すみつき" ], "comment": "handwriting; autograph; authorization; authorisation\ncertificate; certified document; paper with signature of the shogun or lord" },
	{ "question": "壁画", "answers": [ "へきが" ], "comment": "fresco; mural; wall painting" },
	{ "question": "壁面", "answers": [ "へきめん" ], "comment": "surface of a wall" },
	{ "question": "壇", "answers": [ "だん" ], "comment": "platform; podium; rostrum\nmandala" },
	{ "question": "壇上", "answers": [ "だんじょう" ], "comment": "on a stage; on a platform; on an altar" },
	{ "question": "壕", "answers": [ "ごう" ], "comment": "moat; fosse; trench; ditch\nunderground air-raid shelter; dugout" },
	{ "question": "士気", "answers": [ "しき" ], "comment": "morale (of troops, team, etc.); esprit de corps" },
	{ "question": "壮年", "answers": [ "そうねん" ], "comment": "prime of life" },
	{ "question": "壮行", "answers": [ "そうこう" ], "comment": "rousing" },
	{ "question": "声援", "answers": [ "せいえん" ], "comment": "encouragement; cheering; support" },
	{ "question": "声明", "answers": [ "せいめい" ], "comment": "declaration; statement; proclamation" },
	{ "question": "声楽", "answers": [ "せいがく" ], "comment": "vocal music" },
	{ "question": "声高", "answers": [ "こわだか" ], "comment": "with a loud voice" },
	{ "question": "売り出し", "answers": [ "うりだし" ], "comment": "(bargain) sale" },
	{ "question": "売り出す", "answers": [ "うりだす" ], "comment": "to put on the market; to put out for sale; to put on sale; to begin selling; to market\nto become popular" },
	{ "question": "売り手", "answers": [ "うりて" ], "comment": "seller; vendor" },
	{ "question": "売り物", "answers": [ "うりもの" ], "comment": "article for sale; goods for sale; offering; For Sale (on a sign)\nspecialty; selling point" },
	{ "question": "売り込み", "answers": [ "うりこみ" ], "comment": "sales promotion; hard selling" },
	{ "question": "売り込む", "answers": [ "うりこむ" ], "comment": "to build a market for; to promote (a product); to sell; to become well known\nto promote oneself; to sell oneself\nto sell heavily" },
	{ "question": "変則", "answers": [ "へんそく" ], "comment": "irregularity" },
	{ "question": "変移", "answers": [ "へんい" ], "comment": "change; alteration; transmutation; mutation" },
	{ "question": "変質", "answers": [ "へんしつ" ], "comment": "alteration (of character or essence); change in quality; transformation; deterioration; degeneration; transmutation" },
	{ "question": "変造", "answers": [ "へんぞう" ], "comment": "alteration; defacement; debasement; falsification; forgery" },
	{ "question": "夏ばて", "answers": [ "なつばて", "なつバテ" ], "comment": "suffering from summer heat; summer heat fatigue" },
	{ "question": "夏場", "answers": [ "なつば" ], "comment": "summertime" },
	{ "question": "夏季", "answers": [ "なつき", "かき" ], "comment": "summer season" },
	{ "question": "夏期", "answers": [ "かき" ], "comment": "summer term (e.g. school); summer period" },
	{ "question": "夏至", "answers": [ "げし" ], "comment": "summer solstice" },
	{ "question": "夕刻", "answers": [ "ゆうこく" ], "comment": "evening; evening hour" },
	{ "question": "夕焼け", "answers": [ "ゆうやけ" ], "comment": "evening glow; red sunset; afterglow (of sunset)" },
	{ "question": "外付", "answers": [ "そとづけ" ], "comment": "external (hard drive, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "外付け", "answers": [ "そとづけ" ], "comment": "external (hard drive, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "外信", "answers": [ "がいしん" ], "comment": "external communication" },
	{ "question": "外傷", "answers": [ "がいしょう" ], "comment": "external wound; (physical) trauma" },
	{ "question": "外圧", "answers": [ "がいあつ" ], "comment": "external pressure" },
	{ "question": "外壁", "answers": [ "がいへき", "そとかべ" ], "comment": "outer wall" },
	{ "question": "外気", "answers": [ "がいき" ], "comment": "open air" },
	{ "question": "外洋", "answers": [ "がいよう" ], "comment": "open sea; ocean" },
	{ "question": "外苑", "answers": [ "がいえん" ], "comment": "outer garden" },
	{ "question": "外角", "answers": [ "がいかく" ], "comment": "external angle; exterior angle\noutside corner" },
	{ "question": "外貨", "answers": [ "がいか" ], "comment": "foreign currency; foreign money; foreign exchange\nforeign goods; imported goods" },
	{ "question": "外資", "answers": [ "がいし" ], "comment": "foreign capital (e.g. in a company); foreign investment" },
	{ "question": "外車", "answers": [ "がいしゃ" ], "comment": "foreign automobile" },
	{ "question": "外遊", "answers": [ "がいゆう" ], "comment": "foreign travel" },
	{ "question": "外野", "answers": [ "がいや" ], "comment": "outfield\noutfielder\noutfield bleachers\nthird party; outsider" },
	{ "question": "外需", "answers": [ "がいじゅ" ], "comment": "foreign demand" },
	{ "question": "外面", "answers": [ "がいめん", "そとづら", "げめん" ], "comment": "outer surface; outward appearance; outside; exterior\noutside; outer; outward; exterior; external" },
	{ "question": "外食", "answers": [ "がいしょく" ], "comment": "eating out" },
	{ "question": "多め", "answers": [ "おおめ" ], "comment": "somewhat larger quantity; larger portion" },
	{ "question": "多岐", "answers": [ "たき" ], "comment": "digression; many divergences" },
	{ "question": "多湿", "answers": [ "たしつ" ], "comment": "high humidity" },
	{ "question": "多角", "answers": [ "たかく" ], "comment": "many-sided; versatile; polygonal; diversified" },
	{ "question": "多重", "answers": [ "たじゅう" ], "comment": "multiple; multiplex" },
	{ "question": "多難", "answers": [ "たなん" ], "comment": "full of troubles, difficulties" },
	{ "question": "多面", "answers": [ "ためん" ], "comment": "many-sided; multifaceted" },
	{ "question": "夜具", "answers": [ "やぐ" ], "comment": "bedding; bedclothes" },
	{ "question": "夜勤", "answers": [ "やきん" ], "comment": "night shift" },
	{ "question": "夜学", "answers": [ "やがく" ], "comment": "evening course; night-school" },
	{ "question": "夜景", "answers": [ "やけい" ], "comment": "night view; night skyline; nightscape" },
	{ "question": "夜更かし", "answers": [ "よふかし" ], "comment": "staying up late; keeping late hours; sitting up late at night; nighthawk" },
	{ "question": "夜更け", "answers": [ "よふけ" ], "comment": "late at night; small hours of the morning" },
	{ "question": "夜空", "answers": [ "よぞら" ], "comment": "night sky" },
	{ "question": "夢想", "answers": [ "むそう" ], "comment": "dream; vision; reverie" },
	{ "question": "大さじ", "answers": [ "おおさじ" ], "comment": "tablespoon" },
	{ "question": "大仏", "answers": [ "だいぶつ" ], "comment": "large statue of Buddha (trad. at least 4.8m high)" },
	{ "question": "大作", "answers": [ "たいさく" ], "comment": "epic" },
	{ "question": "大便", "answers": [ "だいべん" ], "comment": "feces; excrement; shit" },
	{ "question": "大別", "answers": [ "たいべつ" ], "comment": "general classification" },
	{ "question": "大勝", "answers": [ "たいしょう" ], "comment": "great victory; crushing victory" },
	{ "question": "大卒", "answers": [ "だいそつ" ], "comment": "university graduate" },
	{ "question": "大口", "answers": [ "おおぐち", "おおくち" ], "comment": "big mouth\nboastful speech; tall talk\nlarge amount; large sum" },
	{ "question": "大台", "answers": [ "おおだい" ], "comment": "(major) mark; level; barrier\n100-yen unit (stock market)" },
	{ "question": "大同", "answers": [ "だいどう" ], "comment": "largely the same\nDaidou era (806.5.18-810.9.19)" },
	{ "question": "大商い", "answers": [ "おおあきない" ], "comment": "heavy turnover (trading)" },
	{ "question": "大喜び", "answers": [ "おおよろこび" ], "comment": "great joy" },
	{ "question": "大山", "answers": [ "たいざん" ], "comment": "great mountain" },
	{ "question": "大店", "answers": [ "おおだな" ], "comment": "large store" },
	{ "question": "大当たり", "answers": [ "おおあたり" ], "comment": "big hit; big prize; bumper crop; striking it rich; right on the mark; bonanza; bull's eye; bullseye" },
	{ "question": "大役", "answers": [ "たいやく" ], "comment": "important task; important role; great duty; important mission\nmajor part (e.g. in a movie)" },
	{ "question": "大急ぎ", "answers": [ "おおいそぎ" ], "comment": "urgent; pressing" },
	{ "question": "大成", "answers": [ "たいせい" ], "comment": "completion; accomplishment; attainment of greatness or success" },
	{ "question": "大掛かり", "answers": [ "おおがかり" ], "comment": "large-scale" },
	{ "question": "大敗", "answers": [ "たいはい" ], "comment": "crushing defeat" },
	{ "question": "大晦日", "answers": [ "おおみそか" ], "comment": "New Year's Eve; December 31st" },
	{ "question": "大水", "answers": [ "おおみず" ], "comment": "flood" },
	{ "question": "大河", "answers": [ "たいが" ], "comment": "large river" },
	{ "question": "大洋", "answers": [ "たいよう" ], "comment": "ocean" },
	{ "question": "大火", "answers": [ "たいか" ], "comment": "large fire" },
	{ "question": "大病", "answers": [ "たいびょう" ], "comment": "serious illness; dangerous disease" },
	{ "question": "大盛り", "answers": [ "おおもり" ], "comment": "large serving" },
	{ "question": "大砲", "answers": [ "たいほう" ], "comment": "gun; cannon; artillery" },
	{ "question": "大破", "answers": [ "たいは" ], "comment": "serious damage; drubbing" },
	{ "question": "大社", "answers": [ "たいしゃ", "おおやしろ" ], "comment": "grand shrine; famous shrine\nIzumo Grand Shrine" },
	{ "question": "大空", "answers": [ "おおぞら" ], "comment": "heavens; firmament; sky" },
	{ "question": "大筋", "answers": [ "おおすじ" ], "comment": "outline; summary" },
	{ "question": "大綱", "answers": [ "たいこう" ], "comment": "fundamental principles; outline; general features" },
	{ "question": "大義", "answers": [ "たいぎ" ], "comment": "great cause; moral law; justice" },
	{ "question": "大脳", "answers": [ "だいのう" ], "comment": "cerebrum" },
	{ "question": "大腸", "answers": [ "だいちょう" ], "comment": "large intestine; large bowel; colon" },
	{ "question": "大船", "answers": [ "おおふね", "たいせん", "おおぶね" ], "comment": "large boat" },
	{ "question": "大詰め", "answers": [ "おおづめ" ], "comment": "final scene; the end; finale" },
	{ "question": "大賞", "answers": [ "たいしょう" ], "comment": "big prize; first prize" },
	{ "question": "大道", "answers": [ "たいどう", "だいどう" ], "comment": "main street; avenue" },
	{ "question": "大関", "answers": [ "おおぜき" ], "comment": "ōzeki (second highest rank in sumo)" },
	{ "question": "大隊", "answers": [ "だいたい" ], "comment": "battalion" },
	{ "question": "大雨", "answers": [ "おおあめ" ], "comment": "heavy rain" },
	{ "question": "大雪", "answers": [ "たいせつ", "おおゆき" ], "comment": "heavy snow\n\"major snow\" solar term (approx. Dec. 7)" },
	{ "question": "大麦", "answers": [ "おおむぎ" ], "comment": "barley (Hordeum vulgare)" },
	{ "question": "大麻", "answers": [ "おおあさ", "たいま" ], "comment": "hemp\ncannabis; marijuana; pot; hashish\nShinto paper offerings" },
	{ "question": "天の川", "answers": [ "あまのがわ" ], "comment": "Milky Way; luminous band corresponding to the plane of the galaxy" },
	{ "question": "天下り", "answers": [ "あまくだり" ], "comment": "retiring high-ranking government officials taking a lucrative job in a private or semi-private corporation\ncommand (from superior to inferior, government to private sector, etc.); order; imposition\ndescent from heaven" },
	{ "question": "天体", "answers": [ "てんたい" ], "comment": "heavenly body; celestial body; astronomical object" },
	{ "question": "天災", "answers": [ "てんさい" ], "comment": "natural calamity; disaster" },
	{ "question": "天神", "answers": [ "てんじん" ], "comment": "heavenly god; heavenly gods\nspirit of Sugawara no Michizane\nTenmangu shrine (dedicated to Michizane's spirit)\npit of a dried plum; dried plum\ntenjin hairstyle\nprostitute of the second-highest class (Edo period)" },
	{ "question": "太っ腹", "answers": [ "ふとっぱら" ], "comment": "generous; magnanimous; big-hearted; broad-minded" },
	{ "question": "失態", "answers": [ "しったい" ], "comment": "mismanagement; fault; error; failure; disgrace; discredit" },
	{ "question": "失敬", "answers": [ "しっけい" ], "comment": "rudeness; saying good-bye; acting impolitely; stealing; impoliteness; disrespect; impertinence" },
	{ "question": "失明", "answers": [ "しつめい" ], "comment": "loss of eyesight; loss of vision; going blind; blindness" },
	{ "question": "失格", "answers": [ "しっかく" ], "comment": "disqualification; elimination; incapacity (legal)" },
	{ "question": "失点", "answers": [ "しってん" ], "comment": "losing points; lost points\nrun charged to the pitcher\nblunder; mistake; error" },
	{ "question": "失策", "answers": [ "しっさく" ], "comment": "blunder; slip; error" },
	{ "question": "失脚", "answers": [ "しっきゃく" ], "comment": "losing one's standing; being overthrown; falling" },
	{ "question": "失跡", "answers": [ "しっせき" ], "comment": "absconding; disappearance" },
	{ "question": "失速", "answers": [ "しっそく" ], "comment": "stall (in flying); stalling\nsuddenly losing momentum; downturn; slump; weakening; decline" },
	{ "question": "奇抜", "answers": [ "きばつ" ], "comment": "novel; original; striking; strange; eccentric; fantastic" },
	{ "question": "奇数", "answers": [ "きすう" ], "comment": "odd number" },
	{ "question": "奇異", "answers": [ "きい" ], "comment": "odd; strange; queer; peculiar" },
	{ "question": "奇襲", "answers": [ "きしゅう" ], "comment": "surprise attack" },
	{ "question": "奏功", "answers": [ "そうこう" ], "comment": "success; achievement; fruition" },
	{ "question": "奏者", "answers": [ "そうしゃ" ], "comment": "instrumentalist; player" },
	{ "question": "奔放", "answers": [ "ほんぽう" ], "comment": "wild; uninhibited; extravagant; rampant" },
	{ "question": "奥地", "answers": [ "おくち", "おうち" ], "comment": "interior; backwoods; hinterland; back regions" },
	{ "question": "奥山", "answers": [ "おくやま" ], "comment": "remote mountain; mountain recesses" },
	{ "question": "奥行", "answers": [ "おくゆき" ], "comment": "depth; length" },
	{ "question": "奥行き", "answers": [ "おくゆき" ], "comment": "depth; length" },
	{ "question": "奨学", "answers": [ "しょうがく" ], "comment": "encouragement to study" },
	{ "question": "奪取", "answers": [ "だっしゅ" ], "comment": "usurpation; taking back; dispossession" },
	{ "question": "奪回", "answers": [ "だっかい" ], "comment": "recovery; rescue; recapture" },
	{ "question": "奪還", "answers": [ "だっかん" ], "comment": "recovery; rescue; recapture" },
	{ "question": "奮う", "answers": [ "ふるう" ], "comment": "to muster (e.g. one's courage); to call forth; to rouse up\nto be enlivened; to be invigorated" },
	{ "question": "奮発", "answers": [ "ふんぱつ" ], "comment": "strenuous exertion; spurt\nsplurge" },
	{ "question": "奮起", "answers": [ "ふんき" ], "comment": "stirring; rousing oneself" },
	{ "question": "奮闘", "answers": [ "ふんとう" ], "comment": "hard struggle; strenuous effort" },
	{ "question": "女児", "answers": [ "じょじ" ], "comment": "baby girl; primary schoolgirl" },
	{ "question": "女史", "answers": [ "じょし" ], "comment": "Ms (nuance of status); Miss; Madame\nhighbrow (woman); cerebral" },
	{ "question": "女形", "answers": [ "おやま", "おんながた" ], "comment": "male actor in female kabuki roles" },
	{ "question": "女流", "answers": [ "じょりゅう" ], "comment": "woman (writer, artist, aviator, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "好天", "answers": [ "こうてん" ], "comment": "fine weather" },
	{ "question": "好投", "answers": [ "こうとう" ], "comment": "good (nice) pitching" },
	{ "question": "好機", "answers": [ "こうき" ], "comment": "good opportunity; chance" },
	{ "question": "好況", "answers": [ "こうきょう" ], "comment": "prosperous conditions; healthy economy" },
	{ "question": "好物", "answers": [ "こうぶつ" ], "comment": "favourite dish (favorite); favourite food" },
	{ "question": "好評", "answers": [ "こうひょう" ], "comment": "popularity; favorable reputation; favourable reputation" },
	{ "question": "好調", "answers": [ "こうちょう" ], "comment": "favourable; favorable; promising; satisfactory; in good shape" },
	{ "question": "好転", "answers": [ "こうてん" ], "comment": "changing for the better" },
	{ "question": "如実", "answers": [ "にょじつ" ], "comment": "reality; actuality; actual conditions; true situation; faithful representation; vivid depiction\nultimate reality; absolute truth" },
	{ "question": "妃", "answers": [ "きさき", "ひ" ], "comment": "princess; consort" },
	{ "question": "妄信", "answers": [ "もうしん", "ぼうしん" ], "comment": "blind acceptance; blind belief; credulity" },
	{ "question": "妖精", "answers": [ "ようせい" ], "comment": "fairy; sprite; elf" },
	{ "question": "妥結", "answers": [ "だけつ" ], "comment": "settlement; an agreement" },
	{ "question": "妨げ", "answers": [ "さまたげ" ], "comment": "obstruction; hindrance" },
	{ "question": "始業", "answers": [ "しぎょう" ], "comment": "start of work; commencement; opening" },
	{ "question": "始発", "answers": [ "しはつ" ], "comment": "first departure (of the day: train, bus, etc.); first train; first bus\ndeparting one's home station (of a train, bus, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "姓名", "answers": [ "せいめい" ], "comment": "full name" },
	{ "question": "委任", "answers": [ "いにん" ], "comment": "charge; trust" },
	{ "question": "委嘱", "answers": [ "いしょく" ], "comment": "entrusting (with)" },
	{ "question": "威信", "answers": [ "いしん" ], "comment": "prestige; dignity" },
	{ "question": "威勢", "answers": [ "いせい" ], "comment": "power; might; authority; influence\nspirits; vigor; vigour; energy; boldness" },
	{ "question": "威嚇", "answers": [ "いかく" ], "comment": "menace; threat; intimidation\nto threaten; to intimidate" },
	{ "question": "娘婿", "answers": [ "むすめむこ" ], "comment": "son-in-law" },
	{ "question": "娼婦", "answers": [ "しょうふ" ], "comment": "prostitute; harlot" },
	{ "question": "婉曲", "answers": [ "えんきょく" ], "comment": "euphemistic; circumlocutory; roundabout; indirect" },
	{ "question": "婦女", "answers": [ "ふじょ" ], "comment": "woman; womankind" },
	{ "question": "嫌がらせ", "answers": [ "いやがらせ" ], "comment": "harassment; pestering" },
	{ "question": "嫌気", "answers": [ "いやけ", "けんき", "いやき" ], "comment": "dislike; disgust; disinclination; tired of" },
	{ "question": "嫌疑", "answers": [ "けんぎ" ], "comment": "suspicion" },
	{ "question": "嫡出", "answers": [ "てきしゅつ", "ちゃくしゅつ" ], "comment": "legitimate birth" },
	{ "question": "子女", "answers": [ "しじょ" ], "comment": "sons and daughters; male and female children; children\ngirl" },
	{ "question": "子弟", "answers": [ "してい" ], "comment": "young(er) people" },
	{ "question": "子役", "answers": [ "こやく" ], "comment": "dramatic role for child; child actor" },
	{ "question": "子息", "answers": [ "しそく" ], "comment": "son" },
	{ "question": "子牛", "answers": [ "こうし" ], "comment": "calf; small cow" },
	{ "question": "子猫", "answers": [ "こねこ" ], "comment": "kitten" },
	{ "question": "子羊", "answers": [ "こひつじ" ], "comment": "lamb" },
	{ "question": "字幕", "answers": [ "じまく" ], "comment": "subtitles; captioning" },
	{ "question": "字形", "answers": [ "じけい" ], "comment": "character style; character form" },
	{ "question": "字数", "answers": [ "じすう" ], "comment": "number of characters or letters" },
	{ "question": "字画", "answers": [ "じかく" ], "comment": "number of strokes in character" },
	{ "question": "存亡", "answers": [ "そんぼう" ], "comment": "life or death; existence; destiny" },
	{ "question": "存廃", "answers": [ "そんぱい" ], "comment": "(whether to) continue or eliminate; existence" },
	{ "question": "存立", "answers": [ "そんりつ" ], "comment": "existence; subsistence" },
	{ "question": "季刊", "answers": [ "きかん" ], "comment": "quarterly (e.g. magazine)" },
	{ "question": "季語", "answers": [ "きご" ], "comment": "seasonal word (in haiku)" },
	{ "question": "孤児", "answers": [ "こじ", "みなしご" ], "comment": "orphan" },
	{ "question": "学位", "answers": [ "がくい" ], "comment": "(university) degree; (academic) degree" },
	{ "question": "学内", "answers": [ "がくない" ], "comment": "within the school" },
	{ "question": "学割", "answers": [ "がくわり" ], "comment": "student discount" },
	{ "question": "学割り", "answers": [ "がくわり" ], "comment": "student discount" },
	{ "question": "学区", "answers": [ "がっく" ], "comment": "school district; school area" },
	{ "question": "学卒", "answers": [ "がくそつ" ], "comment": "college graduate" },
	{ "question": "学士", "answers": [ "がくし" ], "comment": "university graduate; bachelor\nbachelor's degree" },
	{ "question": "学徒", "answers": [ "がくと" ], "comment": "student; follower; students and pupils" },
	{ "question": "学業", "answers": [ "がくぎょう" ], "comment": "studies; schoolwork; classwork" },
	{ "question": "学界", "answers": [ "がっかい" ], "comment": "academic world; academia; academic circles; scientific world; learned circles" },
	{ "question": "学童", "answers": [ "がくどう" ], "comment": "school child; pupil" },
	{ "question": "学芸", "answers": [ "がくげい" ], "comment": "arts and sciences; liberal arts" },
	{ "question": "学識", "answers": [ "がくしき" ], "comment": "scholarship; scientific attainments" },
	{ "question": "学費", "answers": [ "がくひ" ], "comment": "tuition; school expenses" },
	{ "question": "学長", "answers": [ "がくちょう" ], "comment": "university president" },
	{ "question": "学際", "answers": [ "がくさい" ], "comment": "interdisciplinary" },
	{ "question": "宅地", "answers": [ "たくち" ], "comment": "building lot; residential land" },
	{ "question": "守勢", "answers": [ "しゅせい" ], "comment": "(being on the) defensive" },
	{ "question": "守衛", "answers": [ "しゅえい" ], "comment": "security guard; doorkeeper" },
	{ "question": "安っぽい", "answers": [ "やすっぽい" ], "comment": "cheap-looking; tawdry; insignificant" },
	{ "question": "安らか", "answers": [ "やすらか" ], "comment": "peaceful; tranquil; calm; restful" },
	{ "question": "安らぎ", "answers": [ "やすらぎ" ], "comment": "peace (of mind); tranquility; tranquillity; serenity" },
	{ "question": "安らぐ", "answers": [ "やすらぐ" ], "comment": "to feel at ease" },
	{ "question": "安上がり", "answers": [ "やすあがり" ], "comment": "cheap; economical" },
	{ "question": "安住", "answers": [ "あんじゅう" ], "comment": "living in peace; being content with one's present position" },
	{ "question": "安値", "answers": [ "やすね" ], "comment": "low price" },
	{ "question": "安否", "answers": [ "あんぴ" ], "comment": "safety; welfare; well-being" },
	{ "question": "安売り", "answers": [ "やすうり" ], "comment": "discount; bargain sale; selling cheaply" },
	{ "question": "安打", "answers": [ "あんだ" ], "comment": "safe hit" },
	{ "question": "安泰", "answers": [ "あんたい" ], "comment": "peace; security; tranquility; tranquillity" },
	{ "question": "安物", "answers": [ "やすもの" ], "comment": "cheap article; poor quality article" },
	{ "question": "安眠", "answers": [ "あんみん" ], "comment": "quiet sleep" },
	{ "question": "安静", "answers": [ "あんせい" ], "comment": "rest; quiet; repose" },
	{ "question": "完売", "answers": [ "かんばい" ], "comment": "sold out" },
	{ "question": "完封", "answers": [ "かんぷう" ], "comment": "complete blockade (seal); baseball shutout" },
	{ "question": "完工", "answers": [ "かんこう" ], "comment": "completion" },
	{ "question": "完投", "answers": [ "かんとう" ], "comment": "going the whole distance; pitching a whole game" },
	{ "question": "完敗", "answers": [ "かんぱい" ], "comment": "complete defeat; utter defeat; annihilation\nto be completely defeated; to be beaten hollow" },
	{ "question": "完治", "answers": [ "かんち", "かんじ" ], "comment": "complete recovery" },
	{ "question": "完走", "answers": [ "かんそう" ], "comment": "finishing a race; reaching the goal; staying the course" },
	{ "question": "宗派", "answers": [ "しゅうは" ], "comment": "sect; denomination" },
	{ "question": "宗門", "answers": [ "しゅうもん" ], "comment": "doctrine; creed; sect" },
	{ "question": "官公庁", "answers": [ "かんこうちょう" ], "comment": "government administration office" },
	{ "question": "官報", "answers": [ "かんぽう" ], "comment": "official daily gazette; official telegram" },
	{ "question": "官房", "answers": [ "かんぼう" ], "comment": "government secretariat" },
	{ "question": "官民", "answers": [ "かんみん" ], "comment": "government and people; government and private sector; public and private sector" },
	{ "question": "官界", "answers": [ "かんかい" ], "comment": "bureaucracy" },
	{ "question": "官邸", "answers": [ "かんてい" ], "comment": "official residence (e.g. of the prime minister)" },
	{ "question": "定休", "answers": [ "ていきゅう" ], "comment": "regular holiday; fixed day off; regular closing day" },
	{ "question": "定住", "answers": [ "ていじゅう" ], "comment": "settlement; permanent residency\nto settle down in; to reside in" },
	{ "question": "定例", "answers": [ "ていれい", "じょうれい" ], "comment": "regular; ordinary (e.g. session of parliament)\nestablished usage; precedent; regular practice" },
	{ "question": "定刻", "answers": [ "ていこく" ], "comment": "appointed time; timetable; schedule" },
	{ "question": "定型", "answers": [ "ていけい" ], "comment": "fixed form; regular shape; stereotyped" },
	{ "question": "定形", "answers": [ "ていけい" ], "comment": "fixed form; regular shape; stereotyped" },
	{ "question": "定数", "answers": [ "じょうすう", "ていすう" ], "comment": "fixed number; quorum (for an assembly)\nconstant; invariable\nliteral\nfate" },
	{ "question": "定時", "answers": [ "ていじ" ], "comment": "regular time; stated period" },
	{ "question": "定率", "answers": [ "ていりつ" ], "comment": "fixed rate" },
	{ "question": "定番", "answers": [ "ていばん" ], "comment": "standard; routine; regular; basic; staple" },
	{ "question": "定評", "answers": [ "ていひょう" ], "comment": "established opinion; established reputation; acknowledged authority; recognized scholar" },
	{ "question": "定説", "answers": [ "ていせつ" ], "comment": "established theory; accepted opinion; accepted explanation" },
	{ "question": "定量", "answers": [ "ていりょう" ], "comment": "fixed quantity" },
	{ "question": "定額", "answers": [ "ていがく" ], "comment": "ration; fixed amount" },
	{ "question": "定食", "answers": [ "ていしょく" ], "comment": "set meal; special (of the day)" },
	{ "question": "宛先", "answers": [ "あてさき" ], "comment": "address; destination" },
	{ "question": "宝くじ", "answers": [ "たからクジ", "たからくじ" ], "comment": "lottery" },
	{ "question": "宝庫", "answers": [ "ほうこ" ], "comment": "treasury; treasure house" },
	{ "question": "宝飾", "answers": [ "ほうしょく" ], "comment": "jewels and ornaments; jewelry; jewellery" },
	{ "question": "実り", "answers": [ "みのり" ], "comment": "ripening (of a crop)\ncrop; harvest" },
	{ "question": "実像", "answers": [ "じつぞう" ], "comment": "real image\nreal form; real-life image; true picture; actual conditions; actual circumstances" },
	{ "question": "実兄", "answers": [ "じっけい" ], "comment": "one's own elder brother" },
	{ "question": "実刑", "answers": [ "じっけい" ], "comment": "jail sentence; gaol sentence\nimprisonment without a stay of execution" },
	{ "question": "実利", "answers": [ "じつり" ], "comment": "use; utility; profit; gain" },
	{ "question": "実効", "answers": [ "じっこう" ], "comment": "practical effect; efficacy; efficiency" },
	{ "question": "実勢", "answers": [ "じっせい" ], "comment": "actual; real; true" },
	{ "question": "実名", "answers": [ "じつめい" ], "comment": "real name" },
	{ "question": "実地", "answers": [ "じっち" ], "comment": "practice\nthe actual site" },
	{ "question": "実子", "answers": [ "じっし" ], "comment": "biological child; one's own child" },
	{ "question": "実弟", "answers": [ "じってい" ], "comment": "one's (biological) younger brother" },
	{ "question": "実弾", "answers": [ "じつだん" ], "comment": "live bullets; live ammunition; ball cartridge; money" },
	{ "question": "実戦", "answers": [ "じっせん" ], "comment": "combat; actual fighting" },
	{ "question": "実技", "answers": [ "じつぎ" ], "comment": "practical skill" },
	{ "question": "実数", "answers": [ "じっすう" ], "comment": "real number" },
	{ "question": "実権", "answers": [ "じっけん" ], "comment": "real power" },
	{ "question": "実況", "answers": [ "じっきょう" ], "comment": "actual state (of things); real state; actual condition; real condition; actual scene\nlive; on-the-scene\nreporting live; live coverage; live broadcasting" },
	{ "question": "実演", "answers": [ "じつえん" ], "comment": "demonstration; presentation\nstage show; performance" },
	{ "question": "実相", "answers": [ "じっそう" ], "comment": "reality; real state of affairs; true state of affairs\ntrue form of all things as they are; ultimate reality" },
	{ "question": "実話", "answers": [ "じつわ" ], "comment": "true story" },
	{ "question": "実費", "answers": [ "じっぴ" ], "comment": "actual expense; cost price" },
	{ "question": "客体", "answers": [ "きゃくたい", "かくたい" ], "comment": "object" },
	{ "question": "客員", "answers": [ "きゃくいん", "かくいん" ], "comment": "guest (associate) member" },
	{ "question": "客室", "answers": [ "きゃくしつ" ], "comment": "guest room (at a hotel); guest cabin (on a boat); passenger cabin (on a plane)\ndrawing room" },
	{ "question": "客船", "answers": [ "きゃくせん" ], "comment": "passenger boat" },
	{ "question": "客足", "answers": [ "きゃくあし" ], "comment": "customer traffic; customers; custom" },
	{ "question": "客車", "answers": [ "かくしゃ", "きゃくしゃ" ], "comment": "passenger car" },
	{ "question": "宣戦", "answers": [ "せんせん" ], "comment": "declaration of war" },
	{ "question": "宣誓", "answers": [ "せんせい" ], "comment": "oath; abjuration; pledge" },
	{ "question": "室", "answers": [ "しつ" ], "comment": "room\nwife (of someone of high rank)\nscabbard\nChinese \"Encampment\" constellation (one of the 28 mansions)" },
	{ "question": "室長", "answers": [ "しつちょう" ], "comment": "section chief; laboratory manager; office head; room monitor" },
	{ "question": "宮中", "answers": [ "きゅうちゅう" ], "comment": "imperial court" },
	{ "question": "宰相", "answers": [ "さいしょう" ], "comment": "prime minister" },
	{ "question": "害する", "answers": [ "がいする" ], "comment": "to injure; to damage; to harm; to hurt\nto kill\nto hinder; to obstruct" },
	{ "question": "害虫", "answers": [ "がいちゅう" ], "comment": "harmful insect; noxious insect; vermin; pest" },
	{ "question": "家元", "answers": [ "いえもと" ], "comment": "head of a school (of music, dance); head family of a school" },
	{ "question": "家出", "answers": [ "いえで" ], "comment": "running away from home; elopement\nouting; going out\nbecoming a Buddhist monk; entering the priesthood" },
	{ "question": "家宅", "answers": [ "かたく" ], "comment": "domicile; premises" },
	{ "question": "家柄", "answers": [ "いえがら" ], "comment": "social standing of a family; lineage; parentage; pedigree\ngood family" },
	{ "question": "家業", "answers": [ "かぎょう" ], "comment": "family business; trade; occupation; line of work; one's father's occupation" },
	{ "question": "家系", "answers": [ "かけい" ], "comment": "family lineage" },
	{ "question": "家裁", "answers": [ "かさい" ], "comment": "family court" },
	{ "question": "家財", "answers": [ "かざい" ], "comment": "household belongings; household goods\nfamily fortune; family assets" },
	{ "question": "宿屋", "answers": [ "やどや" ], "comment": "inn" },
	{ "question": "宿舎", "answers": [ "しゅくしゃ" ], "comment": "lodging house" },
	{ "question": "宿駅", "answers": [ "しゅくえき" ], "comment": "relay station; post station; stage" },
	{ "question": "寂然", "answers": [ "じゃくねん", "せきぜん" ], "comment": "lonely; desolate\nforlornness; desolation" },
	{ "question": "寄せ集め", "answers": [ "よせあつめ" ], "comment": "mish-mash; miscellany; medley; odds and ends; gathering" },
	{ "question": "寄り道", "answers": [ "よりみち" ], "comment": "dropping in on the way; breaking one's journey; making a stopover; going out of one's way" },
	{ "question": "寄り集まる", "answers": [ "よりあつまる" ], "comment": "to gather together" },
	{ "question": "寄席", "answers": [ "よせ", "よせせき" ], "comment": "entertainment hall (for rakugo, manzai, magic, music, etc.); vaudeville theater (theatre); music hall" },
	{ "question": "寄港", "answers": [ "きこう" ], "comment": "stopping at a port" },
	{ "question": "寄生", "answers": [ "きせい" ], "comment": "parasitism; parasitic" },
	{ "question": "寄贈", "answers": [ "きそう", "きぞう" ], "comment": "donation; presentation; gift" },
	{ "question": "寄金", "answers": [ "ききん" ], "comment": "contribution; donation" },
	{ "question": "寅", "answers": [ "とら" ], "comment": "third sign of Chinese zodiac (The Tiger, 3am-5am, east-northeast, January)" },
	{ "question": "密売", "answers": [ "みつばい" ], "comment": "smuggling; bootlegging; illicit trade" },
	{ "question": "密室", "answers": [ "みっしつ" ], "comment": "room that cannot be entered (e.g. because it's locked from the inside)\nsecret room" },
	{ "question": "密林", "answers": [ "みつりん" ], "comment": "close thicket; dense forest; jungle\namazon.com" },
	{ "question": "密猟", "answers": [ "みつりょう" ], "comment": "poaching" },
	{ "question": "密約", "answers": [ "みつやく" ], "comment": "secret agreement" },
	{ "question": "密航", "answers": [ "みっこう" ], "comment": "smuggling" },
	{ "question": "密輸", "answers": [ "みつゆ" ], "comment": "smuggling; contraband trade" },
	{ "question": "密集", "answers": [ "みっしゅう" ], "comment": "crowd; close formation; dense" },
	{ "question": "富者", "answers": [ "ふしゃ", "ふうしゃ" ], "comment": "rich person; millionaire; the wealthy" },
	{ "question": "富裕", "answers": [ "ふゆう" ], "comment": "wealth; riches; opulence" },
	{ "question": "富豪", "answers": [ "ふごう" ], "comment": "wealthy person; millionaire" },
	{ "question": "寒冷", "answers": [ "かんれい" ], "comment": "cold; coldness; chilliness" },
	{ "question": "寒気", "answers": [ "かんき", "さむけ" ], "comment": "chill; the shivers; shivering fit\ncold; coldness; cold air" },
	{ "question": "寒波", "answers": [ "かんぱ" ], "comment": "cold wave" },
	{ "question": "寛大", "answers": [ "かんだい" ], "comment": "tolerant; generous; lenient; broad-minded; magnanimous" },
	{ "question": "寛容", "answers": [ "かんよう" ], "comment": "tolerance; open-mindedness; forbearance; generosity" },
	{ "question": "寝", "answers": [ "しん", "ね" ], "comment": "sleep" },
	{ "question": "寝かす", "answers": [ "ねかす" ], "comment": "to put to sleep; to lay (something) on its side" },
	{ "question": "寝ぼける", "answers": [ "ねぼける" ], "comment": "to be still half asleep; to be half awake; to be not yet quite awake" },
	{ "question": "寝付く", "answers": [ "ねつく" ], "comment": "to go to bed; to go to sleep; to fall asleep\nto be laid up (with a cold); to be ill in bed" },
	{ "question": "寝具", "answers": [ "しんぐ" ], "comment": "bedding" },
	{ "question": "寝冷え", "answers": [ "ねびえ" ], "comment": "get chilled while asleep" },
	{ "question": "寝床", "answers": [ "ねどこ" ], "comment": "bed; berth; crib; cot; kip" },
	{ "question": "寝息", "answers": [ "ねいき" ], "comment": "sleeper's breathing" },
	{ "question": "寝泊まり", "answers": [ "ねとまり" ], "comment": "staying at; lodging at" },
	{ "question": "寝相", "answers": [ "ねぞう" ], "comment": "one's sleeping posture" },
	{ "question": "寝言", "answers": [ "ねごと" ], "comment": "sleep-talking\nnonsense; gibberish" },
	{ "question": "寝転ぶ", "answers": [ "ねころぶ" ], "comment": "to lie down; to throw oneself down" },
	{ "question": "寝返り", "answers": [ "ねがえり" ], "comment": "turning over while sleeping in bed\nbetrayal; double-crossing" },
	{ "question": "寝返る", "answers": [ "ねがえる" ], "comment": "to change sides; to double-cross; to betray" },
	{ "question": "寝過ごす", "answers": [ "ねすごす" ], "comment": "to oversleep" },
	{ "question": "寝顔", "answers": [ "ねがお" ], "comment": "sleeping face" },
	{ "question": "寡占", "answers": [ "かせん" ], "comment": "oligopoly" },
	{ "question": "寡婦", "answers": [ "やもめ", "かふ" ], "comment": "widow; divorced woman not remarried; unmarried woman" },
	{ "question": "審理", "answers": [ "しんり" ], "comment": "trial" },
	{ "question": "寸断", "answers": [ "すんだん" ], "comment": "cut (tear) to pieces" },
	{ "question": "対中", "answers": [ "たいちゅう" ], "comment": "relating to China" },
	{ "question": "対価", "answers": [ "たいか" ], "comment": "compensation; equivalent value; consideration" },
	{ "question": "対向", "answers": [ "たいこう" ], "comment": "counter-; corresponding; face; opposite" },
	{ "question": "対地", "answers": [ "たいち" ], "comment": "ground to ground" },
	{ "question": "対局", "answers": [ "たいきょく" ], "comment": "(playing) a game of go, shogi or chess, etc." },
	{ "question": "対峙", "answers": [ "たいじ" ], "comment": "confrontation; standing facing each other (e.g. mountains, buildings)\nsquaring off against (adversaries, armies, forces); standing off against; holding one's own with" },
	{ "question": "対戦", "answers": [ "たいせん" ], "comment": "waging war; competition" },
	{ "question": "対日", "answers": [ "たいにち" ], "comment": "with respect to Japan; with Japan" },
	{ "question": "対案", "answers": [ "たいあん" ], "comment": "counter-proposal; counter-suggestion" },
	{ "question": "対極", "answers": [ "たいきょく" ], "comment": "antipodes\nother (opposite) extreme; opposite; antithesis" },
	{ "question": "対米", "answers": [ "たいべい" ], "comment": "relating to the USA; toward America; with America" },
	{ "question": "対談", "answers": [ "たいだん" ], "comment": "talk; dialogue; conversation" },
	{ "question": "寿", "answers": [ "ことぶき" ], "comment": "congratulations; felicitations; best wishes\nlongevity; long life" },
	{ "question": "封", "answers": [ "ふう" ], "comment": "seal" },
	{ "question": "封書", "answers": [ "ふうしょ" ], "comment": "sealed letter" },
	{ "question": "封鎖", "answers": [ "ふうさ" ], "comment": "blockade\nfreezing (funds)" },
	{ "question": "専任", "answers": [ "せんにん" ], "comment": "full-time service" },
	{ "question": "専修", "answers": [ "せんしゅう" ], "comment": "specialization; specialisation" },
	{ "question": "専売", "answers": [ "せんばい" ], "comment": "monopoly" },
	{ "question": "専属", "answers": [ "せんぞく" ], "comment": "exclusive; attached to; specialist" },
	{ "question": "専従", "answers": [ "せんじゅう" ], "comment": "working exclusively for; working full-time (for)" },
	{ "question": "射止める", "answers": [ "いとめる" ], "comment": "to shoot dead; to make something one's own" },
	{ "question": "射殺", "answers": [ "しゃさつ" ], "comment": "shooting to death" },
	{ "question": "射程", "answers": [ "しゃてい" ], "comment": "range (e.g. of a rifle, missile, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "射精", "answers": [ "しゃせい" ], "comment": "ejaculation" },
	{ "question": "将兵", "answers": [ "しょうへい" ], "comment": "officers and men" },
	{ "question": "尊ぶ", "answers": [ "たっとぶ", "とうとぶ" ], "comment": "to value; to prize; to esteem; to respect" },
	{ "question": "尊厳", "answers": [ "そんげん" ], "comment": "dignity; majesty; sanctity" },
	{ "question": "小さじ", "answers": [ "こさじ" ], "comment": "teaspoon" },
	{ "question": "小人", "answers": [ "こども", "こびと", "しょうじん", "しょうにん" ], "comment": "child; small person\ndwarf; midget\nnarrow-minded person; mean person" },
	{ "question": "小切手", "answers": [ "こぎって" ], "comment": "cheque; check" },
	{ "question": "小刻み", "answers": [ "こきざみ" ], "comment": "mincing\ndoing something repeatedly over a short interval (trembling, stepping quickly, etc.)\nbit by bit; little by little" },
	{ "question": "小口", "answers": [ "こぐち" ], "comment": "cut end; edge (of a page, etc.)\nsmall amount; small sum\nbeginning; clue\ntiger's den; jaws of death; dangerous place" },
	{ "question": "小品", "answers": [ "しょうひん" ], "comment": "short piece (of music, writing); small work (painting, sculpture, etc.); literary sketch; essay\nsmall article; small item" },
	{ "question": "小国", "answers": [ "しょうこく" ], "comment": "small country" },
	{ "question": "小売", "answers": [ "こうり" ], "comment": "retail" },
	{ "question": "小売り", "answers": [ "こうり" ], "comment": "retail" },
	{ "question": "小山", "answers": [ "こやま" ], "comment": "hill; knoll" },
	{ "question": "小島", "answers": [ "しょうとう", "こじま", "おじま" ], "comment": "small island; islet" },
	{ "question": "小川", "answers": [ "おがわ" ], "comment": "streamlet; brook" },
	{ "question": "小幅", "answers": [ "こはば" ], "comment": "small; narrow\nsingle-breadth cloth (approx. 36 cm wide)" },
	{ "question": "小康", "answers": [ "しょうこう" ], "comment": "lull" },
	{ "question": "小柄", "answers": [ "こがら" ], "comment": "small build; small stature; petite\nsmall pattern" },
	{ "question": "小火", "answers": [ "ぼや", "しょうか" ], "comment": "small fire" },
	{ "question": "小物", "answers": [ "こもの" ], "comment": "accessories; small articles" },
	{ "question": "小結", "answers": [ "こむすび" ], "comment": "wrestler of the fourth highest rank" },
	{ "question": "小豆", "answers": [ "あずき", "しょうず" ], "comment": "adzuki bean (Vigna angularis)" },
	{ "question": "小量", "answers": [ "しょうりょう" ], "comment": "small dose; small quantity\nnarrowmindedness" },
	{ "question": "小銃", "answers": [ "しょうじゅう" ], "comment": "rifle; small arms" },
	{ "question": "小雨", "answers": [ "しょうう", "こあめ", "こさめ" ], "comment": "light rain; drizzle" },
	{ "question": "少将", "answers": [ "しょうしょう" ], "comment": "major general; rear admiral; air commodore" },
	{ "question": "少額", "answers": [ "しょうがく" ], "comment": "small sum (e.g. of money); small denomination" },
	{ "question": "就労", "answers": [ "しゅうろう" ], "comment": "working; being employed; being hired" },
	{ "question": "就学", "answers": [ "しゅうがく" ], "comment": "entering school; school attendance" },
	{ "question": "就寝", "answers": [ "しゅうしん" ], "comment": "going to bed; retiring (for the night)" },
	{ "question": "就航", "answers": [ "しゅうこう" ], "comment": "going into commission (e.g. ships)" },
	{ "question": "尾根", "answers": [ "おね" ], "comment": "(mountain) ridge; spur" },
	{ "question": "局員", "answers": [ "きょくいん" ], "comment": "clerk; (bureau, post-office) staff" },
	{ "question": "局地", "answers": [ "きょくち" ], "comment": "municipal; limited area; locality" },
	{ "question": "局長", "answers": [ "きょくちょう" ], "comment": "bureau director; office chief" },
	{ "question": "居合わせる", "answers": [ "いあわせる" ], "comment": "to happen to be present" },
	{ "question": "居室", "answers": [ "きょしつ" ], "comment": "living room" },
	{ "question": "屈折", "answers": [ "くっせつ" ], "comment": "bending; indentation\nrefraction\ninflection\nwarping (e.g. of opinion, reasoning, etc.); distortion" },
	{ "question": "屈指", "answers": [ "くっし" ], "comment": "leading; foremost; preeminent; outstanding; one of the best" },
	{ "question": "屈託", "answers": [ "くったく" ], "comment": "worry; care; concern\nennui; boredom" },
	{ "question": "届け出", "answers": [ "とどけで" ], "comment": "report; notification" },
	{ "question": "屋内", "answers": [ "おくない" ], "comment": "indoor (court, pool, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "屋台", "answers": [ "やたい" ], "comment": "cart (esp. a food cart); stall; stand\nfestival float; portable shrine dedicated to a god and shaped like a house; dancing platform\nstage prop fashioned after a large building\nframework (of a house, etc.)\nhouse (esp. a small and miserable house)" },
	{ "question": "屏風", "answers": [ "びょうぶ" ], "comment": "folding screen" },
	{ "question": "履物", "answers": [ "はきもの" ], "comment": "footwear; clogs" },
	{ "question": "山地", "answers": [ "やまち", "さんち" ], "comment": "mountainous district" },
	{ "question": "山川", "answers": [ "さんせん", "やまかわ" ], "comment": "mountains and rivers" },
	{ "question": "山形", "answers": [ "やまがた" ], "comment": "mountain-shape; chevron; cone" },
	{ "question": "山手", "answers": [ "やまて" ], "comment": "place near the mountains\nhilly section of a city (e.g. Tokyo, Kobe, Yokohama)" },
	{ "question": "山村", "answers": [ "さんそん" ], "comment": "mountain village" },
	{ "question": "山登り", "answers": [ "やまのぼり" ], "comment": "mountain climbing; mountaineering" },
	{ "question": "山積", "answers": [ "さんせき" ], "comment": "lying in piles; form into piles; forming a (huge) pile" },
	{ "question": "山系", "answers": [ "さんけい" ], "comment": "mountain range; mountain system" },
	{ "question": "山荘", "answers": [ "さんそう" ], "comment": "mountain villa; mountain retreat; mountain cottage" },
	{ "question": "山菜", "answers": [ "さんさい" ], "comment": "edible wild plants" },
	{ "question": "山野", "answers": [ "さんや" ], "comment": "hills and fields; countryside" },
	{ "question": "山間", "answers": [ "さんかん" ], "comment": "among the mountains" },
	{ "question": "山陰", "answers": [ "やまかげ", "さんいん" ], "comment": "place in the shade of a mountain; shelter of the mountains\nmountain recess" },
	{ "question": "岐路", "answers": [ "きろ" ], "comment": "forked road; crossroads" },
	{ "question": "岩山", "answers": [ "いわやま" ], "comment": "rocky mountain" },
	{ "question": "岩盤", "answers": [ "がんばん" ], "comment": "bedrock" },
	{ "question": "岩石", "answers": [ "がんせき" ], "comment": "rock" },
	{ "question": "岸壁", "answers": [ "がんぺき" ], "comment": "wharf; breakwater; steep cliff" },
	{ "question": "岸辺", "answers": [ "きしべ" ], "comment": "shore; bank (of a body of water)" },
	{ "question": "島々", "answers": [ "しまじま" ], "comment": "islands" },
	{ "question": "島内", "answers": [ "とうない" ], "comment": "on an island; on-island" },
	{ "question": "島国", "answers": [ "とうごく", "しまぐに" ], "comment": "island country (sometimes used as a metaphor for Japan)" },
	{ "question": "崩れ", "answers": [ "くずれ" ], "comment": "crumbling; collapse; ruin\nhas-been; wannabe" },
	{ "question": "崩落", "answers": [ "ほうらく" ], "comment": "collapse; break; cave-in; crash; (market) decline" },
	{ "question": "川上", "answers": [ "かわかみ" ], "comment": "upper reaches of a river; upstream" },
	{ "question": "川口", "answers": [ "かこう", "かわぐち" ], "comment": "mouth of river; estuary" },
	{ "question": "川柳", "answers": [ "せんりゅう" ], "comment": "senryu; comic haiku; humorous seventeen-syllable poem" },
	{ "question": "川沿い", "answers": [ "かわぞい" ], "comment": "along the river; riverside" },
	{ "question": "州都", "answers": [ "しゅうと" ], "comment": "state capital; provincial capital; county town" },
	{ "question": "巡回", "answers": [ "じゅんかい" ], "comment": "going around; patrol; round; tour" },
	{ "question": "巡業", "answers": [ "じゅんぎょう" ], "comment": "provincial tour" },
	{ "question": "巡航", "answers": [ "じゅんこう" ], "comment": "cruise; cruising" },
	{ "question": "巡視", "answers": [ "じゅんし" ], "comment": "inspection tour" },
	{ "question": "工兵", "answers": [ "こうへい" ], "comment": "combat engineer; military engineer; combat engineering; military engineering" },
	{ "question": "工務", "answers": [ "こうむ" ], "comment": "engineering; engineering works" },
	{ "question": "工房", "answers": [ "こうぼう" ], "comment": "workshop; studio; atelier" },
	{ "question": "工法", "answers": [ "こうほう" ], "comment": "method of construction" },
	{ "question": "工科", "answers": [ "こうか" ], "comment": "engineering course" },
	{ "question": "工費", "answers": [ "こうひ" ], "comment": "construction cost" },
	{ "question": "左利き", "answers": [ "ひだりきき" ], "comment": "left-handedness; left-hander\ndrinker; wine lover" },
	{ "question": "左前", "answers": [ "ひだりまえ" ], "comment": "wearing a kimono with the right side over the left (normally used only for the dead)\ngoing badly (one's business, one's fortune, the economy); being in a bad financial situation" },
	{ "question": "左派", "answers": [ "さは" ], "comment": "left wing" },
	{ "question": "左腕", "answers": [ "さわん", "ひだりうで" ], "comment": "left arm\nleft-handed (baseball pitcher)" },
	{ "question": "左記", "answers": [ "さき" ], "comment": "undermentioned (statement); the following; at left" },
	{ "question": "左遷", "answers": [ "させん" ], "comment": "demotion; relegation; reduction in rank; degradation; downward move" },
	{ "question": "巧み", "answers": [ "たくみ" ], "comment": "skillful; adroit; dexterous; masterful; clever; ingenious; cunning" },
	{ "question": "巨体", "answers": [ "きょたい" ], "comment": "large build" },
	{ "question": "巨匠", "answers": [ "きょしょう" ], "comment": "master; masterhand; maestro" },
	{ "question": "巨額", "answers": [ "きょがく" ], "comment": "great sum" },
	{ "question": "差し戻す", "answers": [ "さしもどす" ], "comment": "to send back; to refer back" },
	{ "question": "差し控える", "answers": [ "さしひかえる" ], "comment": "to practice moderation in something; to not do too much of something\nto refrain from doing something; to withhold (e.g. consent, announcement)\nto be close by" },
	{ "question": "差し止め", "answers": [ "さしとめ" ], "comment": "prohibition; ban; suspension" },
	{ "question": "差益", "answers": [ "さえき" ], "comment": "marginal profits" },
	{ "question": "巳", "answers": [ "み" ], "comment": "sixth sign of Chinese zodiac (The Serpent, 9am-11am, south-southeast, April)" },
	{ "question": "巴", "answers": [ "ともえ" ], "comment": "huge comma design" },
	{ "question": "巻き添え", "answers": [ "まきぞえ" ], "comment": "getting mixed up in; getting embroiled in; involvement; entanglement; by-blow" },
	{ "question": "巻き返し", "answers": [ "まきかえし" ], "comment": "rally; recovery; rollback; rewind" },
	{ "question": "巻尺", "answers": [ "まきじゃく" ], "comment": "tape measure" },
	{ "question": "巻末", "answers": [ "かんまつ" ], "comment": "end of a book" },
	{ "question": "巻添え", "answers": [ "まきぞえ" ], "comment": "getting mixed up in; getting embroiled in; involvement; entanglement; by-blow" },
	{ "question": "巽", "answers": [ "そん" ], "comment": "xun (one of the trigrams of the I Ching: wind, southeast)" },
	{ "question": "市中", "answers": [ "しちゅう" ], "comment": "in the city" },
	{ "question": "市内", "answers": [ "しない" ], "comment": "(within a) city; local" },
	{ "question": "市営", "answers": [ "しえい" ], "comment": "municipal management" },
	{ "question": "市外", "answers": [ "しがい" ], "comment": "outside the city area; suburbs" },
	{ "question": "市政", "answers": [ "しせい" ], "comment": "municipal government" },
	{ "question": "市況", "answers": [ "しきょう" ], "comment": "market conditions" },
	{ "question": "市立", "answers": [ "しりつ", "いちりつ" ], "comment": "municipal; city" },
	{ "question": "市議", "answers": [ "しぎ" ], "comment": "city councillor; city councilor; city assemblyman" },
	{ "question": "市道", "answers": [ "しどう" ], "comment": "municipal roads" },
	{ "question": "市部", "answers": [ "しぶ" ], "comment": "urban areas" },
	{ "question": "布告", "answers": [ "ふこく" ], "comment": "edict; ordinance; proclamation" },
	{ "question": "布地", "answers": [ "きれじ", "ぬのじ" ], "comment": "cloth; fabric" },
	{ "question": "布巾", "answers": [ "ふきん" ], "comment": "tea-towel; dish cloth" },
	{ "question": "布教", "answers": [ "ふきょう" ], "comment": "propagation (e.g. a religion); proselytizing; missionary work" },
	{ "question": "布施", "answers": [ "ふせ" ], "comment": "alms; offerings" },
	{ "question": "布石", "answers": [ "ふせき" ], "comment": "strategic arrangement of go stones; opening moves\npreparation; preparatory steps; groundwork" },
	{ "question": "布陣", "answers": [ "ふじん" ], "comment": "battle formation; lineup" },
	{ "question": "帆船", "answers": [ "ほぶね", "はんせん" ], "comment": "sailing ship; sailing boat; sailing vessel" },
	{ "question": "希少", "answers": [ "きしょう" ], "comment": "scarce; rare" },
	{ "question": "帝京", "answers": [ "ていきょう" ], "comment": "the capital" },
	{ "question": "帝政", "answers": [ "ていせい" ], "comment": "imperial government; imperialism; monarchical rule" },
	{ "question": "師事", "answers": [ "しじ" ], "comment": "studying under; looking up to; apprenticing oneself to" },
	{ "question": "師団", "answers": [ "しだん" ], "comment": "(army) division" },
	{ "question": "師走", "answers": [ "しはす", "しわす" ], "comment": "twelfth month (esp. of the lunar calendar); December" },
	{ "question": "席上", "answers": [ "せきじょう" ], "comment": "at the meeting; on the occasion" },
	{ "question": "帰り道", "answers": [ "かえりみち" ], "comment": "the way back or home; return trip" },
	{ "question": "帰京", "answers": [ "ききょう" ], "comment": "returning to Tokyo\nreturning to the capital" },
	{ "question": "帰化", "answers": [ "きか" ], "comment": "naturalization; naturalisation" },
	{ "question": "帰属", "answers": [ "きぞく" ], "comment": "belonging; ascription; attribution; imputation; possession; jurisdiction\nreversion; return; restoration" },
	{ "question": "帰省", "answers": [ "きせい" ], "comment": "homecoming; returning home" },
	{ "question": "帰途", "answers": [ "きと" ], "comment": "on the way back; returning" },
	{ "question": "帰還", "answers": [ "きかん" ], "comment": "repatriation; return\n(electrical) feedback" },
	{ "question": "帳消し", "answers": [ "ちょうけし" ], "comment": "cancellation; writing off" },
	{ "question": "帳簿", "answers": [ "ちょうぼ" ], "comment": "account book; register; ledger" },
	{ "question": "常任", "answers": [ "じょうにん" ], "comment": "standing; regular; permanent" },
	{ "question": "常務", "answers": [ "じょうむ" ], "comment": "managing director; executive director\nroutine business; regular business" },
	{ "question": "常勤", "answers": [ "じょうきん" ], "comment": "full-time employment" },
	{ "question": "常用", "answers": [ "じょうよう" ], "comment": "habitual use; daily use" },
	{ "question": "常習", "answers": [ "じょうしゅう" ], "comment": "custom; common practice; habit" },
	{ "question": "常設", "answers": [ "じょうせつ" ], "comment": "standing (committee); permanent (exhibit)" },
	{ "question": "常駐", "answers": [ "じょうちゅう" ], "comment": "staying permanently; being stationed; resident" },
	{ "question": "幕下", "answers": [ "まくした" ], "comment": "third highest division; wrestlers of the third highest division" },
	{ "question": "幕僚", "answers": [ "ばくりょう" ], "comment": "staff; staff officer" },
	{ "question": "幕内", "answers": [ "まくうち" ], "comment": "highest-ranking division" },
	{ "question": "幕切れ", "answers": [ "まくぎれ" ], "comment": "fall of the curtain; last scene; end of act" },
	{ "question": "幕開け", "answers": [ "まくあけ" ], "comment": "the rise of the curtain; opening (of play)\nbeginning (e.g. of an era); opening (festival, event, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "干潟", "answers": [ "ひがた" ], "comment": "tidal flat; tideland" },
	{ "question": "平たい", "answers": [ "ひらたい" ], "comment": "flat; even; level; simple\nplain (speech, etc.); simple" },
	{ "question": "平地", "answers": [ "へいち", "ひらち" ], "comment": "level ground; plain" },
	{ "question": "平常", "answers": [ "へいじょう" ], "comment": "normal; usual" },
	{ "question": "平幕", "answers": [ "ひらまく" ], "comment": "rank-and-file wrestlers in the highest division" },
	{ "question": "平年", "answers": [ "へいねん" ], "comment": "non-leap year\nnormal year (esp. as pertains to weather patterns, vegetative growth, harvest yields, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "平方", "answers": [ "へいほう" ], "comment": "square (e.g. metre)" },
	{ "question": "平時", "answers": [ "へいじ" ], "comment": "normal times; peace time" },
	{ "question": "平泳ぎ", "answers": [ "ひらおよぎ" ], "comment": "breaststroke (swimming)" },
	{ "question": "平穏", "answers": [ "へいおん" ], "comment": "tranquil; calm; restful; peaceful; quiet" },
	{ "question": "平静", "answers": [ "へいせい" ], "comment": "calm; serenity; tranquillity; tranquility" },
	{ "question": "平面", "answers": [ "へいめん" ], "comment": "level surface; plane" },
	{ "question": "年会", "answers": [ "ねんかい" ], "comment": "conference; annual convention" },
	{ "question": "年俸", "answers": [ "ねんぽう" ], "comment": "annual salary" },
	{ "question": "年内", "answers": [ "ねんない" ], "comment": "by the end of the year" },
	{ "question": "年刊", "answers": [ "ねんかん" ], "comment": "annual publication; year of publication" },
	{ "question": "年初", "answers": [ "ねんしょ" ], "comment": "beginning of the year; New Year's greetings" },
	{ "question": "年号", "answers": [ "ねんごう" ], "comment": "name of an era; year number" },
	{ "question": "年商", "answers": [ "ねんしょう" ], "comment": "yearly (annual) turnover" },
	{ "question": "年始", "answers": [ "ねんし" ], "comment": "New Year's call; beginning of the year; New Year's greetings" },
	{ "question": "年明け", "answers": [ "としあけ" ], "comment": "beginning of the year; early in the New Year" },
	{ "question": "年来", "answers": [ "ねんらい" ], "comment": "for some years" },
	{ "question": "年次", "answers": [ "ねんじ" ], "comment": "annual\nfiscal year; school year\nyear (in some sequence)" },
	{ "question": "年率", "answers": [ "ねんりつ" ], "comment": "annual rate (of interest)" },
	{ "question": "年産", "answers": [ "ねんさん" ], "comment": "annual production" },
	{ "question": "年男", "answers": [ "としおとこ" ], "comment": "Man of the Year, referring to a man born in a year with the same Chinese zodiac sign as the current year" },
	{ "question": "年表", "answers": [ "ねんぴょう" ], "comment": "chronological table" },
	{ "question": "年輩", "answers": [ "ねんぱい" ], "comment": "elderly; age; years" },
	{ "question": "年輪", "answers": [ "ねんりん" ], "comment": "annual tree ring" },
	{ "question": "年頭", "answers": [ "としがしら", "ねんとう" ], "comment": "beginning of the year\nthe oldest person" },
	{ "question": "年額", "answers": [ "ねんがく" ], "comment": "yearly amount" },
	{ "question": "幻覚", "answers": [ "げんかく" ], "comment": "hallucination; illusion" },
	{ "question": "幼なじみ", "answers": [ "おさななじみ" ], "comment": "childhood friend; friend from infancy; old playmate" },
	{ "question": "幼少", "answers": [ "ようしょう" ], "comment": "infancy; childhood; tender age" },
	{ "question": "幼虫", "answers": [ "ようちゅう" ], "comment": "larva; grub; maggot" },
	{ "question": "幾何", "answers": [ "きか" ], "comment": "geometry" },
	{ "question": "庁舎", "answers": [ "ちょうしゃ" ], "comment": "government office building" },
	{ "question": "広まり", "answers": [ "ひろまり" ], "comment": "spread" },
	{ "question": "床下", "answers": [ "ゆかした" ], "comment": "under the floor" },
	{ "question": "序列", "answers": [ "じょれつ" ], "comment": "rank; ranking order; hierarchy" },
	{ "question": "序盤", "answers": [ "じょばん" ], "comment": "the opening(s) (e.g. in a game of go or chess)" },
	{ "question": "底値", "answers": [ "そこね" ], "comment": "bottom price" },
	{ "question": "底力", "answers": [ "そこぢから" ], "comment": "latent energy; reserve strength; potentiality" },
	{ "question": "底打ち", "answers": [ "そこうち" ], "comment": "bottoming out" },
	{ "question": "底流", "answers": [ "ていりゅう" ], "comment": "bottom current; undercurrent" },
	{ "question": "底辺", "answers": [ "ていへん" ], "comment": "base (e.g. of a triangle)\nlow class; low in social standing; low level; of poor reputation\nbase (e.g. of support); foundation; basis" },
	{ "question": "店主", "answers": [ "てんしゅ" ], "comment": "shopkeeper" },
	{ "question": "店先", "answers": [ "みせさき" ], "comment": "storefront; shopfront" },
	{ "question": "店長", "answers": [ "てんちょう" ], "comment": "shop manager" },
	{ "question": "店開き", "answers": [ "みせびらき" ], "comment": "starting a business\nopening a store (for the day)" },
	{ "question": "度数", "answers": [ "どすう" ], "comment": "frequency; number of times; incidence\ndegree (e.g. temperature); strength (e.g. alcohol, lens, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "度胸", "answers": [ "どきょう" ], "comment": "courage; bravery; pluck; nerve; grit; guts" },
	{ "question": "座り", "answers": [ "すわり" ], "comment": "sitting\nstability" },
	{ "question": "座禅", "answers": [ "ざぜん" ], "comment": "zazen (seated Zen meditation, usu. in a cross-legged position)" },
	{ "question": "座長", "answers": [ "ざちょう" ], "comment": "chairman\nleader of a troupe; proprietor of a theatrical company" },
	{ "question": "庭木", "answers": [ "にわき" ], "comment": "garden tree" },
	{ "question": "廃材", "answers": [ "はいざい" ], "comment": "scrap wood; scrap material" },
	{ "question": "廃案", "answers": [ "はいあん" ], "comment": "rejected bill (project)" },
	{ "question": "廃業", "answers": [ "はいぎょう" ], "comment": "cessation of business; discontinuation of business" },
	{ "question": "廃絶", "answers": [ "はいぜつ" ], "comment": "abolition; elimination\nextinction; discontinuation" },
	{ "question": "延々", "answers": [ "えんえん" ], "comment": "forever; endlessly; on and on\nmeandering; wandering; winding; sinuous; serpentine; zigzagging" },
	{ "question": "延べ", "answers": [ "のべ" ], "comment": "futures\ncredit (buying)\nstretching\ntotal (preceding counter, unit, etc.); aggregate; gross" },
	{ "question": "延命", "answers": [ "えんめい" ], "comment": "keeping alive longer; prolonging life; life extension; life-support" },
	{ "question": "延滞", "answers": [ "えんたい" ], "comment": "arrears; (being) overdue; delay (e.g. in payment); procrastination" },
	{ "question": "建国", "answers": [ "けんこく" ], "comment": "founding of a nation" },
	{ "question": "建材", "answers": [ "けんざい" ], "comment": "building material" },
	{ "question": "建立", "answers": [ "こんりゅう", "けんりつ" ], "comment": "(act of) building (temple, monument, etc.); erection" },
	{ "question": "建議", "answers": [ "けんぎ" ], "comment": "proposition; motion; proposal; suggestion" },
	{ "question": "弁償", "answers": [ "べんしょう" ], "comment": "reimbursement; compensation; reparation; indemnity" },
	{ "question": "弁明", "answers": [ "べんめい" ], "comment": "explanation; excuse; vindication; apology" },
	{ "question": "弁済", "answers": [ "べんさい" ], "comment": "settlement; payment" },
	{ "question": "弁解", "answers": [ "べんかい" ], "comment": "explanation (e.g. for one's actions); excuse; justification; defense; defence" },
	{ "question": "弁論", "answers": [ "べんろん" ], "comment": "discussion; debate; argument" },
	{ "question": "弊害", "answers": [ "へいがい" ], "comment": "harmful effect; harmful influence; evil practice; abuse; malady" },
	{ "question": "式典", "answers": [ "しきてん" ], "comment": "ceremony; rites" },
	{ "question": "式場", "answers": [ "しきじょう" ], "comment": "ceremonial hall (e.g. wedding, funeral); hall for ceremonies; place of ceremony" },
	{ "question": "式部", "answers": [ "しきぶ" ], "comment": "(Meiji era) official responsible for court ceremonies" },
	{ "question": "弔問", "answers": [ "ちょうもん" ], "comment": "condolence call" },
	{ "question": "弔辞", "answers": [ "ちょうじ" ], "comment": "message of condolence; memorial address" },
	{ "question": "引きこもり", "answers": [ "ひきこもり" ], "comment": "shut-in; stay-at-home; hikikomori; people who withdraw from society\nsocial withdrawal; shunning other people" },
	{ "question": "引き上げ", "answers": [ "ひきあげ" ], "comment": "pulling up; drawing up; salvage; re-flotation\nraising; increase; upward revision\nrepatriation; evacuation" },
	{ "question": "引き下げ", "answers": [ "ひきさげ" ], "comment": "reduction; cut" },
	{ "question": "引き下げる", "answers": [ "ひきさげる" ], "comment": "to pull down; to lower; to reduce; to withdraw" },
	{ "question": "引き取り", "answers": [ "ひきとり" ], "comment": "leaving; accepting" },
	{ "question": "引き受け", "answers": [ "ひきうけ" ], "comment": "undertaking; underwriting; acceptance" },
	{ "question": "引き合い", "answers": [ "ひきあい" ], "comment": "reference; comparison; example\ninquiry; enquiry\nwitness; being involved in a court case; deal" },
	{ "question": "引き延ばし", "answers": [ "ひきのばし" ], "comment": "extension; prolongation\nenlargement" },
	{ "question": "引き延ばす", "answers": [ "ひきのばす" ], "comment": "to stretch larger\nto enlarge (photos)\nto delay (e.g. the end of a meeting)" },
	{ "question": "引き戻す", "answers": [ "ひきもどす" ], "comment": "to bring back; to restore" },
	{ "question": "引き換え", "answers": [ "ひきかえ" ], "comment": "exchange; conversion" },
	{ "question": "引き渡し", "answers": [ "ひきわたし" ], "comment": "delivery; handing over; turning over; extradition" },
	{ "question": "引き渡す", "answers": [ "ひきわたす" ], "comment": "to deliver; to extradite; to stretch across; to hand over" },
	{ "question": "引き継ぎ", "answers": [ "ひきつぎ" ], "comment": "taking over; handing over; transfer of control; inheriting; passing on the baton" },
	{ "question": "引き締まる", "answers": [ "ひきしまる" ], "comment": "to become tense; to be tightened" },
	{ "question": "引き締め", "answers": [ "ひきしめ" ], "comment": "tightening" },
	{ "question": "引き締める", "answers": [ "ひきしめる" ], "comment": "to tighten; to stiffen; to brace; to strain" },
	{ "question": "引き裂く", "answers": [ "ひきさく" ], "comment": "to tear up; to tear off; to rip up\nto separate (e.g. a couple); to disrupt (a relationship)" },
	{ "question": "引き離す", "answers": [ "ひきはなす" ], "comment": "to pull apart; to separate" },
	{ "question": "引け目", "answers": [ "ひけめ" ], "comment": "sense of inferiority; one's weak point" },
	{ "question": "引っ付く", "answers": [ "ひっつく" ], "comment": "to stick to; to cling to; to adhere to\nto become intimate (of a man and woman); to get close; to get married" },
	{ "question": "引下げる", "answers": [ "ひきさげる" ], "comment": "to pull down; to lower; to reduce; to withdraw" },
	{ "question": "引延ばす", "answers": [ "ひきのばす" ], "comment": "to stretch larger\nto enlarge (photos)\nto delay (e.g. the end of a meeting)" },
	{ "question": "引戻す", "answers": [ "ひきもどす" ], "comment": "to bring back; to restore" },
	{ "question": "引換え", "answers": [ "ひきかえ" ], "comment": "exchange; conversion" },
	{ "question": "引継ぎ", "answers": [ "ひきつぎ" ], "comment": "taking over; handing over; transfer of control; inheriting; passing on the baton" },
	{ "question": "引締め", "answers": [ "ひきしめ" ], "comment": "tightening" },
	{ "question": "引裂く", "answers": [ "ひきさく" ], "comment": "to tear up; to tear off; to rip up\nto separate (e.g. a couple); to disrupt (a relationship)" },
	{ "question": "引責", "answers": [ "いんせき" ], "comment": "taking responsibility" },
	{ "question": "引離す", "answers": [ "ひきはなす" ], "comment": "to pull apart; to separate" },
	{ "question": "弟子", "answers": [ "でし", "ていし" ], "comment": "pupil; disciple; adherent; follower; apprentice; young person; teacher's student-helper" },
	{ "question": "弥生", "answers": [ "やよい", "いやおい" ], "comment": "third month of the lunar calendar\nthick growth (of grass, etc.)\nYayoi period (ca. 300 BCE - 300 CE)" },
	{ "question": "弦楽", "answers": [ "げんがく" ], "comment": "music for strings; string music" },
	{ "question": "弱まる", "answers": [ "よわまる" ], "comment": "to abate; to weaken; to be emaciated; to be dejected; to be perplexed" },
	{ "question": "弱み", "answers": [ "よわみ" ], "comment": "(a) weakness; shortcoming; failing; sore point" },
	{ "question": "弱める", "answers": [ "よわめる" ], "comment": "to weaken" },
	{ "question": "弱体", "answers": [ "じゃくたい" ], "comment": "weak (organization, organisation)" },
	{ "question": "弱気", "answers": [ "よわき" ], "comment": "timid; weak-kneed; fainthearted\nbearish (e.g. market)" },
	{ "question": "弱者", "answers": [ "じゃくしゃ" ], "comment": "weak person; the weak; vulnerable person; disadvantaged person" },
	{ "question": "弱虫", "answers": [ "よわむし" ], "comment": "coward; weakling; scaredy cat; wimp; sissy" },
	{ "question": "弱音", "answers": [ "よわね" ], "comment": "feeble complaint; whine" },
	{ "question": "張り", "answers": [ "ばり" ], "comment": "in the style of (esp. literary, artistic, etc. works); reminiscent of\nattached or stretched on" },
	{ "question": "張り出す", "answers": [ "はりだす" ], "comment": "to project; to overhang; to stick out; to jut out; to overlie\nto put up (a notice); to post" },
	{ "question": "張り紙", "answers": [ "はりがみ" ], "comment": "paper patch; paper backing; poster; sticker; label" },
	{ "question": "強いて", "answers": [ "しいて" ], "comment": "by force" },
	{ "question": "強いる", "answers": [ "しいる" ], "comment": "to force; to compel; to coerce" },
	{ "question": "強み", "answers": [ "つよみ" ], "comment": "forte; strong point" },
	{ "question": "強大", "answers": [ "きょうだい" ], "comment": "mighty; powerful" },
	{ "question": "強度", "answers": [ "きょうど" ], "comment": "strength; intensity" },
	{ "question": "強情", "answers": [ "ごうじょう" ], "comment": "obstinate; stubborn; headstrong" },
	{ "question": "強打", "answers": [ "きょうだ" ], "comment": "smiting; blow" },
	{ "question": "強敵", "answers": [ "きょうてき" ], "comment": "formidable enemy; strong enemy; tough enemy" },
	{ "question": "強権", "answers": [ "きょうけん" ], "comment": "power of the state" },
	{ "question": "強硬", "answers": [ "きょうこう" ], "comment": "firm; vigorous; unbending; unyielding; strong; stubborn" },
	{ "question": "強者", "answers": [ "きょうしゃ" ], "comment": "strong person" },
	{ "question": "強行", "answers": [ "きょうこう" ], "comment": "forcing; enforcement\nforced; enforced" },
	{ "question": "強要", "answers": [ "きょうよう" ], "comment": "coercion; extortion; compulsion; force" },
	{ "question": "強豪", "answers": [ "きょうごう" ], "comment": "veteran; champion" },
	{ "question": "強風", "answers": [ "きょうふう" ], "comment": "strong wind; high wind; moderate gale" },
	{ "question": "弾丸", "answers": [ "だんがん" ], "comment": "bullet; shot; shell" },
	{ "question": "弾力", "answers": [ "だんりょく" ], "comment": "elasticity; flexibility" },
	{ "question": "弾劾", "answers": [ "だんがい" ], "comment": "impeachment\ndenunciation; accusation; censure; arraignment" },
	{ "question": "弾薬", "answers": [ "だんやく" ], "comment": "ammunition; ammo" },
	{ "question": "弾道", "answers": [ "だんどう" ], "comment": "trajectory; line of fire\nballistic" },
	{ "question": "弾頭", "answers": [ "だんとう" ], "comment": "warhead" },
	{ "question": "当たり役", "answers": [ "あたりやく" ], "comment": "successful role" },
	{ "question": "当地", "answers": [ "とうち" ], "comment": "this place; here" },
	{ "question": "当惑", "answers": [ "とうわく" ], "comment": "bewilderment; perplexity; embarrassment; confusion" },
	{ "question": "当期", "answers": [ "とうき" ], "comment": "current term (period)" },
	{ "question": "当直", "answers": [ "とうちょく" ], "comment": "on duty; on a shift; keeping watch" },
	{ "question": "当社", "answers": [ "とうしゃ" ], "comment": "(this) shrine\n(this) company; (this) firm" },
	{ "question": "当落", "answers": [ "とうらく" ], "comment": "result of an election; success or defeat in an election" },
	{ "question": "形勢", "answers": [ "けいせい" ], "comment": "condition; situation; prospects" },
	{ "question": "形見", "answers": [ "かたみ" ], "comment": "memento; keepsake; souvenir" },
	{ "question": "形跡", "answers": [ "けいせき" ], "comment": "traces; evidence" },
	{ "question": "彩り", "answers": [ "いろどり" ], "comment": "coloring; colouring; coloration; colouration; assortment; color scheme; colour scheme; makeup" },
	{ "question": "彩る", "answers": [ "いろどる" ], "comment": "to colour; to color; to paint\nto apply make-up\nto decorate; to garnish; to adorn; to add flair" },
	{ "question": "彩色", "answers": [ "さいしき", "さいしょく" ], "comment": "colouring; coloring; colouration; coloration; painting" },
	{ "question": "役回り", "answers": [ "やくまわり" ], "comment": "role; part; duty" },
	{ "question": "役柄", "answers": [ "やくがら" ], "comment": "role" },
	{ "question": "彼岸", "answers": [ "ひがん" ], "comment": "equinoctial week (when Buddhist services are held)\nBuddhist services during the equinoctial week\nnirvana" },
	{ "question": "往年", "answers": [ "おうねん" ], "comment": "former; one-time; years ago" },
	{ "question": "往生", "answers": [ "おうじょう" ], "comment": "passing on to the next life\ndeath\ngiving up a struggle; submission\nbeing at one's wits' end; being flummoxed\ncoercion" },
	{ "question": "待たす", "answers": [ "またす" ], "comment": "to keep (a person) waiting" },
	{ "question": "待ち伏せ", "answers": [ "まちぶせ" ], "comment": "ambush; lying in wait for an ambush" },
	{ "question": "待ち合わせ", "answers": [ "まちあわせ" ], "comment": "appointment" },
	{ "question": "待ち望む", "answers": [ "まちのぞむ" ], "comment": "to wait eagerly for; to look forward to" },
	{ "question": "待ち構える", "answers": [ "まちかまえる" ], "comment": "to lie in wait; to be on the watch for" },
	{ "question": "待ち遠しい", "answers": [ "まちどおしい" ], "comment": "looking forward to; anxiously awaited" },
	{ "question": "待望", "answers": [ "たいぼう" ], "comment": "waiting expectantly; waiting eagerly; looking forward to\nlong-awaited" },
	{ "question": "後ろ向き", "answers": [ "うしろむき" ], "comment": "back facing; turning one's back to; pessimistic; backwards\nreactionary; backward-looking" },
	{ "question": "後ろ盾", "answers": [ "うしろだて" ], "comment": "backing; support; backer; supporter; patron; sponsor\nshield that protects one's back" },
	{ "question": "後任", "answers": [ "こうにん" ], "comment": "successor" },
	{ "question": "後回し", "answers": [ "あとまわし" ], "comment": "putting off; postponing" },
	{ "question": "後戻り", "answers": [ "あともどり" ], "comment": "going backward; turning back; backtracking; doubling back\nretrogression; relapse; returning to a bad state" },
	{ "question": "後手", "answers": [ "ごて" ], "comment": "losing initiative; being forestalled\nsecond move (in go or shogi); moving second; person with the second move\nrear guard" },
	{ "question": "後押し", "answers": [ "あとおし" ], "comment": "pushing; backing; boosting; supporting\npushing from behind (a cart, etc.); pusher" },
	{ "question": "後援", "answers": [ "こうえん" ], "comment": "support; backing" },
	{ "question": "後書", "answers": [ "あとがき" ], "comment": "afterword; postscript" },
	{ "question": "後書き", "answers": [ "あとがき" ], "comment": "afterword; postscript" },
	{ "question": "後発", "answers": [ "こうはつ" ], "comment": "starting late" },
	{ "question": "後続", "answers": [ "こうぞく" ], "comment": "succeeding; following; trailing" },
	{ "question": "後見", "answers": [ "こうけん" ], "comment": "guardianship; guardian\n(theatrical) assistant; prompter" },
	{ "question": "後進", "answers": [ "こうしん" ], "comment": "one's junior; next generation\nreversing; going astern; going backwards" },
	{ "question": "徐行", "answers": [ "じょこう" ], "comment": "going slowly" },
	{ "question": "従える", "answers": [ "したがえる" ], "comment": "to be accompanied by\nto conquer; to subjugate; to subdue" },
	{ "question": "従軍", "answers": [ "じゅうぐん" ], "comment": "military service; serving in a war; taking part in a campaign" },
	{ "question": "得々", "answers": [ "とくとく" ], "comment": "triumphantly; proudly" },
	{ "question": "得する", "answers": [ "とくする" ], "comment": "to make a profit" },
	{ "question": "得失", "answers": [ "とくしつ" ], "comment": "advantages and disadvantages; plus and minuses" },
	{ "question": "得点", "answers": [ "とくてん" ], "comment": "score; points made; marks obtained; runs" },
	{ "question": "得票", "answers": [ "とくひょう" ], "comment": "number of votes polled; poll votes" },
	{ "question": "得策", "answers": [ "とくさく" ], "comment": "profitable plan; good plan" },
	{ "question": "御苑", "answers": [ "ぎょえん" ], "comment": "imperial garden" },
	{ "question": "復刻", "answers": [ "ふっこく" ], "comment": "republishing; republication; reissuing; reproduction" },
	{ "question": "復員", "answers": [ "ふくいん" ], "comment": "demobilization; demobilisation; repatriation" },
	{ "question": "復旧", "answers": [ "ふっきゅう", "ふくきゅう" ], "comment": "restoration; restitution; rehabilitation" },
	{ "question": "復権", "answers": [ "ふっけん", "ふくけん" ], "comment": "rehabilitation; reinstatement; restoration of rights" },
	{ "question": "復調", "answers": [ "ふくちょう" ], "comment": "demodulation\nrecovery; getting back to form" },
	{ "question": "微動", "answers": [ "びどう" ], "comment": "slight tremor; slight movement; a quiver" },
	{ "question": "微小", "answers": [ "びしょう" ], "comment": "microscopic" },
	{ "question": "微細", "answers": [ "びさい" ], "comment": "minute; micro; detailed; delicate; subtle" },
	{ "question": "微量", "answers": [ "びりょう" ], "comment": "minuscule amount; extremely small quantity" },
	{ "question": "徴兵", "answers": [ "ちょうへい" ], "comment": "conscription; recruitment; enlistment" },
	{ "question": "徹する", "answers": [ "てっする" ], "comment": "to penetrate; to sink in\nto devote oneself (to); to do intently and exclusively\nto do throughout (e.g. the night)" },
	{ "question": "心外", "answers": [ "しんがい" ], "comment": "regrettable; vexing; upsetting\nunthinkable; wholly unexpected" },
	{ "question": "心強い", "answers": [ "こころづよい" ], "comment": "heartening; reassuring" },
	{ "question": "心待ち", "answers": [ "こころまち" ], "comment": "anticipation; expectation" },
	{ "question": "心掛け", "answers": [ "こころがけ" ], "comment": "intention; attention; dedication; care; prudence; readiness; mental attitude" },
	{ "question": "心構え", "answers": [ "こころがまえ" ], "comment": "preparedness; readiness; mental attitude; frame of mind" },
	{ "question": "心筋", "answers": [ "しんきん" ], "comment": "heart muscle; myocardium" },
	{ "question": "心細い", "answers": [ "こころぼそい" ], "comment": "helpless; forlorn; hopeless; unpromising; lonely; discouraging; disheartening" },
	{ "question": "必修", "answers": [ "ひっしゅう" ], "comment": "required (subject)" },
	{ "question": "必勝", "answers": [ "ひっしょう" ], "comment": "certain victory" },
	{ "question": "必至", "answers": [ "ひっし" ], "comment": "inevitable; necessary; foregone\nbrinkmate (inevitable checkmate)" },
	{ "question": "必読", "answers": [ "ひつどく" ], "comment": "must-read; obligatory reading" },
	{ "question": "必需", "answers": [ "ひつじゅ" ], "comment": "necessary" },
	{ "question": "志す", "answers": [ "こころざす" ], "comment": "to plan; to intend; to aspire to; to set aims (sights on)" },
	{ "question": "志願", "answers": [ "しがん" ], "comment": "aspiration; volunteering; desire; application" },
	{ "question": "忘却", "answers": [ "ぼうきゃく" ], "comment": "lapse of memory; forgetfulness; oblivion" },
	{ "question": "応分", "answers": [ "おうぶん" ], "comment": "according to one's abilities; appropriate; reasonable" },
	{ "question": "応急", "answers": [ "おうきゅう" ], "comment": "emergency; first-aid" },
	{ "question": "応札", "answers": [ "おうさつ" ], "comment": "making a bid; tendering a bid" },
	{ "question": "応酬", "answers": [ "おうしゅう" ], "comment": "exchange; reciprocation; give-and-take; return\nreply; riposte" },
	{ "question": "忠臣", "answers": [ "ちゅうしん" ], "comment": "loyal retainer; loyal subject" },
	{ "question": "快勝", "answers": [ "かいしょう" ], "comment": "sweeping victory; easy victory" },
	{ "question": "快挙", "answers": [ "かいきょ" ], "comment": "brilliant achievement; spectacular feat; splendid accomplishment; remarkable deed" },
	{ "question": "快調", "answers": [ "かいちょう" ], "comment": "good (condition); going well; fine; smooth" },
	{ "question": "快速", "answers": [ "かいそく" ], "comment": "high speed; rapidity\nrapid-service train (not as fast as express); rapid train" },
	{ "question": "念入り", "answers": [ "ねんいり" ], "comment": "careful; scrupulous; thorough; conscientious; elaborate; deliberate; attentive" },
	{ "question": "念力", "answers": [ "ねんりき" ], "comment": "willpower; faith\ntelekinesis; psychokinesis" },
	{ "question": "念書", "answers": [ "ねんしょ" ], "comment": "written pledge; signed note of assurance; memorandum; legal instrument" },
	{ "question": "念願", "answers": [ "ねんがん" ], "comment": "one's heart's desire; one's dearest wish" },
	{ "question": "怒鳴り込む", "answers": [ "どなりこむ" ], "comment": "to storm in with a yell" },
	{ "question": "思いつき", "answers": [ "おもいつき" ], "comment": "plan; idea; suggestion" },
	{ "question": "思いとどまる", "answers": [ "おもいとどまる" ], "comment": "to give up (a plan or idea); to desist from (doing)" },
	{ "question": "思いやる", "answers": [ "おもいやる" ], "comment": "to be considerate; to sympathize with; to sympathise with" },
	{ "question": "思い上がる", "answers": [ "おもいあがる" ], "comment": "to be conceited" },
	{ "question": "思い付き", "answers": [ "おもいつき" ], "comment": "plan; idea; suggestion" },
	{ "question": "思い思い", "answers": [ "おもいおもい" ], "comment": "just as one likes; as one pleases; as one prefers" },
	{ "question": "思い描く", "answers": [ "おもいえがく" ], "comment": "to imagine; to picture; to figure; to see" },
	{ "question": "思い直す", "answers": [ "おもいなおす" ], "comment": "to re-think; to think back upon; to change one's mind" },
	{ "question": "怠惰", "answers": [ "たいだ" ], "comment": "lazy; idle; indolent; slothful" },
	{ "question": "怠慢", "answers": [ "たいまん" ], "comment": "negligence; neglect; carelessness; procrastination" },
	{ "question": "急かす", "answers": [ "せかす" ], "comment": "to hurry; to urge on" },
	{ "question": "急きょ", "answers": [ "きゅうきょ" ], "comment": "hurriedly; in a hurry; in haste\nsudden" },
	{ "question": "急ぎ", "answers": [ "いそぎ" ], "comment": "haste; hurry; expedition; speed; dispatch" },
	{ "question": "急伸", "answers": [ "きゅうしん" ], "comment": "sudden rise (esp. of stock prices); jump" },
	{ "question": "急務", "answers": [ "きゅうむ" ], "comment": "urgent business" },
	{ "question": "急変", "answers": [ "きゅうへん" ], "comment": "sudden turn; sudden change\n(suddenly occurring) accident; emergency" },
	{ "question": "急性", "answers": [ "きゅうせい" ], "comment": "acute (e.g. illness)" },
	{ "question": "急所", "answers": [ "きゅうしょ" ], "comment": "vitals; tender spot\nkey (of a problem); crux; essential point; secret\nmale crotch (as a target in fighting)" },
	{ "question": "急死", "answers": [ "きゅうし" ], "comment": "sudden death" },
	{ "question": "急用", "answers": [ "きゅうよう" ], "comment": "urgent business" },
	{ "question": "急病", "answers": [ "きゅうびょう" ], "comment": "sudden illness" },
	{ "question": "急落", "answers": [ "きゅうらく" ], "comment": "sudden fall; sharp fall; sudden drop; sharp drop" },
	{ "question": "急進", "answers": [ "きゅうしん" ], "comment": "rapid progress; radical" },
	{ "question": "急遽", "answers": [ "きゅうきょ" ], "comment": "hurriedly; in a hurry; in haste\nsudden" },
	{ "question": "急騰", "answers": [ "きゅうとう" ], "comment": "sudden rise; jump; sharp rise" },
	{ "question": "性向", "answers": [ "せいこう" ], "comment": "inclination; tendency; nature; character" },
	{ "question": "性急", "answers": [ "せいきゅう" ], "comment": "hasty; impatient; impetuous; quick-tempered" },
	{ "question": "性行", "answers": [ "せいこう" ], "comment": "character and conduct" },
	{ "question": "怪しむ", "answers": [ "あやしむ" ], "comment": "to suspect" },
	{ "question": "怪奇", "answers": [ "かいき" ], "comment": "bizarre; strange; wonderful; weird; outrageous" },
	{ "question": "怪獣", "answers": [ "かいじゅう" ], "comment": "monster" },
	{ "question": "怪談", "answers": [ "かいだん" ], "comment": "ghost story" },
	{ "question": "恋する", "answers": [ "こいする" ], "comment": "to fall in love with; to love" },
	{ "question": "恐る恐る", "answers": [ "おそるおそる" ], "comment": "timidly" },
	{ "question": "恐喝", "answers": [ "きょうかつ" ], "comment": "blackmail; extortion; threat (to extort money)" },
	{ "question": "恐慌", "answers": [ "きょうこう" ], "comment": "panic; scare; consternation" },
	{ "question": "恐竜", "answers": [ "きょうりゅう" ], "comment": "dinosaur" },
	{ "question": "恒久", "answers": [ "こうきゅう" ], "comment": "permanent; perpetuity" },
	{ "question": "恒例", "answers": [ "こうれい" ], "comment": "established practice; custom" },
	{ "question": "恒常", "answers": [ "こうじょう" ], "comment": "constancy" },
	{ "question": "恥", "answers": [ "はじ" ], "comment": "shame; embarrassment; disgrace" },
	{ "question": "恥さらし", "answers": [ "はじさらし" ], "comment": "disgrace; shame" },
	{ "question": "恩人", "answers": [ "おんじん" ], "comment": "benefactor; patron" },
	{ "question": "恩師", "answers": [ "おんし" ], "comment": "teacher; one's former teacher" },
	{ "question": "恩赦", "answers": [ "おんしゃ" ], "comment": "amnesty; pardon" },
	{ "question": "恩返し", "answers": [ "おんがえし" ], "comment": "requital of a favour (favor); repayment (of an obligation, kindness, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "息切れ", "answers": [ "いきぎれ" ], "comment": "shortness of breath; panting; puffing\nrunning out of steam (e.g. economy); losing momentum" },
	{ "question": "息吹", "answers": [ "いぶき" ], "comment": "breath\nsign (of something new and fresh); breath (metaphor)" },
	{ "question": "恵み", "answers": [ "めぐみ" ], "comment": "blessing; grace" },
	{ "question": "恵む", "answers": [ "めぐむ" ], "comment": "to bless; to show mercy to\nto give (money, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "悔い", "answers": [ "くい" ], "comment": "regret; repentance" },
	{ "question": "悪事", "answers": [ "あくじ" ], "comment": "evil deed; crime; wickedness" },
	{ "question": "悪人", "answers": [ "あくにん" ], "comment": "bad person; villain; scoundrel; wrongdoer; wicked person" },
	{ "question": "悪夢", "answers": [ "あくむ" ], "comment": "nightmare; bad dream" },
	{ "question": "悪女", "answers": [ "あくじょ" ], "comment": "wicked woman\nugly woman" },
	{ "question": "悪寒", "answers": [ "おかん" ], "comment": "chill; shakes; ague" },
	{ "question": "悪役", "answers": [ "あくやく" ], "comment": "villain; baddie; the villain's part" },
	{ "question": "悪徳", "answers": [ "あくとく" ], "comment": "vice; immorality; corruption" },
	{ "question": "悪性", "answers": [ "あくせい" ], "comment": "malignancy; virulence; malignant (cancer); pernicious (anemia, anaemia)" },
	{ "question": "悪意", "answers": [ "あくい" ], "comment": "ill will; spite; evil intention; malice\nbad meaning\nmala fides; bad faith; criminal intent to deceive\nmalice" },
	{ "question": "悪気", "answers": [ "わるぎ" ], "comment": "ill will; malice; evil intent; ill feeling; distrust" },
	{ "question": "悪用", "answers": [ "あくよう" ], "comment": "abuse; misuse; perversion" },
	{ "question": "悪者", "answers": [ "わるもの" ], "comment": "bad fellow; rascal; ruffian; scoundrel" },
	{ "question": "悪臭", "answers": [ "あくしゅう" ], "comment": "stink; bad odor; bad odour; stench" },
	{ "question": "悪賢い", "answers": [ "わるがしこい" ], "comment": "cunning; crafty; wily; sly" },
	{ "question": "悲哀", "answers": [ "ひあい" ], "comment": "sorrow; grief; sadness" },
	{ "question": "悲壮", "answers": [ "ひそう" ], "comment": "heroic; tragic; grim; pathetic; touching" },
	{ "question": "悲痛", "answers": [ "ひつう" ], "comment": "grief; sorrow; extreme sadness; heartbreak" },
	{ "question": "悲観", "answers": [ "ひかん" ], "comment": "pessimism; disappointment" },
	{ "question": "悲願", "answers": [ "ひがん" ], "comment": "one's dearest wish; Buddha's vow to save humanity" },
	{ "question": "悼む", "answers": [ "いたむ" ], "comment": "to grieve over; to mourn; to lament" },
	{ "question": "情け", "answers": [ "なさけ" ], "comment": "pity; sympathy; compassion; mercy\naffection" },
	{ "question": "情け深い", "answers": [ "なさけぶかい" ], "comment": "tender-hearted; compassionate; charitable; good-hearted" },
	{ "question": "情感", "answers": [ "じょうかん" ], "comment": "feeling; sensitivity; emotion" },
	{ "question": "惑わす", "answers": [ "まどわす" ], "comment": "to bewilder; to perplex; to puzzle; to delude; to mislead; to deceive\nto tempt; to seduce" },
	{ "question": "惑星", "answers": [ "わくせい" ], "comment": "planet" },
	{ "question": "惣菜", "answers": [ "そうざい" ], "comment": "side dish; daily (household) dish" },
	{ "question": "惨事", "answers": [ "さんじ" ], "comment": "disaster; tragedy; tragic incident; horrible accident" },
	{ "question": "惨敗", "answers": [ "ざんぱい", "さんぱい" ], "comment": "ignominious defeat; crushing failure; utterly beaten; overwhelming defeat" },
	{ "question": "惨状", "answers": [ "さんじょう" ], "comment": "disastrous scene; terrible spectacle" },
	{ "question": "意表", "answers": [ "いひょう" ], "comment": "surprise; something unexpected" },
	{ "question": "愚", "answers": [ "ぐ" ], "comment": "foolishness; silliness; stupidity; folly\nI; me" },
	{ "question": "愛好", "answers": [ "あいこう" ], "comment": "love; adoration" },
	{ "question": "愛犬", "answers": [ "あいけん" ], "comment": "pet dog; beloved dog" },
	{ "question": "愛称", "answers": [ "あいしょう" ], "comment": "pet name; nickname; name used to indicate affection, intimacy, informality, etc." },
	{ "question": "愛読", "answers": [ "あいどく" ], "comment": "reading with pleasure" },
	{ "question": "愛護", "answers": [ "あいご" ], "comment": "protection; tender care" },
	{ "question": "感化", "answers": [ "かんか" ], "comment": "influence; inspiration; reform; correction" },
	{ "question": "感度", "answers": [ "かんど" ], "comment": "sensitivity; reception (e.g. radio and television); severity (quake)" },
	{ "question": "感銘", "answers": [ "かんめい" ], "comment": "deep impression" },
	{ "question": "慈善", "answers": [ "じぜん" ], "comment": "charity; philanthropy" },
	{ "question": "慈悲", "answers": [ "じひ" ], "comment": "compassion (e.g. of Buddha); benevolence; charity; mercy\nHodgson's hawk-cuckoo (Cuculus fugax); Horsfield's hawk cuckoo" },
	{ "question": "慎む", "answers": [ "つつしむ" ], "comment": "to be careful; to be discreet\nto do in moderation; to refrain (from overdoing); to abstain\nto be reverent\nto be purified; to be chaste" },
	{ "question": "慢性", "answers": [ "まんせい" ], "comment": "chronicity; chronic" },
	{ "question": "慣らす", "answers": [ "ならす" ], "comment": "to accustom; to train (e.g. one's ear)\nto tame; to domesticate; to train (e.g. an animal)" },
	{ "question": "慣れ", "answers": [ "なれ" ], "comment": "practice; practising; experience" },
	{ "question": "慣例", "answers": [ "かんれい" ], "comment": "custom; precedent; of convention" },
	{ "question": "慣行", "answers": [ "かんこう" ], "comment": "customary practice; habit; traditional event" },
	{ "question": "慰安", "answers": [ "いあん" ], "comment": "solace; relaxation" },
	{ "question": "慰霊", "answers": [ "いれい" ], "comment": "comfort the spirit (of the dead)" },
	{ "question": "憂える", "answers": [ "うれえる" ], "comment": "to worry about; to be anxious about; to be concerned about\nto lament; to grieve; to feel sorrow for" },
	{ "question": "憂慮", "answers": [ "ゆうりょ" ], "comment": "anxiety; concern; fear" },
	{ "question": "憤り", "answers": [ "いきどおり" ], "comment": "resentment; indignation; anger" },
	{ "question": "憤慨", "answers": [ "ふんがい" ], "comment": "indignation; resentment" },
	{ "question": "憩", "answers": [ "いこい" ], "comment": "rest" },
	{ "question": "憩い", "answers": [ "いこい" ], "comment": "rest" },
	{ "question": "憲政", "answers": [ "けんせい" ], "comment": "constitutional government" },
	{ "question": "憲章", "answers": [ "けんしょう" ], "comment": "charter" },
	{ "question": "憶測", "answers": [ "おくそく" ], "comment": "guess; speculation; supposition" },
	{ "question": "懇親", "answers": [ "こんしん" ], "comment": "friendship; intimacy" },
	{ "question": "懇話", "answers": [ "こんわ" ], "comment": "friendly (familiar) chat (talk)" },
	{ "question": "懇談", "answers": [ "こんだん" ], "comment": "informal talk" },
	{ "question": "懐かしむ", "answers": [ "なつかしむ" ], "comment": "to yearn for (someone, something); to miss" },
	{ "question": "懐疑", "answers": [ "かいぎ" ], "comment": "doubt; skepticism; scepticism; disbelief" },
	{ "question": "懲りる", "answers": [ "こりる" ], "comment": "to learn by experience; to learn one's lesson; to learn the hard way\nto have enough (of); to be disgusted with" },
	{ "question": "懲役", "answers": [ "ちょうえき" ], "comment": "penal servitude; imprisonment with hard labor (hard labour)" },
	{ "question": "懲戒", "answers": [ "ちょうかい" ], "comment": "discipline; punishment; reprimand" },
	{ "question": "懲罰", "answers": [ "ちょうばつ" ], "comment": "discipline; punishment; reprimand" },
	{ "question": "懸案", "answers": [ "けんあん" ], "comment": "pending question; unresolved problem" },
	{ "question": "懸賞", "answers": [ "けんしょう" ], "comment": "offering prizes; winning; reward" },
	{ "question": "成否", "answers": [ "せいひ" ], "comment": "success or failure; outcome; result" },
	{ "question": "成案", "answers": [ "せいあん" ], "comment": "definite plan" },
	{ "question": "成算", "answers": [ "せいさん" ], "comment": "hope of success; prospects of success" },
	{ "question": "成約", "answers": [ "せいやく" ], "comment": "conclusion of a contract" },
	{ "question": "成金", "answers": [ "なりきん" ], "comment": "upstart; nouveau riche; new rich; coming into wealth suddenly\npiece promoted to gold general" },
	{ "question": "戒め", "answers": [ "いましめ" ], "comment": "caution; admonition; warning; lesson\nprohibition; ban; commandment; precept\npunishment\ncaution; guard" },
	{ "question": "戒める", "answers": [ "いましめる" ], "comment": "to warn against; to caution against\nto admonish; to scold; to rebuke\nto prohibit; to forbid; to ban\nto be cautious\nto detest; to loathe\nto punish" },
	{ "question": "戒告", "answers": [ "かいこく" ], "comment": "admonition; warning; caution" },
	{ "question": "戦中", "answers": [ "せんちゅう" ], "comment": "during the war" },
	{ "question": "戦列", "answers": [ "せんれつ" ], "comment": "line of battle" },
	{ "question": "戦勝", "answers": [ "せんしょう" ], "comment": "victory; triumph" },
	{ "question": "戦友", "answers": [ "せんゆう" ], "comment": "comrade in arms; war buddy" },
	{ "question": "戦地", "answers": [ "せんち" ], "comment": "front (in battle)" },
	{ "question": "戦域", "answers": [ "せんいき" ], "comment": "war area; battlefield; theater; theatre" },
	{ "question": "戦没", "answers": [ "せんぼつ" ], "comment": "death in battle; killed in action" },
	{ "question": "戦況", "answers": [ "せんきょう" ], "comment": "war situation; progress of a battle" },
	{ "question": "戦法", "answers": [ "せんぽう" ], "comment": "tactics; strategy" },
	{ "question": "戦火", "answers": [ "せんか" ], "comment": "wartime fire\nwar; wartime destruction; horrors of war" },
	{ "question": "戦災", "answers": [ "せんさい" ], "comment": "war damage" },
	{ "question": "戦犯", "answers": [ "せんぱん" ], "comment": "war criminal" },
	{ "question": "戦績", "answers": [ "せんせき" ], "comment": "war or military record; score; military achievements; results" },
	{ "question": "戦費", "answers": [ "せんぴ" ], "comment": "war expenditures" },
	{ "question": "戯れ", "answers": [ "たわむれ" ], "comment": "play; sport; fun; caprice; joke; jest; flirtation" },
	{ "question": "戯れる", "answers": [ "じゃれる", "ざれる", "たわむれる" ], "comment": "to be playful; to gambol; to be amused (with something); to play; to sport; to frolic; to joke\nto flirt with" },
	{ "question": "戯曲", "answers": [ "ぎきょく" ], "comment": "play; drama" },
	{ "question": "戸外", "answers": [ "こがい" ], "comment": "open-air; outdoors" },
	{ "question": "戸惑い", "answers": [ "とまどい" ], "comment": "being at sea; losing one's bearings; confusion; wonderment" },
	{ "question": "戸数", "answers": [ "こすう" ], "comment": "number of households (houses)" },
	{ "question": "戸締まり", "answers": [ "とじまり" ], "comment": "closing up; fastening the doors" },
	{ "question": "戻り", "answers": [ "もどり" ], "comment": "return; reaction; recovery\nreturn (from a procedure)" },
	{ "question": "所信", "answers": [ "しょしん" ], "comment": "belief; conviction; opinion" },
	{ "question": "所定", "answers": [ "しょてい" ], "comment": "fixed; prescribed; certain; given" },
	{ "question": "所管", "answers": [ "しょかん" ], "comment": "jurisdiction" },
	{ "question": "所見", "answers": [ "しょけん" ], "comment": "view; opinion; finding; findings" },
	{ "question": "扇形", "answers": [ "おうぎがた", "せんけい" ], "comment": "fan shape" },
	{ "question": "手ごわい", "answers": [ "てごわい" ], "comment": "difficult; tough; formidable; redoubtable; stubborn" },
	{ "question": "手すり", "answers": [ "てすり" ], "comment": "handrail; railing; banister" },
	{ "question": "手ぬぐい", "answers": [ "てぬぐい" ], "comment": "(hand) towel" },
	{ "question": "手中", "answers": [ "しゅちゅう" ], "comment": "in one's hands; in one's control" },
	{ "question": "手分け", "answers": [ "てわけ" ], "comment": "division of labour; division of labor; splitting into groups (e.g. to search)" },
	{ "question": "手動", "answers": [ "しゅどう" ], "comment": "manual (operation)" },
	{ "question": "手口", "answers": [ "てぐち" ], "comment": "modus operandi; criminal technique; trick" },
	{ "question": "手堅い", "answers": [ "てがたい" ], "comment": "steady; firm; solid; secure" },
	{ "question": "手始め", "answers": [ "てはじめ" ], "comment": "outset; start; beginning" },
	{ "question": "手引", "answers": [ "てびき" ], "comment": "guidance; guide; introduction; guideline" },
	{ "question": "手引き", "answers": [ "てびき" ], "comment": "guidance; guide; introduction; guideline" },
	{ "question": "手抜き", "answers": [ "てぬき" ], "comment": "omitting crucial steps; cutting corners; skimping\nintentional negligence\ntenuki; taking the initiative by ignoring the opponent's last move and playing somewhere else (in go)" },
	{ "question": "手振り", "answers": [ "てぶり" ], "comment": "movements or gestures of hands or arms" },
	{ "question": "手探り", "answers": [ "てさぐり" ], "comment": "fumbling; groping" },
	{ "question": "手提げ", "answers": [ "てさげ" ], "comment": "handbag; purse" },
	{ "question": "手摺り", "answers": [ "てすり" ], "comment": "handrail; railing; banister" },
	{ "question": "手放し", "answers": [ "てばなし" ], "comment": "without holding on; without using the hands; letting go one's hold\nlack of reserve; lack of restraint; openly" },
	{ "question": "手書き", "answers": [ "てがき" ], "comment": "handwriting\nhandwritten; hand-painted; hand-drawn" },
	{ "question": "手本", "answers": [ "てほん" ], "comment": "copybook\nmodel; pattern" },
	{ "question": "手柄", "answers": [ "てがら" ], "comment": "achievement; feat; meritorious deed; distinguished service" },
	{ "question": "手痛い", "answers": [ "ていたい" ], "comment": "severe; hard" },
	{ "question": "手直し", "answers": [ "てなおし" ], "comment": "adjustment; tweaking; improvement; modification; tinkering; minor alteration; correction" },
	{ "question": "手腕", "answers": [ "しゅわん" ], "comment": "ability" },
	{ "question": "手落ち", "answers": [ "ておち" ], "comment": "oversight; omission" },
	{ "question": "手薄", "answers": [ "てうす" ], "comment": "short of hands; insufficient" },
	{ "question": "手製", "answers": [ "てせい" ], "comment": "handmade" },
	{ "question": "手記", "answers": [ "しゅき" ], "comment": "note; memorandum" },
	{ "question": "手話", "answers": [ "しゅわ" ], "comment": "sign language" },
	{ "question": "手軽", "answers": [ "てがる" ], "comment": "easy; simple; informal; offhand; cheap" },
	{ "question": "手遅れ", "answers": [ "ておくれ" ], "comment": "being (too) late\nbelated treatment" },
	{ "question": "手錠", "answers": [ "てじょう" ], "comment": "handcuffs; manacles" },
	{ "question": "手際", "answers": [ "てぎわ" ], "comment": "performance; skill; tact" },
	{ "question": "才", "answers": [ "さい" ], "comment": "-years-old\nability; gift; talent; aptitude; genius" },
	{ "question": "打ち上げ", "answers": [ "うちあげ" ], "comment": "launching; launch\nend (of a theatrical run, etc.)\nclosing party (e.g. a theater show); cast party; party to celebrate successful completion of a project" },
	{ "question": "打ち切り", "answers": [ "うちきり" ], "comment": "end; close; finish; truncation; discontinuance" },
	{ "question": "打ち切る", "answers": [ "うちきる" ], "comment": "to stop; to abort; to discontinue; to close" },
	{ "question": "打ち合い", "answers": [ "うちあい" ], "comment": "exchange of blows; long rally" },
	{ "question": "打ち合わせる", "answers": [ "うちあわせる" ], "comment": "to knock together\nto arrange (e.g. a meeting)" },
	{ "question": "打ち消し", "answers": [ "うちけし" ], "comment": "negation; denial; negative" },
	{ "question": "打ち込み", "answers": [ "うちこみ" ], "comment": "driving; pounding in; shooting into; implantation; invasion\nfalling badly in love\nputting (one's heart) into\nstep recording (in electronic or computer music)" },
	{ "question": "打倒", "answers": [ "だとう" ], "comment": "knockdown (e.g. in boxing); overthrow; defeat" },
	{ "question": "打席", "answers": [ "だせき" ], "comment": "batter's box; one's turn at bat" },
	{ "question": "打撲", "answers": [ "だぼく" ], "comment": "blow; hit (on the body); beating" },
	{ "question": "打数", "answers": [ "だすう" ], "comment": "times at bat" },
	{ "question": "打消し", "answers": [ "うちけし" ], "comment": "negation; denial; negative" },
	{ "question": "打点", "answers": [ "だてん" ], "comment": "runs batted in; RBI" },
	{ "question": "打率", "answers": [ "だりつ" ], "comment": "batting average" },
	{ "question": "打球", "answers": [ "だきゅう" ], "comment": "batting; batted ball" },
	{ "question": "打破", "answers": [ "だは" ], "comment": "breaking down; defeating; abolishing" },
	{ "question": "打線", "answers": [ "だせん" ], "comment": "batting lineup (line-up)" },
	{ "question": "打者", "answers": [ "だしゃ" ], "comment": "batter" },
	{ "question": "打診", "answers": [ "だしん" ], "comment": "percussion; tapping\nsounding someone out" },
	{ "question": "打開", "answers": [ "だかい" ], "comment": "break in the deadlock" },
	{ "question": "打順", "answers": [ "だじゅん" ], "comment": "batting order" },
	{ "question": "払い戻し", "answers": [ "はらいもどし" ], "comment": "repayment; refund; payback" },
	{ "question": "払拭", "answers": [ "ふっしょく", "ふっしき" ], "comment": "wiping out; sweeping away" },
	{ "question": "扶助", "answers": [ "ふじょ" ], "comment": "aid; help; assistance; support" },
	{ "question": "批准", "answers": [ "ひじゅん" ], "comment": "ratification; ratify" },
	{ "question": "技巧", "answers": [ "ぎこう" ], "comment": "technique; finesse" },
	{ "question": "抑揚", "answers": [ "よくよう" ], "comment": "intonation; accent; modulation; inflection" },
	{ "question": "抑止", "answers": [ "よくし" ], "comment": "check; checkmate; stave off; control; restraint; inhibit; deterrent; deterrence" },
	{ "question": "抑留", "answers": [ "よくりゅう" ], "comment": "internment; detainment; detention" },
	{ "question": "投げ", "answers": [ "なげ" ], "comment": "a throw; a fall" },
	{ "question": "投与", "answers": [ "とうよ" ], "comment": "prescribing medicine; administering (medicine)" },
	{ "question": "投信", "answers": [ "とうしん" ], "comment": "investment trust" },
	{ "question": "投入", "answers": [ "とうにゅう" ], "comment": "throwing into; inserting; depositing\ninvestment; putting in (personnel, etc.)\nrelease of a product\nmaking (an electrical circuit)" },
	{ "question": "投射", "answers": [ "とうしゃ" ], "comment": "projection" },
	{ "question": "投影", "answers": [ "とうえい" ], "comment": "projection" },
	{ "question": "投棄", "answers": [ "とうき" ], "comment": "abandonment; giving up; throwing away; disposal; dumping" },
	{ "question": "投機", "answers": [ "とうき" ], "comment": "speculation; venture; stockjobbing; gambling (on stocks)" },
	{ "question": "投球", "answers": [ "とうきゅう" ], "comment": "pitching; throwing a ball; bowling (in cricket); pitched ball" },
	{ "question": "投石", "answers": [ "とうせき" ], "comment": "stone throwing" },
	{ "question": "投薬", "answers": [ "とうやく" ], "comment": "administration; medication; dosage" },
	{ "question": "投融資", "answers": [ "とうゆうし" ], "comment": "investment and lending" },
	{ "question": "投降", "answers": [ "とうこう" ], "comment": "surrender" },
	{ "question": "抗争", "answers": [ "こうそう" ], "comment": "dispute; resistance" },
	{ "question": "抗体", "answers": [ "こうたい" ], "comment": "antibody" },
	{ "question": "抗原", "answers": [ "こうげん" ], "comment": "antigen" },
	{ "question": "抗告", "answers": [ "こうこく" ], "comment": "kokoku (interlocutory) appeal; protest; complaint" },
	{ "question": "抗戦", "answers": [ "こうせん" ], "comment": "resistance" },
	{ "question": "抗日", "answers": [ "こうにち" ], "comment": "anti-Japanese" },
	{ "question": "抗菌", "answers": [ "こうきん" ], "comment": "antibacterial; antimicrobial" },
	{ "question": "折", "answers": [ "おり" ], "comment": "opportunity; chance; occasion; time\nfold; pleat; crease\nsmall food box (wooden or cardboard)" },
	{ "question": "折々", "answers": [ "おりおり" ], "comment": "occasionally" },
	{ "question": "折から", "answers": [ "おりから", "おりがら" ], "comment": "just then; at that time; right then; at that moment\nappropriate moment" },
	{ "question": "折りたたみ", "answers": [ "おりたたみ" ], "comment": "folding; collapsible; telescopic" },
	{ "question": "折り合い", "answers": [ "おりあい" ], "comment": "agreement (e.g. business, dispute); compromise\nmutual relations (e.g. between parents and child, coworkers, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "折り畳み", "answers": [ "おりたたみ" ], "comment": "folding; collapsible; telescopic" },
	{ "question": "折り紙", "answers": [ "おりがみ" ], "comment": "origami; art of paper folding\nhallmark; certificate of authenticity" },
	{ "question": "折り返し", "answers": [ "おりかえし" ], "comment": "by return; (call or write back) without delay\nlapel; cuffs; flap\nchorus; refrain\nrepetition\naliasing (in imaging)\nshuttle service\nback-to-back; BTB\nwrapping (text on computer screen); wrap" },
	{ "question": "折り返す", "answers": [ "おりかえす" ], "comment": "to turn up; to fold back\nto loopback (a signal, a message)" },
	{ "question": "折半", "answers": [ "せっぱん" ], "comment": "halving; splitting evenly; sharing equally" },
	{ "question": "折紙", "answers": [ "おりがみ" ], "comment": "origami; art of paper folding\nhallmark; certificate of authenticity" },
	{ "question": "折衝", "answers": [ "せっしょう" ], "comment": "negotiation" },
	{ "question": "折衷", "answers": [ "せっちゅう" ], "comment": "compromise; cross; blending; eclecticism" },
	{ "question": "抜かす", "answers": [ "ぬかす" ], "comment": "to omit; to leave out; to skip\nto say; to speak" },
	{ "question": "抜き", "answers": [ "ぬき" ], "comment": "without; not including; dispensed with\n(beating) in succession" },
	{ "question": "抜粋", "answers": [ "ばっすい" ], "comment": "extract; excerpt; selection" },
	{ "question": "択一", "answers": [ "たくいつ" ], "comment": "choosing an alternative" },
	{ "question": "抱え", "answers": [ "かかえ" ], "comment": "armful\nemployee" },
	{ "question": "抱っこ", "answers": [ "だっこ" ], "comment": "(child's) hug; carrying a baby in one's arms; carrying a pet in one's arms" },
	{ "question": "抱負", "answers": [ "ほうふ" ], "comment": "aspiration; ambition; pretension" },
	{ "question": "抵触", "answers": [ "ていしょく" ], "comment": "collision; conflict\nbeing contrary; being incompatible; being inconsistent; being contradictory\nbeing in violation (of a law, treaty, etc.); contravention" },
	{ "question": "抹消", "answers": [ "まっしょう" ], "comment": "erasure; striking off; crossing out; cancellation; deletion" },
	{ "question": "押し入る", "answers": [ "おしいる" ], "comment": "to push in; to force into; to break in (e.g. into a house); to intrude" },
	{ "question": "押し出し", "answers": [ "おしだし" ], "comment": "pushing something out; extrusion\npresence; appearance\nrun walked in\npushing one's opponent out by pressing one's hands up against them" },
	{ "question": "押し切る", "answers": [ "おしきる" ], "comment": "to face down the opposition; to overcome resistance; to have one's own way\nto press and cut" },
	{ "question": "押し売り", "answers": [ "おしうり" ], "comment": "high-pressure salesmanship" },
	{ "question": "押収", "answers": [ "おうしゅう" ], "comment": "seizure; confiscation" },
	{ "question": "押売", "answers": [ "おしうり" ], "comment": "high-pressure salesmanship" },
	{ "question": "押売り", "answers": [ "おしうり" ], "comment": "high-pressure salesmanship" },
	{ "question": "抽選", "answers": [ "ちゅうせん" ], "comment": "lottery; raffle; drawing (of lots)" },
	{ "question": "担ぎ", "answers": [ "かつぎ" ], "comment": "carrier" },
	{ "question": "担任", "answers": [ "たんにん" ], "comment": "in charge (of something)\nclass teacher; homeroom teacher; form teacher" },
	{ "question": "担保", "answers": [ "たんぽ" ], "comment": "security; guarantee; collateral (e.g. mortgage)" },
	{ "question": "担架", "answers": [ "たんか" ], "comment": "stretcher; litter" },
	{ "question": "拍車", "answers": [ "はくしゃ" ], "comment": "(riding) spur" },
	{ "question": "拘禁", "answers": [ "こうきん" ], "comment": "detention; custody; confinement; internment" },
	{ "question": "拘置", "answers": [ "こうち" ], "comment": "detention; confinement; arrest" },
	{ "question": "拙速", "answers": [ "せっそく" ], "comment": "hasty; rough and ready" },
	{ "question": "招き", "answers": [ "まねき" ], "comment": "invitation" },
	{ "question": "招致", "answers": [ "しょうち" ], "comment": "invitation; summons; bidding (e.g. to host the Olympics); calling" },
	{ "question": "招請", "answers": [ "しょうせい" ], "comment": "calling together; invitation" },
	{ "question": "招集", "answers": [ "しょうしゅう" ], "comment": "call; summons; convening; convocation" },
	{ "question": "拝啓", "answers": [ "はいけい" ], "comment": "Dear (so and so); Dear Sir; Dear Madam; To Whom It May Concern" },
	{ "question": "拠出", "answers": [ "きょしゅつ" ], "comment": "donation; contribution" },
	{ "question": "拾い物", "answers": [ "ひろいもの" ], "comment": "a find\nwindfall; bargain" },
	{ "question": "拾得", "answers": [ "しゅうとく" ], "comment": "picking up; finding" },
	{ "question": "持ち出し", "answers": [ "もちだし" ], "comment": "taking something out; carrying out\nproviding money oneself; paying with one's own money\ncorbel\nstrengthening under a seam (clothing)" },
	{ "question": "持ち前", "answers": [ "もちまえ" ], "comment": "one's nature; characteristic; inherent; natural" },
	{ "question": "持ち合い", "answers": [ "たもちあい", "もちあい" ], "comment": "unity; even matching; interdependence\nsteadiness (of market price); holding; no change" },
	{ "question": "持ち味", "answers": [ "もちあじ" ], "comment": "inherent flavor; inherent flavour; distinctive characteristic" },
	{ "question": "持ち回り", "answers": [ "もちまわり" ], "comment": "rotation; by turns" },
	{ "question": "持ち堪える", "answers": [ "もちこたえる" ], "comment": "to hold out (e.g. against an attack); to hang on; to withstand; to endure; to last" },
	{ "question": "持ち家", "answers": [ "もちや", "もちいえ" ], "comment": "one's (own) house" },
	{ "question": "持ち帰り", "answers": [ "もちかえり" ], "comment": "takeout (i.e. food); take-out; takeaway; take-away" },
	{ "question": "持ち帰る", "answers": [ "もちかえる" ], "comment": "to bring back; to carry home; to take out (e.g. food)" },
	{ "question": "持ち株", "answers": [ "もちかぶ" ], "comment": "stock holdings; one's shares" },
	{ "question": "持ち直す", "answers": [ "もちなおす" ], "comment": "to recover; to rally; to improve; to pick up" },
	{ "question": "持ち越す", "answers": [ "もちこす" ], "comment": "to carry over; to carry forward; to keep (for later); to defer" },
	{ "question": "持ち込み", "answers": [ "もちこみ" ], "comment": "bring-your-own (e.g. food and drink); carry-on (e.g. luggage)" },
	{ "question": "持久", "answers": [ "じきゅう" ], "comment": "endurance; persistence" },
	{ "question": "持堪える", "answers": [ "もちこたえる" ], "comment": "to hold out (e.g. against an attack); to hang on; to withstand; to endure; to last" },
	{ "question": "持病", "answers": [ "じびょう" ], "comment": "chronic disease" },
	{ "question": "持直す", "answers": [ "もちなおす" ], "comment": "to recover; to rally; to improve; to pick up" },
	{ "question": "持論", "answers": [ "じろん" ], "comment": "one's cherished opinion; pet theory" },
	{ "question": "指し示す", "answers": [ "さししめす" ], "comment": "to indicate; to show; to point to" },
	{ "question": "指切り", "answers": [ "ゆびきり" ], "comment": "linking little fingers to confirm a promise" },
	{ "question": "指図", "answers": [ "さしず" ], "comment": "instruction; mandate; directions" },
	{ "question": "指数", "answers": [ "しすう" ], "comment": "index; index number; exponent (e.g. in floating-point representation); characteristic" },
	{ "question": "挑発", "answers": [ "ちょうはつ" ], "comment": "provocation; stirring up; arousal" },
	{ "question": "挙がる", "answers": [ "あがる" ], "comment": "to rise; to go up; to come up; to ascend; to be raised\nto enter (esp. from outdoors); to come in; to go in\nto enter (a school); to advance to the next grade\nto get out (of water); to come ashore\nto increase\nto improve; to make progress\nto be promoted; to advance\nto be made (of profit, etc.)\nto occur (esp. of a favourable result)\nto be adequate (to cover expenses, etc.)\nto be finished; to be done; to be over\n(of rain) to stop; to lift\nto stop (working properly); to cut out; to give out; to die\nto win (in a card game, etc.)\nto be arrested\nto turn up (of evidence, etc.)\nto be deep fried\nto be spoken loudly\nto get stage fright\nto be offered (to the gods, etc.)\nto go; to visit\nto eat; to drink\nto be listed (as a candidate)\nto serve (in one's master's home)\nto go north\nindicates completion" },
	{ "question": "挙党", "answers": [ "きょとう" ], "comment": "entire (political) party" },
	{ "question": "挙式", "answers": [ "きょしき" ], "comment": "holding a ceremony; wedding ceremony" },
	{ "question": "挟み撃ち", "answers": [ "はさみうち" ], "comment": "pincer attack; attack on both sides (flanks)" },
	{ "question": "振り付け", "answers": [ "ふりつけ" ], "comment": "choreography; dance composition; dance coaching" },
	{ "question": "振り出し", "answers": [ "ふりだし" ], "comment": "starting point; beginning; outset\ndrawing; issuing; draft; draught\nshaking out\nthrow (of dice); toss\ninfusion" },
	{ "question": "振り切る", "answers": [ "ふりきる" ], "comment": "to shake off; to shake free from\nto swing completely" },
	{ "question": "振り子", "answers": [ "しんし", "ふりこ" ], "comment": "pendulum" },
	{ "question": "振り込む", "answers": [ "ふりこむ" ], "comment": "to make a payment via bank deposit transfer\nto discard another player's winning tile" },
	{ "question": "振り返る", "answers": [ "ふりかえる" ], "comment": "to turn head; to look over one's shoulder; to turn around; to look back\nto think back (on); to reminisce; to look back (on); to reflect (on)" },
	{ "question": "振替", "answers": [ "ふりかえ" ], "comment": "transfer; switching over; change\nmoney transfer (usu. between accounts held by the same person)\npostal transfer" },
	{ "question": "挽肉", "answers": [ "ひきにく" ], "comment": "minced meat; ground meat" },
	{ "question": "挿絵", "answers": [ "さしえ" ], "comment": "illustration (e.g. book); picture" },
	{ "question": "捕手", "answers": [ "ほしゅ" ], "comment": "catcher" },
	{ "question": "捕獲", "answers": [ "ほかく" ], "comment": "capture; seizure" },
	{ "question": "捕鯨", "answers": [ "ほげい" ], "comment": "whaling; whale fishing" },
	{ "question": "捨て子", "answers": [ "すてご", "きじ" ], "comment": "abandoned child; foundling" },
	{ "question": "据える", "answers": [ "すえる" ], "comment": "to place (in position); to fix; to set (e.g. table); to lay (foundation)\nto install; to seat (someone)\nto settle (upon something); to fix (e.g. one's gaze)\nto apply (moxa)" },
	{ "question": "据え置き", "answers": [ "すえおき" ], "comment": "deferment (e.g. of savings); leaving (a thing) as it stands\nunredeemed; unredeemable; irredeemable; deferred; stationary" },
	{ "question": "捻挫", "answers": [ "ねんざ" ], "comment": "sprain" },
	{ "question": "掃海", "answers": [ "そうかい" ], "comment": "sweeping the sea for mines; dragging for mines" },
	{ "question": "掃討", "answers": [ "そうとう" ], "comment": "cleaning up; sweeping up; mopping up" },
	{ "question": "授与", "answers": [ "じゅよ" ], "comment": "award; conferment" },
	{ "question": "授受", "answers": [ "じゅじゅ" ], "comment": "giving and receiving; transferring; transfer; changing hands" },
	{ "question": "排他", "answers": [ "はいた" ], "comment": "exclusion" },
	{ "question": "排斥", "answers": [ "はいせき" ], "comment": "rejection; expulsion; boycott; ostracism" },
	{ "question": "排日", "answers": [ "はいにち" ], "comment": "anti-Japanese" },
	{ "question": "排水", "answers": [ "はいすい" ], "comment": "drainage" },
	{ "question": "掘削", "answers": [ "くっさく" ], "comment": "digging out; excavation" },
	{ "question": "掛け声", "answers": [ "かけごえ" ], "comment": "yell used to time or encourage activity (e.g. \"Heave ho!\", \"On three ... One, two, three!\" in English); enthusiastic shout from the audience (e.g. in kabuki); shouting (in concerts)" },
	{ "question": "掛け金", "answers": [ "かけきん" ], "comment": "installment; instalment; premium; bill" },
	{ "question": "掛軸", "answers": [ "かけじく" ], "comment": "hanging scroll" },
	{ "question": "掟", "answers": [ "おきて" ], "comment": "law; regulation; rule; code; agreement; arrangement; compact" },
	{ "question": "採取", "answers": [ "さいしゅ" ], "comment": "picking; collecting; harvesting" },
	{ "question": "採択", "answers": [ "さいたく" ], "comment": "adoption; selection; choice" },
	{ "question": "採掘", "answers": [ "さいくつ" ], "comment": "mining" },
	{ "question": "採決", "answers": [ "さいけつ" ], "comment": "vote; roll call" },
	{ "question": "採算", "answers": [ "さいさん" ], "comment": "profit" },
	{ "question": "探し回る", "answers": [ "さがしまわる" ], "comment": "to search about for; to hunt around for; to look high and low for; to look everywhere for" },
	{ "question": "探査", "answers": [ "たんさ" ], "comment": "probe; inquiry; enquiry; investigation" },
	{ "question": "探求", "answers": [ "たんきゅう" ], "comment": "search; quest; pursuit" },
	{ "question": "探究", "answers": [ "たんきゅう" ], "comment": "research; investigation; enquiry; inquiry; study" },
	{ "question": "接戦", "answers": [ "せっせん" ], "comment": "close combat; close contest" },
	{ "question": "接着", "answers": [ "せっちゃく" ], "comment": "adhesion; glueing; gluing; bonding; binding; adhering; fastening" },
	{ "question": "接種", "answers": [ "せっしゅ" ], "comment": "inoculation; vaccination" },
	{ "question": "接見", "answers": [ "せっけん" ], "comment": "interview" },
	{ "question": "控え", "answers": [ "ひかえ" ], "comment": "reserve; spare; backup\nnote; memorandum\nduplicate; copy; stub (of a ticket, etc.)\nwaiting one's turn" },
	{ "question": "控え室", "answers": [ "ひかえしつ" ], "comment": "waiting room" },
	{ "question": "控室", "answers": [ "ひかえしつ" ], "comment": "waiting room" },
	{ "question": "控訴", "answers": [ "こうそ" ], "comment": "koso appeal (initial appeal to a higher court)" },
	{ "question": "推す", "answers": [ "おす" ], "comment": "to recommend; to endorse (e.g. a candidate); to nominate\nto infer; to conclude; to conjecture; to surmise\nto think something through; to ponder deeply" },
	{ "question": "推奨", "answers": [ "すいしょう" ], "comment": "recommendation; endorsement" },
	{ "question": "推敲", "answers": [ "すいこう" ], "comment": "polishing (e.g. essay); revision; elaboration; refinement; improvement" },
	{ "question": "推計", "answers": [ "すいけい" ], "comment": "estimate; estimation" },
	{ "question": "推量", "answers": [ "すいりょう" ], "comment": "guess; conjecture; supposition; inference" },
	{ "question": "掲揚", "answers": [ "けいよう" ], "comment": "hoist (flag); fly; display" },
	{ "question": "掻き回す", "answers": [ "かきまわす" ], "comment": "to stir up; to churn; to ransack; to disturb" },
	{ "question": "提訴", "answers": [ "ていそ" ], "comment": "presenting a case; suing" },
	{ "question": "揚げ", "answers": [ "あげ" ], "comment": "frying; fried food\nfried tofu; fried bean curd" },
	{ "question": "換金", "answers": [ "かんきん" ], "comment": "realization (of goods into money); conversion (into money); liquidation" },
	{ "question": "握り", "answers": [ "にぎり" ], "comment": "grasping; gripping; grasp; grip; clutch\nhandful; fistful\nhandle; grip; knob\nrice ball\nnigirizushi; hand-formed sushi with a topping of seafood, etc." },
	{ "question": "握力", "answers": [ "あくりょく" ], "comment": "grip (of hand); grip strength" },
	{ "question": "援護", "answers": [ "えんご" ], "comment": "covering; protection; backing; relief" },
	{ "question": "揺さぶり", "answers": [ "ゆさぶり" ], "comment": "shaking; shaking up (one's adversary)" },
	{ "question": "揺らぎ", "answers": [ "ゆらぎ" ], "comment": "tremor; fluctuation" },
	{ "question": "揺らぐ", "answers": [ "ゆらぐ" ], "comment": "to swing; to sway; to shake; to tremble\nto waver; to feel shaken; to become unstable" },
	{ "question": "揺る", "answers": [ "ゆる" ], "comment": "to shake; to jolt; to rock (cradle); to swing" },
	{ "question": "揺るがす", "answers": [ "ゆるがす" ], "comment": "to shake; to swing; to sway; to shock" },
	{ "question": "損する", "answers": [ "そんする" ], "comment": "to lose (money, etc.)\nto have wasted one's (time, etc.); to have one's efforts come to naught" },
	{ "question": "損ねる", "answers": [ "そこねる" ], "comment": "to harm; to hurt; to injure; to wreck\nto miss one's chance to (do something); to fail to (do what one ought to have done)" },
	{ "question": "損壊", "answers": [ "そんかい" ], "comment": "damage; destruction" },
	{ "question": "損益", "answers": [ "そんえき" ], "comment": "profit and loss; advantage and disadvantage" },
	{ "question": "搬入", "answers": [ "はんにゅう" ], "comment": "taking in; bringing in (esp. heavy objects, artwork, furniture); carrying in" },
	{ "question": "搬送", "answers": [ "はんそう" ], "comment": "transportation; conveyance; delivery\nhospitalization; transfer to hospital" },
	{ "question": "携える", "answers": [ "たずさえる" ], "comment": "to carry in one's hand" },
	{ "question": "搾取", "answers": [ "さくしゅ" ], "comment": "exploitation; squeezing; sweating" },
	{ "question": "摂氏", "answers": [ "せっし" ], "comment": "Centigrade; Celsius" },
	{ "question": "摘出", "answers": [ "てきしゅつ" ], "comment": "picking out; taking out; (surgical) removal\nexposure" },
	{ "question": "摘発", "answers": [ "てきはつ" ], "comment": "exposing; unmasking; laying bare" },
	{ "question": "撃墜", "answers": [ "げきつい" ], "comment": "shooting down (aircraft)" },
	{ "question": "撤去", "answers": [ "てっきょ" ], "comment": "withdrawal; revocation; repeal\ndemolition; removal" },
	{ "question": "撤収", "answers": [ "てっしゅう" ], "comment": "removal (e.g. of a building); dismantling (e.g. a tent); striking (e.g. a stage set)\nwithdrawal (of troops); evacuation; retreating" },
	{ "question": "撤回", "answers": [ "てっかい" ], "comment": "withdrawal; retraction; revocation; repeal" },
	{ "question": "撤廃", "answers": [ "てっぱい" ], "comment": "annulment; abolition; repeal; rescission" },
	{ "question": "撲滅", "answers": [ "ぼくめつ" ], "comment": "eradication; extermination; destruction; suppression" },
	{ "question": "擁する", "answers": [ "ようする" ], "comment": "to have; to possess" },
	{ "question": "擁立", "answers": [ "ようりつ" ], "comment": "backing (for a position); support" },
	{ "question": "操業", "answers": [ "そうぎょう" ], "comment": "operation" },
	{ "question": "擬装", "answers": [ "ぎそう" ], "comment": "camouflage; disguise\npretense; feigning; masquerade" },
	{ "question": "支局", "answers": [ "しきょく" ], "comment": "branch office" },
	{ "question": "支所", "answers": [ "ししょ" ], "comment": "branch (office)" },
	{ "question": "支柱", "answers": [ "しちゅう" ], "comment": "prop; stay; support; brace; fulcrum" },
	{ "question": "支流", "answers": [ "しりゅう" ], "comment": "tributary; branch" },
	{ "question": "支社", "answers": [ "ししゃ" ], "comment": "branch office" },
	{ "question": "支部", "answers": [ "しぶ" ], "comment": "branch; subdivision" },
	{ "question": "改まる", "answers": [ "あらたまる" ], "comment": "to be renewed\nto stand on ceremony; to be formal\nto take a turn for the worse" },
	{ "question": "改修", "answers": [ "かいしゅう" ], "comment": "repair; improvement" },
	{ "question": "改定", "answers": [ "かいてい", "かいじょう" ], "comment": "revision (of a rule, price, etc.); reform; alteration; change" },
	{ "question": "改憲", "answers": [ "かいけん" ], "comment": "constitutional change" },
	{ "question": "改新", "answers": [ "かいしん" ], "comment": "reformation" },
	{ "question": "改築", "answers": [ "かいちく" ], "comment": "structural alteration of building; reconstruction" },
	{ "question": "改組", "answers": [ "かいそ" ], "comment": "reorganization; reorganisation" },
	{ "question": "改編", "answers": [ "かいへん" ], "comment": "reorganization; reorganisation" },
	{ "question": "改装", "answers": [ "かいそう" ], "comment": "remodelling; remodeling; reorganization; reorganisation" },
	{ "question": "改選", "answers": [ "かいせん" ], "comment": "re-election" },
	{ "question": "攻勢", "answers": [ "こうせい" ], "comment": "offensive (movement); aggression" },
	{ "question": "攻守", "answers": [ "こうしゅ" ], "comment": "offense and defense; offence and defence; batting and fielding" },
	{ "question": "攻防", "answers": [ "こうぼう" ], "comment": "offense and defense; offence and defence" },
	{ "question": "放任", "answers": [ "ほうにん" ], "comment": "noninterference; leaving something to take its own course; giving someone a free hand with something" },
	{ "question": "放水", "answers": [ "ほうすい" ], "comment": "hosing down; drainage; discharge of water; spraying with water" },
	{ "question": "放流", "answers": [ "ほうりゅう" ], "comment": "discharge (e.g. of water from a dam)\nliberation; stocking (e.g. a river with fish)" },
	{ "question": "放浪", "answers": [ "ほうろう" ], "comment": "wandering" },
	{ "question": "政争", "answers": [ "せいそう" ], "comment": "political strife" },
	{ "question": "政令", "answers": [ "せいれい" ], "comment": "government ordinance; cabinet order" },
	{ "question": "政務", "answers": [ "せいむ" ], "comment": "government affairs" },
	{ "question": "政変", "answers": [ "せいへん" ], "comment": "political disturbance; political change; coup d'état; coup; revolution; overthrowing of a government (e.g. Jasmine Revolution)" },
	{ "question": "政局", "answers": [ "せいきょく" ], "comment": "political situation" },
	{ "question": "政庁", "answers": [ "せいちょう" ], "comment": "government office" },
	{ "question": "政情", "answers": [ "せいじょう" ], "comment": "political situation; political affairs" },
	{ "question": "政教", "answers": [ "せいきょう" ], "comment": "religion and politics; church and state" },
	{ "question": "政敵", "answers": [ "せいてき" ], "comment": "political opponent" },
	{ "question": "政界", "answers": [ "せいかい" ], "comment": "political world" },
	{ "question": "政経", "answers": [ "せいけい" ], "comment": "politics and economics" },
	{ "question": "政見", "answers": [ "せいけん" ], "comment": "political views" },
	{ "question": "故事", "answers": [ "こじ" ], "comment": "historical event; ancient event\ntradition; folklore; legend; origin" },
	{ "question": "故国", "answers": [ "ここく" ], "comment": "one's native land" },
	{ "question": "救出", "answers": [ "きゅうしゅつ" ], "comment": "rescue; extricate; reclaim; deliverance" },
	{ "question": "救命", "answers": [ "きゅうめい" ], "comment": "lifesaving" },
	{ "question": "救国", "answers": [ "きゅうこく" ], "comment": "patriot devoted to the salvation of his country" },
	{ "question": "救急", "answers": [ "きゅうきゅう" ], "comment": "first-aid; emergency (aid)" },
	{ "question": "救援", "answers": [ "きゅうえん" ], "comment": "relief; rescue; reinforcement" },
	{ "question": "敗因", "answers": [ "はいいん" ], "comment": "cause of defeat" },
	{ "question": "敗者", "answers": [ "はいしゃ" ], "comment": "the defeated; vanquished; loser" },
	{ "question": "敗訴", "answers": [ "はいそ" ], "comment": "loss of a court-case" },
	{ "question": "敗退", "answers": [ "はいたい" ], "comment": "being defeated; being eliminated (from competition)" },
	{ "question": "教え", "answers": [ "おしえ" ], "comment": "teaching; instruction; teachings; precept; lesson; doctrine" },
	{ "question": "教え子", "answers": [ "おしえご" ], "comment": "student; disciple" },
	{ "question": "教務", "answers": [ "きょうむ" ], "comment": "school affairs; religious affairs" },
	{ "question": "教壇", "answers": [ "きょうだん" ], "comment": "(teacher's) platform; podium; dais" },
	{ "question": "教書", "answers": [ "きょうしょ" ], "comment": "(presidential) message" },
	{ "question": "教祖", "answers": [ "きょうそ" ], "comment": "founder of a religious sect" },
	{ "question": "教習", "answers": [ "きょうしゅう" ], "comment": "training; instruction" },
	{ "question": "教職員", "answers": [ "きょうしょくいん" ], "comment": "teaching staff; faculty" },
	{ "question": "教諭", "answers": [ "きょうゆ" ], "comment": "(licensed) teacher" },
	{ "question": "教頭", "answers": [ "きょうとう" ], "comment": "deputy head teacher; vice principal" },
	{ "question": "敢行", "answers": [ "かんこう" ], "comment": "decisive action" },
	{ "question": "敢闘", "answers": [ "かんとう" ], "comment": "fighting bravely" },
	{ "question": "散会", "answers": [ "さんかい" ], "comment": "adjournment" },
	{ "question": "散布", "answers": [ "さんぷ", "さっぷ" ], "comment": "dissemination; scattering; sprinkling; spraying" },
	{ "question": "散発", "answers": [ "さんぱつ" ], "comment": "sporadic; scattering" },
	{ "question": "散策", "answers": [ "さんさく" ], "comment": "walking; strolling; roaming; wandering; exploring" },
	{ "question": "散骨", "answers": [ "さんこつ" ], "comment": "scattering of ashes (cremated remains)" },
	{ "question": "散髪", "answers": [ "さんぱつ" ], "comment": "(having a) haircut; hair-cutting; hair-dressing" },
	{ "question": "敬具", "answers": [ "けいぐ" ], "comment": "Yours sincerely; Yours truly; Sincerely yours" },
	{ "question": "敬称", "answers": [ "けいしょう" ], "comment": "title of honour; title of honor" },
	{ "question": "敬老", "answers": [ "けいろう" ], "comment": "respect for the aged" },
	{ "question": "敬遠", "answers": [ "けいえん" ], "comment": "pretending to respect someone while in fact staying distant; keeping at arms length; giving a wide berth\navoiding (something unpleasant); shying away from\ngiving the batter an \"intentional walk\"" },
	{ "question": "数次", "answers": [ "すうじ" ], "comment": "number of times" },
	{ "question": "整列", "answers": [ "せいれつ" ], "comment": "standing in a row; forming a line; alignment" },
	{ "question": "整頓", "answers": [ "せいとん" ], "comment": "orderliness; put in order; tidying up; arranging neatly" },
	{ "question": "敵国", "answers": [ "てきこく", "てっこく" ], "comment": "enemy nation" },
	{ "question": "敵意", "answers": [ "てきい" ], "comment": "hostility; animosity; enmity" },
	{ "question": "敷居", "answers": [ "しき", "しきみ", "しきい" ], "comment": "threshold (esp. one with grooves for sliding doors); sill" },
	{ "question": "敷設", "answers": [ "ふせつ" ], "comment": "laying (a railroad, pipes, naval mines, etc.); construction" },
	{ "question": "敷金", "answers": [ "しききん" ], "comment": "(security) deposit; caution money" },
	{ "question": "文中", "answers": [ "ぶんちゅう" ], "comment": "in the document\nBunchuu era (of the Southern Court) (1372.4.?-1375.5.27)" },
	{ "question": "文具", "answers": [ "ぶんぐ" ], "comment": "stationery" },
	{ "question": "文壇", "answers": [ "ぶんだん" ], "comment": "literary world; literary circles" },
	{ "question": "文教", "answers": [ "ぶんきょう" ], "comment": "education; culture" },
	{ "question": "文楽", "answers": [ "ぶんらく" ], "comment": "Japanese puppet theatre (theater); bunraku" },
	{ "question": "文様", "answers": [ "もんよう" ], "comment": "pattern; design" },
	{ "question": "文民", "answers": [ "ぶんみん" ], "comment": "civilian" },
	{ "question": "文相", "answers": [ "ぶんしょう" ], "comment": "Minister of Education, Science and Culture" },
	{ "question": "文科", "answers": [ "ぶんか" ], "comment": "literary course\nthe arts" },
	{ "question": "文系", "answers": [ "ぶんけい" ], "comment": "humanities, social sciences, and fine arts; liberal arts" },
	{ "question": "文語", "answers": [ "ぶんご" ], "comment": "written language; literary language\nformal (or archaic) written style based on Heian-period Japanese" },
	{ "question": "文通", "answers": [ "ぶんつう" ], "comment": "correspondence; exchange of letters" },
	{ "question": "斉唱", "answers": [ "せいしょう" ], "comment": "singing or chanting in unison" },
	{ "question": "斎場", "answers": [ "さいじょう" ], "comment": "funeral hall\nceremony site" },
	{ "question": "斗", "answers": [ "と" ], "comment": "to (measure of volume, approx. 18 litres)\nsquare bearing block (at the top of a pillar)\nChinese \"Dipper\" constellation (one of the 28 mansions)" },
	{ "question": "料亭", "answers": [ "りょうてい" ], "comment": "ryotei; traditional Japanese restaurant (esp. a luxurious one)" },
	{ "question": "斡旋", "answers": [ "あっせん" ], "comment": "kind offices; services; through the good offices of; influence\nintercession; mediation" },
	{ "question": "断", "answers": [ "だん" ], "comment": "decision; judgment; resolution" },
	{ "question": "断層", "answers": [ "だんそう" ], "comment": "fault; dislocation\ngap; discrepancy" },
	{ "question": "断然", "answers": [ "だんぜん" ], "comment": "firmly; absolutely; definitely; flatly; far and away; by far; by a long shot; hands down" },
	{ "question": "断熱", "answers": [ "だんねつ" ], "comment": "insulation" },
	{ "question": "断絶", "answers": [ "だんぜつ" ], "comment": "extinction; discontinuation; interruption\nseverance; rupture\nto become extinct; to cease to exist\nto sever; to break off; to divide (between two things)" },
	{ "question": "断続", "answers": [ "だんぞく" ], "comment": "intermittent" },
	{ "question": "断行", "answers": [ "だんこう" ], "comment": "decisive action; carry out" },
	{ "question": "断面", "answers": [ "だんめん" ], "comment": "cross-section" },
	{ "question": "断食", "answers": [ "だんじき" ], "comment": "fasting" },
	{ "question": "新", "answers": [ "しん" ], "comment": "new; neo-\nGregorian calendar\nXin (dynasty of China)" },
	{ "question": "新任", "answers": [ "しんにん" ], "comment": "inaugural; new" },
	{ "question": "新体", "answers": [ "しんたい" ], "comment": "new style" },
	{ "question": "新作", "answers": [ "しんさく" ], "comment": "new work; new production" },
	{ "question": "新党", "answers": [ "しんとう" ], "comment": "new (political) party" },
	{ "question": "新刊", "answers": [ "しんかん" ], "comment": "new book; new publication" },
	{ "question": "新制", "answers": [ "しんせい" ], "comment": "new system" },
	{ "question": "新劇", "answers": [ "しんげき" ], "comment": "new type or school of drama" },
	{ "question": "新卒", "answers": [ "しんそつ" ], "comment": "new (recent) graduate" },
	{ "question": "新型", "answers": [ "しんがた" ], "comment": "new type; new style; new model; new strain (e.g. infectious disease)" },
	{ "question": "新居", "answers": [ "しんきょ" ], "comment": "new home" },
	{ "question": "新年", "answers": [ "しんねん" ], "comment": "New Year" },
	{ "question": "新手", "answers": [ "あらて", "しんて" ], "comment": "fresh supply of troops; newcomer\nnew method; new trick" },
	{ "question": "新政", "answers": [ "しんせい" ], "comment": "new government; new administration" },
	{ "question": "新旧", "answers": [ "しんきゅう" ], "comment": "new and old; incoming and outgoing" },
	{ "question": "新星", "answers": [ "しんせい" ], "comment": "nova\nnew face; new star" },
	{ "question": "新春", "answers": [ "しんしゅん" ], "comment": "New Year (Spring)" },
	{ "question": "新曲", "answers": [ "しんきょく" ], "comment": "new piece; new song" },
	{ "question": "新書", "answers": [ "しんしょ" ], "comment": "new book\n17 x 11 cm paperbook book" },
	{ "question": "新株", "answers": [ "しんかぶ" ], "comment": "new stocks or shares" },
	{ "question": "新法", "answers": [ "しんぽう" ], "comment": "new law\nnew method" },
	{ "question": "新派", "answers": [ "しんぱ" ], "comment": "new school (of thought, etc.)\nnew drama" },
	{ "question": "新田", "answers": [ "しんでん", "あらた" ], "comment": "new rice field; newly developed rice field\nwasteland or marshland newly reclaimed as a rice field (Edo period)" },
	{ "question": "新米", "answers": [ "しんまい" ], "comment": "new rice\nnovice; beginner; tyro; newcomer; newbie" },
	{ "question": "新緑", "answers": [ "しんりょく" ], "comment": "fresh verdure; new green leaves" },
	{ "question": "新薬", "answers": [ "しんやく" ], "comment": "new medicine" },
	{ "question": "新装", "answers": [ "しんそう" ], "comment": "redecoration; remodelling; remodeling; refurbishment" },
	{ "question": "新語", "answers": [ "しんご" ], "comment": "new word; neologism; word of recent origin; recent word; modern term" },
	{ "question": "新進", "answers": [ "しんしん" ], "comment": "rising; up-and-coming" },
	{ "question": "新鋭", "answers": [ "しんえい" ], "comment": "young and energetic; up-and-coming; new and excellent; newly produced; up-and-comer" },
	{ "question": "新風", "answers": [ "しんぷう" ], "comment": "new style" },
	{ "question": "方位", "answers": [ "ほうい" ], "comment": "bearing; heading; point of the compass" },
	{ "question": "施工", "answers": [ "せこう", "しこう" ], "comment": "construction; constructing; carrying out; work; formation; workmanship; execution" },
	{ "question": "施政", "answers": [ "しせい" ], "comment": "government; administration; statesmanship" },
	{ "question": "旁", "answers": [ "つくり" ], "comment": "right-hand radical of a character" },
	{ "question": "旅先", "answers": [ "たびさき" ], "comment": "destination; goal (of travel); place one stays during a journey" },
	{ "question": "旅券", "answers": [ "りょけん" ], "comment": "passport" },
	{ "question": "旅団", "answers": [ "りょだん" ], "comment": "brigade" },
	{ "question": "旅客", "answers": [ "りょきゃく", "りょかく" ], "comment": "passenger (transport)" },
	{ "question": "旅立つ", "answers": [ "たびだつ" ], "comment": "to begin a trip; to depart; to embark\nto die; to pass away; to depart this life" },
	{ "question": "旅費", "answers": [ "りょひ" ], "comment": "travel expenses" },
	{ "question": "旋律", "answers": [ "せんりつ" ], "comment": "melody; tune" },
	{ "question": "旋風", "answers": [ "せんぷう", "つむじかぜ", "つじかぜ" ], "comment": "whirlwind\ncommotion; sensation; hullabaloo" },
	{ "question": "旗印", "answers": [ "はたじるし" ], "comment": "(design on a) banner; slogan; emblem (on flag); insignia" },
	{ "question": "旗手", "answers": [ "きしゅ" ], "comment": "standard-bearer" },
	{ "question": "旗揚げ", "answers": [ "はたあげ" ], "comment": "raising an army\nlaunching business" },
	{ "question": "既定", "answers": [ "きてい" ], "comment": "default; established; pre-arranged; fixed; predetermined" },
	{ "question": "既製", "answers": [ "きせい" ], "comment": "ready-made; off the shelf" },
	{ "question": "日の丸", "answers": [ "ひのまる" ], "comment": "outline of the sun (esp. represented as a red circle)\nthe Japanese flag" },
	{ "question": "日の目", "answers": [ "ひのめ" ], "comment": "sunlight" },
	{ "question": "日ソ", "answers": [ "にっソ" ], "comment": "Japanese-Soviet" },
	{ "question": "日出", "answers": [ "にっしゅつ" ], "comment": "sunrise" },
	{ "question": "日刊", "answers": [ "にっかん" ], "comment": "daily issue" },
	{ "question": "日取り", "answers": [ "ひどり" ], "comment": "fixed date; appointed day" },
	{ "question": "日向", "answers": [ "ひなた" ], "comment": "sunny place; in the sun" },
	{ "question": "日和", "answers": [ "ひより" ], "comment": "weather; climatic conditions\nfine weather; clear day\nsituation; state of affairs\nsea conditions; good day for sailing" },
	{ "question": "日報", "answers": [ "にっぽう" ], "comment": "daily report" },
	{ "question": "日夜", "answers": [ "にちや" ], "comment": "day and night; always" },
	{ "question": "日日", "answers": [ "ひにち", "ひび" ], "comment": "the number of days; date" },
	{ "question": "日暮れ", "answers": [ "ひぐれ" ], "comment": "twilight; sunset; dusk; evening" },
	{ "question": "日替り", "answers": [ "ひがわり" ], "comment": "changing every day" },
	{ "question": "日替わり", "answers": [ "ひがわり" ], "comment": "changing every day" },
	{ "question": "日没", "answers": [ "にちぼつ" ], "comment": "sunset" },
	{ "question": "日照", "answers": [ "にっしょう" ], "comment": "sunlight" },
	{ "question": "日給", "answers": [ "にっきゅう" ], "comment": "daily wages" },
	{ "question": "日誌", "answers": [ "にっし" ], "comment": "journal; log" },
	{ "question": "日韓", "answers": [ "にっかん" ], "comment": "Japan and (South) Korea\nJapanese and (South) Korean" },
	{ "question": "日食", "answers": [ "にっしょく" ], "comment": "solar eclipse" },
	{ "question": "旧制", "answers": [ "きゅうせい" ], "comment": "old system; old order" },
	{ "question": "旧姓", "answers": [ "きゅうせい" ], "comment": "one's original family name; maiden name" },
	{ "question": "旧式", "answers": [ "きゅうしき" ], "comment": "old type; old style" },
	{ "question": "旧態", "answers": [ "きゅうたい" ], "comment": "old state of affairs" },
	{ "question": "旧来", "answers": [ "きゅうらい" ], "comment": "traditional; from ancient times; formerly" },
	{ "question": "早", "answers": [ "はや" ], "comment": "already; now; by this time" },
	{ "question": "早く", "answers": [ "はやく" ], "comment": "early; soon\nquickly; swiftly; rapidly; fast" },
	{ "question": "早まる", "answers": [ "はやまる" ], "comment": "to move ahead (three hours, etc.); to move up\nto quicken; to speed up; to gather speed\nto be hasty; to be rash" },
	{ "question": "早める", "answers": [ "はやめる" ], "comment": "to hasten; to quicken; to expedite; to precipitate; to accelerate" },
	{ "question": "早乙女", "answers": [ "さおとめ" ], "comment": "young female rice planter; young girl" },
	{ "question": "早寝", "answers": [ "はやね" ], "comment": "go to bed early" },
	{ "question": "早春", "answers": [ "そうしゅん" ], "comment": "early spring" },
	{ "question": "早瀬", "answers": [ "はやせ" ], "comment": "swift current; rapids" },
	{ "question": "早熟", "answers": [ "そうじゅく" ], "comment": "precocity; early ripening; premature development" },
	{ "question": "早起き", "answers": [ "はやおき" ], "comment": "early rising" },
	{ "question": "早退", "answers": [ "そうたい" ], "comment": "leaving early" },
	{ "question": "旬", "answers": [ "じゅん" ], "comment": "ten-day period" },
	{ "question": "昆虫", "answers": [ "こんちゅう" ], "comment": "insect; bug" },
	{ "question": "昇格", "answers": [ "しょうかく" ], "comment": "raising of status; promotion; advance" },
	{ "question": "昇給", "answers": [ "しょうきゅう" ], "comment": "salary raise" },
	{ "question": "明かす", "answers": [ "あかす" ], "comment": "to pass (e.g. the night); to spend\nto reveal; to divulge" },
	{ "question": "明け暮れ", "answers": [ "あけくれ" ], "comment": "morning and evening; all the time" },
	{ "question": "明年", "answers": [ "みょうねん" ], "comment": "next year" },
	{ "question": "明晩", "answers": [ "みょうばん" ], "comment": "tomorrow evening" },
	{ "question": "明暗", "answers": [ "めいあん" ], "comment": "light and darkness; light and shade" },
	{ "question": "明朗", "answers": [ "めいろう" ], "comment": "cheerful; bright\nclear; clean; honest; fair" },
	{ "question": "明朝", "answers": [ "みょうちょう" ], "comment": "tomorrow morning" },
	{ "question": "明言", "answers": [ "めいげん" ], "comment": "declaration; statement" },
	{ "question": "昔話", "answers": [ "むかしばなし" ], "comment": "old tale; folk tale; legend\nreminiscence" },
	{ "question": "星座", "answers": [ "せいざ" ], "comment": "constellation; star sign; zodiac sign" },
	{ "question": "星空", "answers": [ "ほしぞら" ], "comment": "starry sky" },
	{ "question": "映える", "answers": [ "はえる" ], "comment": "to shine; to look attractive; to look pretty" },
	{ "question": "春休み", "answers": [ "はるやすみ" ], "comment": "spring break; spring vacation" },
	{ "question": "春先", "answers": [ "はるさき" ], "comment": "beginning of spring" },
	{ "question": "春分", "answers": [ "しゅんぶん" ], "comment": "vernal equinox; spring equinox" },
	{ "question": "春季", "answers": [ "しゅんき" ], "comment": "spring season" },
	{ "question": "春闘", "answers": [ "しゅんとう" ], "comment": "spring labor offensive; annual spring wage bargaining round" },
	{ "question": "昨春", "answers": [ "さくしゅん" ], "comment": "last spring; the spring of last year" },
	{ "question": "昨晩", "answers": [ "さくばん" ], "comment": "last night" },
	{ "question": "昨秋", "answers": [ "さくしゅう" ], "comment": "autumn of last year; fall of last year" },
	{ "question": "是正", "answers": [ "ぜせい" ], "comment": "correction; revision; redressing; rectifying" },
	{ "question": "昼下がり", "answers": [ "ひるさがり" ], "comment": "early afternoon" },
	{ "question": "昼前", "answers": [ "ひるまえ" ], "comment": "forenoon; just before noon" },
	{ "question": "昼夜", "answers": [ "ちゅうや" ], "comment": "day and night" },
	{ "question": "昼過ぎ", "answers": [ "ひるすぎ" ], "comment": "just past noon; afternoon" },
	{ "question": "時事", "answers": [ "じじ" ], "comment": "events of the day; current affairs" },
	{ "question": "時価", "answers": [ "じか" ], "comment": "current value; price; market value" },
	{ "question": "時効", "answers": [ "じこう" ], "comment": "statute of limitations; lapse of rights after a period of time; prescription (including acquisitive and extinctive prescription)\nageing; aging" },
	{ "question": "時報", "answers": [ "じほう" ], "comment": "announcement of time; time signal\nnews report; newsletter" },
	{ "question": "時差", "answers": [ "じさ" ], "comment": "time difference" },
	{ "question": "時機", "answers": [ "じき" ], "comment": "opportunity; chance; time; occasion" },
	{ "question": "時流", "answers": [ "じりゅう" ], "comment": "fashion (current) of the times; general drift of affairs" },
	{ "question": "時給", "answers": [ "じきゅう" ], "comment": "hourly pay; hourly wage" },
	{ "question": "時限", "answers": [ "じげん" ], "comment": "(school) period\nperiod or division of time; time limit" },
	{ "question": "時雨", "answers": [ "しぐれ", "じう" ], "comment": "rain shower in late autumn (fall) or early winter\nseasonable rain" },
	{ "question": "晩婚", "answers": [ "ばんこん" ], "comment": "late marriage" },
	{ "question": "普賢", "answers": [ "ふげん" ], "comment": "Samantabhadra (bodhisattva); Universal Compassion" },
	{ "question": "景品", "answers": [ "けいひん" ], "comment": "gift; premium; freebie; giveaway; something additional; an extra\nprize (lottery drawing, pachinko, etc.)\nparty favor (favour)" },
	{ "question": "景観", "answers": [ "けいかん" ], "comment": "scenery" },
	{ "question": "晴天", "answers": [ "せいてん" ], "comment": "fine weather (i.e. little or no clouds); fair weather; clear weather; clear sky; fair skies" },
	{ "question": "暁", "answers": [ "あかつき" ], "comment": "dawn; daybreak\nevent (e.g. \"in the event of ...\"); occasion; occurrence" },
	{ "question": "暇つぶし", "answers": [ "ひまつぶし" ], "comment": "waste of time; killing time" },
	{ "question": "暇潰し", "answers": [ "ひまつぶし" ], "comment": "waste of time; killing time" },
	{ "question": "暖冬", "answers": [ "だんとう" ], "comment": "mild winter; warm winter" },
	{ "question": "暗に", "answers": [ "あんに" ], "comment": "implicitly" },
	{ "question": "暗礁", "answers": [ "あんしょう" ], "comment": "reef; sunken rock" },
	{ "question": "暗雲", "answers": [ "あんうん" ], "comment": "dark clouds" },
	{ "question": "暗黒", "answers": [ "あんこく" ], "comment": "darkness" },
	{ "question": "暫定", "answers": [ "ざんてい" ], "comment": "tentative; temporary" },
	{ "question": "暴動", "answers": [ "ぼうどう" ], "comment": "insurrection; rebellion; revolt; riot; uprising" },
	{ "question": "暴徒", "answers": [ "ぼうと" ], "comment": "insurgent; rioter; mob" },
	{ "question": "暴挙", "answers": [ "ぼうきょ" ], "comment": "violence; reckless action" },
	{ "question": "暴落", "answers": [ "ぼうらく" ], "comment": "slump; crash; heavy fall; decline" },
	{ "question": "暴行", "answers": [ "ぼうこう" ], "comment": "assault; outrage; act of violence\nrape" },
	{ "question": "暴風", "answers": [ "あらし", "ぼうふう" ], "comment": "storm; windstorm; gale" },
	{ "question": "暴風雨", "answers": [ "あらし", "ぼうふうう" ], "comment": "storm; rainstorm" },
	{ "question": "暴騰", "answers": [ "ぼうとう" ], "comment": "sudden rise; sharp rise; boom; skyrocketing" },
	{ "question": "曙", "answers": [ "あけぼの" ], "comment": "dawn; daybreak; beginning" },
	{ "question": "曲", "answers": [ "きょく" ], "comment": "song; tune; composition; piece of music" },
	{ "question": "曲がり", "answers": [ "まがり" ], "comment": "curvature; warp; bend" },
	{ "question": "曲がり角", "answers": [ "まがりかど" ], "comment": "street corner; road turn; bend in the road\nturning point; watershed" },
	{ "question": "曲折", "answers": [ "きょくせつ" ], "comment": "windings; meanderings; complications; twists and turns" },
	{ "question": "曲目", "answers": [ "きょくもく" ], "comment": "program; programme; musical selection; tunes" },
	{ "question": "更改", "answers": [ "こうかい" ], "comment": "renewal; extension; revision" },
	{ "question": "更正", "answers": [ "こうせい" ], "comment": "correction; revision; rectification" },
	{ "question": "更生", "answers": [ "こうせい" ], "comment": "rehabilitation\nrebirth; resuscitation\nreorganization; reorganisation; recycle; reuse" },
	{ "question": "更迭", "answers": [ "こうてつ" ], "comment": "change; shake-up; reshuffle (e.g. of a cabinet); dismissal (e.g. of a minister); exchanging places" },
	{ "question": "書き上げる", "answers": [ "かきあげる" ], "comment": "to write out or down; to finish writing" },
	{ "question": "書き初め", "answers": [ "かきぞめ" ], "comment": "first calligraphy of the year" },
	{ "question": "書き取る", "answers": [ "かきとる" ], "comment": "to write down; to take dictation; to take notes" },
	{ "question": "書き換える", "answers": [ "かきかえる" ], "comment": "to rewrite; to overwrite; to renew; to transfer" },
	{ "question": "書き直す", "answers": [ "かきなおす" ], "comment": "to write out; to make a fair copy; to rewrite" },
	{ "question": "書き言葉", "answers": [ "かきことば" ], "comment": "written word; written language" },
	{ "question": "書き込む", "answers": [ "かきこむ" ], "comment": "to fill in (field, entry, etc.); to fill out (form)\nto post a message (e.g. on a bulletin-board)\nto store" },
	{ "question": "書体", "answers": [ "しょたい" ], "comment": "calligraphic style; calligraphic styles; typeface" },
	{ "question": "書名", "answers": [ "しょめい" ], "comment": "book title" },
	{ "question": "書家", "answers": [ "しょか" ], "comment": "calligrapher; individual with good penmanship" },
	{ "question": "書評", "answers": [ "しょひょう" ], "comment": "book review" },
	{ "question": "替え玉", "answers": [ "かえだま" ], "comment": "substitute; double\nsecond serving (ball) of noodles (to add to previously purchased ramen)" },
	{ "question": "替わり", "answers": [ "かわり" ], "comment": "substitute; replacement; substituting; replacing\nstand-in; proxy; alternate; deputy; relief; successor\ncompensation; exchange; return\nsecond helping; another cup; seconds\nupcoming program; upcoming programme" },
	{ "question": "替わる", "answers": [ "かわる" ], "comment": "to succeed; to relieve; to replace\nto take the place of; to substitute for; to take over for; to represent\nto be exchanged; to change (places with); to switch" },
	{ "question": "最上", "answers": [ "もがみ", "さいじょう" ], "comment": "best" },
	{ "question": "最下", "answers": [ "さいか" ], "comment": "the lowest; the worst" },
	{ "question": "最古", "answers": [ "さいこ" ], "comment": "the oldest" },
	{ "question": "最善", "answers": [ "さいぜん" ], "comment": "the very best" },
	{ "question": "最多", "answers": [ "さいた" ], "comment": "most (numerous)" },
	{ "question": "最少", "answers": [ "さいしょう" ], "comment": "fewest; least; smallest (number); lowest; minimum\nyoungest" },
	{ "question": "最愛", "answers": [ "さいあい" ], "comment": "beloved; dearest" },
	{ "question": "最短", "answers": [ "さいたん" ], "comment": "shortest" },
	{ "question": "最良", "answers": [ "さいりょう" ], "comment": "the best; ideal" },
	{ "question": "最長", "answers": [ "さいちょう" ], "comment": "longest\noldest" },
	{ "question": "月々", "answers": [ "つきづき" ], "comment": "every month; monthly; month by month" },
	{ "question": "月並", "answers": [ "つきなみ", "げつじ" ], "comment": "every month\ntrite; common" },
	{ "question": "月並み", "answers": [ "つきなみ", "げつじ" ], "comment": "every month\ntrite; common" },
	{ "question": "月例", "answers": [ "げつれい" ], "comment": "monthly" },
	{ "question": "月光", "answers": [ "げっこう" ], "comment": "moonlight; moonbeam" },
	{ "question": "月刊", "answers": [ "げっかん" ], "comment": "monthly publication; monthly issue" },
	{ "question": "月初め", "answers": [ "つきはじめ" ], "comment": "beginning of month" },
	{ "question": "月収", "answers": [ "げっしゅう" ], "comment": "monthly income" },
	{ "question": "月夜", "answers": [ "つきよ" ], "comment": "moonlit night" },
	{ "question": "月産", "answers": [ "げっさん" ], "comment": "monthly output (production)" },
	{ "question": "月経", "answers": [ "げっけい" ], "comment": "menstruation; menstrual period" },
	{ "question": "月見", "answers": [ "つきみ" ], "comment": "viewing the moon" },
	{ "question": "月謝", "answers": [ "げっしゃ" ], "comment": "monthly tuition fee" },
	{ "question": "月賦", "answers": [ "げっぷ" ], "comment": "monthly installment (instalment); monthly payment" },
	{ "question": "月間", "answers": [ "げっかん" ], "comment": "month-long period; (during) month" },
	{ "question": "月面", "answers": [ "げつめん" ], "comment": "moon's surface" },
	{ "question": "月額", "answers": [ "げつがく" ], "comment": "monthly amount (sum)" },
	{ "question": "月食", "answers": [ "げっしょく" ], "comment": "lunar eclipse" },
	{ "question": "有事", "answers": [ "ゆうじ" ], "comment": "emergency" },
	{ "question": "有人", "answers": [ "ゆうじん" ], "comment": "manned; occupied; piloted" },
	{ "question": "有償", "answers": [ "ゆうしょう" ], "comment": "compensation; consideration\nfor profit; non-free\nonerous" },
	{ "question": "有志", "answers": [ "ゆうし" ], "comment": "voluntary; volunteer; sympathizer; sympathiser" },
	{ "question": "有数", "answers": [ "ゆうすう" ], "comment": "prominent; leading; foremost; distinguished" },
	{ "question": "有望", "answers": [ "ゆうぼう" ], "comment": "good prospects; full of hope; promising" },
	{ "question": "有毒", "answers": [ "ゆうどく" ], "comment": "poisonous; toxic" },
	{ "question": "有給", "answers": [ "ゆうきゅう" ], "comment": "salaried; with pay\nvacation; (paid) holiday" },
	{ "question": "有線", "answers": [ "ゆうせん" ], "comment": "communicate by wire" },
	{ "question": "有罪", "answers": [ "ゆうざい" ], "comment": "guilt; culpability" },
	{ "question": "有頂天", "answers": [ "うちょうてん" ], "comment": "ecstasy" },
	{ "question": "服役", "answers": [ "ふくえき" ], "comment": "penal servitude; military service" },
	{ "question": "服従", "answers": [ "ふくじゅう" ], "comment": "obedience; submission; resignation" },
	{ "question": "服飾", "answers": [ "ふくしょく" ], "comment": "clothing and accessories; attire" },
	{ "question": "朗報", "answers": [ "ろうほう" ], "comment": "good news" },
	{ "question": "朗読", "answers": [ "ろうどく" ], "comment": "reading aloud; recitation" },
	{ "question": "朝刊", "answers": [ "ちょうかん" ], "comment": "morning newspaper" },
	{ "question": "朝夕", "answers": [ "ちょうせき", "あさゆう" ], "comment": "morning and evening; from morning until night; constantly" },
	{ "question": "朝方", "answers": [ "あさがた" ], "comment": "early morning; early hours; toward morning" },
	{ "question": "朝礼", "answers": [ "ちょうれい" ], "comment": "morning assembly (company, school, etc.); pep talk" },
	{ "question": "朝顔", "answers": [ "あさがお" ], "comment": "Japanese morning glory (Ipomoea nil, Pharbitis nil)\nany funnel shaped object; bell (i.e. of a trumpet); funnel-shaped urinal" },
	{ "question": "朝飯", "answers": [ "あさめし", "あさはん" ], "comment": "breakfast" },
	{ "question": "期日", "answers": [ "きじつ", "きにち" ], "comment": "fixed date; settlement date" },
	{ "question": "期末", "answers": [ "きまつ" ], "comment": "end of term" },
	{ "question": "木の実", "answers": [ "このみ", "きのみ" ], "comment": "nut; fruit; berry" },
	{ "question": "木の葉", "answers": [ "このは", "きのは" ], "comment": "foliage; leaves of trees" },
	{ "question": "木場", "answers": [ "きば" ], "comment": "lumberyard" },
	{ "question": "木工", "answers": [ "もっこう" ], "comment": "woodworking; woodworker; carpenter" },
	{ "question": "木戸", "answers": [ "きど" ], "comment": "wicket gate; wooden door\nentrance to an entertainment venue (i.e. sumo arena, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "木星", "answers": [ "もくせい" ], "comment": "Jupiter (planet)" },
	{ "question": "木枯し", "answers": [ "こがらし" ], "comment": "cold wintry wind" },
	{ "question": "木枯らし", "answers": [ "こがらし" ], "comment": "cold wintry wind" },
	{ "question": "木炭", "answers": [ "もくたん" ], "comment": "charcoal" },
	{ "question": "未亡人", "answers": [ "みぼうじん" ], "comment": "widow" },
	{ "question": "未婚", "answers": [ "みこん" ], "comment": "unmarried" },
	{ "question": "未定", "answers": [ "みてい" ], "comment": "not yet fixed; undecided; pending" },
	{ "question": "未払い", "answers": [ "みばらい", "みはらい" ], "comment": "unpaid; overdue" },
	{ "question": "未明", "answers": [ "みめい" ], "comment": "early dawn; grey of morning; gray of morning" },
	{ "question": "未然", "answers": [ "みぜん" ], "comment": "before it happens; previously" },
	{ "question": "未納", "answers": [ "みのう" ], "comment": "payment default; overdue on a payment" },
	{ "question": "未遂", "answers": [ "みすい" ], "comment": "attempt (e.g. at crime)" },
	{ "question": "未開", "answers": [ "みかい" ], "comment": "savage land; backward region; uncivilized; uncivilised" },
	{ "question": "末広", "answers": [ "すえひろ" ], "comment": "spreading out like an open fan\nbecoming prosperous\nfolding fan; ceremonial folding fan" },
	{ "question": "末日", "answers": [ "まつじつ" ], "comment": "last day (of a month)" },
	{ "question": "末端", "answers": [ "まったん" ], "comment": "end; tip; extremities; terminal" },
	{ "question": "本件", "answers": [ "ほんけん" ], "comment": "this matter; this case" },
	{ "question": "本命", "answers": [ "ほんめい" ], "comment": "favorite (to win); favourite; likely winner\none's heart's desire; first choice" },
	{ "question": "本場", "answers": [ "ほんば" ], "comment": "home; habitat; center; centre; best place\nauthentic; genuine" },
	{ "question": "本塁", "answers": [ "ほんるい" ], "comment": "base; stronghold; main fort\nhome base; home plate" },
	{ "question": "本山", "answers": [ "ほんざん" ], "comment": "head temple; this temple" },
	{ "question": "本島", "answers": [ "ほんとう" ], "comment": "main island\nthis island" },
	{ "question": "本年", "answers": [ "ほんねん" ], "comment": "this (current) year" },
	{ "question": "本店", "answers": [ "ほんだな", "ほんてん" ], "comment": "head office; flagship store; main store\nthis store" },
	{ "question": "本数", "answers": [ "ほんすう" ], "comment": "number of long thin objects (movies, TV programs, baseball games, etc.) (programmes)" },
	{ "question": "本朝", "answers": [ "ほんちょう" ], "comment": "this land; our country; Imperial Court" },
	{ "question": "本業", "answers": [ "ほんぎょう" ], "comment": "principal occupation; core business" },
	{ "question": "本流", "answers": [ "ほんりゅう" ], "comment": "main course (of a river)\nmainstream; main current (e.g. of thought)" },
	{ "question": "本番", "answers": [ "ほんばん" ], "comment": "performance; take; going before an audience or on-air\ngame; season; crucial moment\nactual sexual intercourse (i.e. not simulated); penetration" },
	{ "question": "本省", "answers": [ "ほんしょう" ], "comment": "this ministry; the home office" },
	{ "question": "本箱", "answers": [ "ほんばこ" ], "comment": "bookcase" },
	{ "question": "本籍", "answers": [ "ほんせき" ], "comment": "one's registered domicile (as recorded in the family register); one's legal domicile (as opposed to where one lives)" },
	{ "question": "本紙", "answers": [ "ほんし" ], "comment": "this newspaper" },
	{ "question": "本線", "answers": [ "ほんせん" ], "comment": "main line" },
	{ "question": "本職", "answers": [ "ほんしょく" ], "comment": "principal occupation; main job\nprofessional; an expert; specialist\nI (of a government official, etc.); me" },
	{ "question": "本腰", "answers": [ "ほんごし" ], "comment": "strenuous effort; earnestness; seriousness" },
	{ "question": "本隊", "answers": [ "ほんたい" ], "comment": "main body (of an army); main force\nthese troops" },
	{ "question": "本領", "answers": [ "ほんりょう" ], "comment": "speciality; specialty; characteristic\nproper function; duty\noriginal fief" },
	{ "question": "本館", "answers": [ "ほんかん" ], "comment": "main building" },
	{ "question": "札束", "answers": [ "さつたば" ], "comment": "roll of banknotes" },
	{ "question": "朱", "answers": [ "しゅ", "あけ" ], "comment": "scarlet; red\nblood" },
	{ "question": "机上", "answers": [ "きじょう" ], "comment": "on the desk\ntheoretical; academic" },
	{ "question": "材質", "answers": [ "ざいしつ" ], "comment": "material\nmaterial properties; quality of material" },
	{ "question": "村民", "answers": [ "そんみん" ], "comment": "villager" },
	{ "question": "村長", "answers": [ "むらおさ", "そんちょう" ], "comment": "village headman; village mayor" },
	{ "question": "束ねる", "answers": [ "たばねる", "つかねる" ], "comment": "to tie up in a bundle (e.g. straw, hair, bills, letters); to bundle; to sheathe\nto govern; to manage; to control; to administer\nto fold (one's arms)" },
	{ "question": "束縛", "answers": [ "そくばく" ], "comment": "restraint; restriction; fetters; yoke; shackles\nbinding; confinement with rope" },
	{ "question": "条文", "answers": [ "じょうぶん" ], "comment": "text; provisions (act, treaty)" },
	{ "question": "来", "answers": [ "らい" ], "comment": "next (year, etc.)\nsince (last month, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "来客", "answers": [ "らいかく", "らいきゃく" ], "comment": "visitor; caller" },
	{ "question": "来店", "answers": [ "らいてん" ], "comment": "coming to the store" },
	{ "question": "来春", "answers": [ "らいはる", "らいしゅん" ], "comment": "next spring" },
	{ "question": "来訪", "answers": [ "らいほう" ], "comment": "visit; call" },
	{ "question": "来賓", "answers": [ "らいひん" ], "comment": "guest; visitor; visitor's arrival" },
	{ "question": "東北", "answers": [ "とうほく", "ひがしきた" ], "comment": "north-east\nTohoku (northernmost six prefectures of Honshu)" },
	{ "question": "東口", "answers": [ "ひがしぐち" ], "comment": "east entrance" },
	{ "question": "東宮", "answers": [ "とうぐう" ], "comment": "crown prince" },
	{ "question": "東独", "answers": [ "とうどく" ], "comment": "East Germany (1949-1990)" },
	{ "question": "東経", "answers": [ "とうけい" ], "comment": "east longitude" },
	{ "question": "東邦", "answers": [ "とうほう" ], "comment": "Oriental country; the Orient" },
	{ "question": "東都", "answers": [ "とうと" ], "comment": "the Eastern Capital (now Tokyo); Yedo; Edo" },
	{ "question": "松原", "answers": [ "まつばら" ], "comment": "pine grove" },
	{ "question": "松葉", "answers": [ "まつば" ], "comment": "pine needle" },
	{ "question": "林業", "answers": [ "りんぎょう" ], "comment": "forestry" },
	{ "question": "林立", "answers": [ "りんりつ" ], "comment": "standing close together; bristling (with)" },
	{ "question": "林道", "answers": [ "りんどう" ], "comment": "path through forest; woodland path\nlogging road" },
	{ "question": "林野", "answers": [ "りんや" ], "comment": "forests and fields" },
	{ "question": "果敢", "answers": [ "かかん" ], "comment": "resolute; determined; bold" },
	{ "question": "果樹", "answers": [ "かじゅ" ], "comment": "fruit tree" },
	{ "question": "果汁", "answers": [ "かじゅう" ], "comment": "fruit juice" },
	{ "question": "枝葉", "answers": [ "しよう", "えだは" ], "comment": "branches and leaves; foliage\nunimportant details; nonessentials; side issue; digression" },
	{ "question": "枠内", "answers": [ "わくない" ], "comment": "within the limits (framework, boundaries, price, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "枠外", "answers": [ "わくがい" ], "comment": "beyond (the) limits" },
	{ "question": "枯れ木", "answers": [ "かれき" ], "comment": "dead tree; dry wood" },
	{ "question": "枯れ葉", "answers": [ "かれは" ], "comment": "dead leaf; dry leaves" },
	{ "question": "枯木", "answers": [ "かれき" ], "comment": "dead tree; dry wood" },
	{ "question": "枯葉", "answers": [ "かれは" ], "comment": "dead leaf; dry leaves" },
	{ "question": "架橋", "answers": [ "かきょう" ], "comment": "bridge building; bridge\ncross-linking" },
	{ "question": "柏", "answers": [ "かしわ" ], "comment": "oak; daimyo oak; Japanese emperor oak; Quercus dentata" },
	{ "question": "染め", "answers": [ "そめ" ], "comment": "dyeing; printing" },
	{ "question": "染色", "answers": [ "せんしょく" ], "comment": "staining; stain; dyeing" },
	{ "question": "柴", "answers": [ "しば" ], "comment": "brushwood; firewood" },
	{ "question": "査定", "answers": [ "さてい" ], "comment": "assessment; investigation; audit; revision" },
	{ "question": "査察", "answers": [ "ささつ" ], "comment": "inspection (for compliance); investigation (tax, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "査証", "answers": [ "さしょう" ], "comment": "visa" },
	{ "question": "栄冠", "answers": [ "えいかん" ], "comment": "laurels; garland" },
	{ "question": "栄誉", "answers": [ "えいよ" ], "comment": "honour; honor" },
	{ "question": "校内", "answers": [ "こうない" ], "comment": "within a school" },
	{ "question": "校則", "answers": [ "こうそく" ], "comment": "school regulations" },
	{ "question": "校歌", "answers": [ "こうか" ], "comment": "school song" },
	{ "question": "校門", "answers": [ "こうもん" ], "comment": "school gate" },
	{ "question": "株価", "answers": [ "かぶか" ], "comment": "stock prices" },
	{ "question": "株券", "answers": [ "かぶけん" ], "comment": "stock certificate" },
	{ "question": "核酸", "answers": [ "かくさん" ], "comment": "nucleic acid" },
	{ "question": "根ざす", "answers": [ "ねざす" ], "comment": "to come from; to have roots in" },
	{ "question": "根っこ", "answers": [ "ねっこ" ], "comment": "root; stub; stump" },
	{ "question": "根っ子", "answers": [ "ねっこ" ], "comment": "root; stub; stump" },
	{ "question": "根回し", "answers": [ "ねまわし" ], "comment": "making necessary arrangements; laying the groundwork\ndigging around the roots of a tree (before transplanting)" },
	{ "question": "根幹", "answers": [ "こんかん" ], "comment": "foundation; root; basis; core; fundamentals\nroot and trunk" },
	{ "question": "根絶", "answers": [ "こんぜつ" ], "comment": "eradication; extermination" },
	{ "question": "格上げ", "answers": [ "かくあげ" ], "comment": "status elevation" },
	{ "question": "格付け", "answers": [ "かくづけ" ], "comment": "rating; classification; allocation; grading" },
	{ "question": "格安", "answers": [ "かくやす" ], "comment": "cheap; reasonable" },
	{ "question": "格段", "answers": [ "かくだん" ], "comment": "special; exceptional; remarkable" },
	{ "question": "桂", "answers": [ "かつら" ], "comment": "katsura (Cercidiphyllum japonicum); Japanese Judas tree" },
	{ "question": "案の定", "answers": [ "あんのじょう" ], "comment": "just as one thought; as usual; sure enough" },
	{ "question": "案件", "answers": [ "あんけん" ], "comment": "matter in question; subject; case; item" },
	{ "question": "桑", "answers": [ "くわ" ], "comment": "mulberry (tree)" },
	{ "question": "桑原", "answers": [ "くわばら" ], "comment": "mulberry field" },
	{ "question": "桑田", "answers": [ "そうでん" ], "comment": "mulberry plantation" },
	{ "question": "桟橋", "answers": [ "さんきょう", "さんばし" ], "comment": "wharf; bridge; jetty; pier" },
	{ "question": "梁", "answers": [ "はり" ], "comment": "beam; joist" },
	{ "question": "梅干", "answers": [ "うめぼし" ], "comment": "umeboshi; pickled ume; pickled plum" },
	{ "question": "梅干し", "answers": [ "うめぼし" ], "comment": "umeboshi; pickled ume; pickled plum" },
	{ "question": "梅雨入り", "answers": [ "つゆいり", "にゅうばい" ], "comment": "entering the rainy season; beginning of the rainy season" },
	{ "question": "梅雨明け", "answers": [ "つゆあけ" ], "comment": "the end of the rainy season" },
	{ "question": "棄却", "answers": [ "ききゃく" ], "comment": "rejection; dismissal; abandoning; renunciation; waiver" },
	{ "question": "棄権", "answers": [ "きけん" ], "comment": "abstention (from voting); renunciation (of a right); withdrawal (from a contest)" },
	{ "question": "棋士", "answers": [ "きし" ], "comment": "shogi player; go player" },
	{ "question": "棋聖", "answers": [ "きせい" ], "comment": "great master of go; great master of shogi" },
	{ "question": "棋院", "answers": [ "きいん" ], "comment": "go institution; go club; go hall" },
	{ "question": "棘", "answers": [ "とげ" ], "comment": "thorn; spine; prickle\nsplinter (esp. lodged in one's flesh); hard sharp item (esp. lodged in one's throat, e.g. fish bone)\nbiting words" },
	{ "question": "棚上げ", "answers": [ "たなあげ" ], "comment": "shelving; pigeonholing" },
	{ "question": "棺", "answers": [ "かん", "ひつぎ" ], "comment": "coffin; casket" },
	{ "question": "植林", "answers": [ "しょくりん" ], "comment": "afforestation" },
	{ "question": "植樹", "answers": [ "しょくじゅ" ], "comment": "tree-planting" },
	{ "question": "検問", "answers": [ "けんもん" ], "comment": "inspection; examination; check" },
	{ "question": "検挙", "answers": [ "けんきょ" ], "comment": "arrest; roundup" },
	{ "question": "検疫", "answers": [ "けんえき" ], "comment": "quarantine; medical inspection" },
	{ "question": "検視", "answers": [ "けんし" ], "comment": "autopsy; inquest; investigation of death" },
	{ "question": "検閲", "answers": [ "けんえつ" ], "comment": "censorship; inspection; examination" },
	{ "question": "業種", "answers": [ "ぎょうしゅ" ], "comment": "type of industry" },
	{ "question": "極まる", "answers": [ "きわまる" ], "comment": "to reach an extreme; to reach a limit; to terminate; to come to an end\nextremely\nto be stuck; to be in a dilemma; to be at a loss\nto be decided; to be settled" },
	{ "question": "極右", "answers": [ "きょくう" ], "comment": "far right (in politics); extreme right; ultraconservative" },
	{ "question": "極東", "answers": [ "きょくとう" ], "comment": "Far East" },
	{ "question": "極楽", "answers": [ "ごくらく" ], "comment": "Sukhavati (Amitabha's Pure Land)\nparadise" },
	{ "question": "極秘", "answers": [ "ごくひ" ], "comment": "absolute secrecy" },
	{ "question": "楷書", "answers": [ "かいしょ" ], "comment": "square style of handwriting; printed style of handwriting; block style; standard style" },
	{ "question": "楼閣", "answers": [ "ろうかく" ], "comment": "multistoried building" },
	{ "question": "楽団", "answers": [ "がくだん" ], "comment": "orchestra; band" },
	{ "question": "楽園", "answers": [ "らくえん" ], "comment": "pleasure garden; paradise" },
	{ "question": "楽屋", "answers": [ "がくや" ], "comment": "dressing room; green room; backstage\nbehind the scenes; the inside; inside affairs" },
	{ "question": "楽曲", "answers": [ "がっきょく" ], "comment": "musical composition; tune" },
	{ "question": "楽章", "answers": [ "がくしょう" ], "comment": "(musical) movement" },
	{ "question": "楽観", "answers": [ "らっかん" ], "comment": "optimism" },
	{ "question": "楽譜", "answers": [ "がくふ" ], "comment": "score; sheet music" },
	{ "question": "概算", "answers": [ "がいさん" ], "comment": "approximation; rough estimate" },
	{ "question": "構内", "answers": [ "こうない" ], "comment": "premises; grounds; campus; in-house" },
	{ "question": "様変わり", "answers": [ "さまがわり" ], "comment": "changing completely" },
	{ "question": "標的", "answers": [ "ひょうてき" ], "comment": "target" },
	{ "question": "標語", "answers": [ "ひょうご" ], "comment": "motto; slogan; catchword" },
	{ "question": "標題", "answers": [ "ひょうだい" ], "comment": "title; index; heading; headline; caption" },
	{ "question": "標高", "answers": [ "ひょうこう" ], "comment": "elevation; height above sea level" },
	{ "question": "模型", "answers": [ "もけい" ], "comment": "model; dummy; maquette" },
	{ "question": "模擬", "answers": [ "もぎ" ], "comment": "imitation; sham; mock\nsimulation" },
	{ "question": "模範", "answers": [ "もはん" ], "comment": "exemplar; exemplification; exemplum; model; example" },
	{ "question": "権益", "answers": [ "けんえき" ], "comment": "(one's) interests" },
	{ "question": "横取り", "answers": [ "よこどり" ], "comment": "usurpation; snatching; seizure" },
	{ "question": "横手", "answers": [ "よこて", "よこで" ], "comment": "side; beside\nfeature of a sword blade" },
	{ "question": "横暴", "answers": [ "おうぼう" ], "comment": "violence; oppression; high-handedness; tyranny; despotism" },
	{ "question": "横書き", "answers": [ "よこがき" ], "comment": "writing horizontally" },
	{ "question": "横目", "answers": [ "よこめ" ], "comment": "sidelong glance" },
	{ "question": "横着", "answers": [ "おうちゃく" ], "comment": "laziness; shirking\nimpudent; brazenly dishonest" },
	{ "question": "横綱", "answers": [ "よこづな" ], "comment": "yokozuna (highest rank in sumo); grand champion\nbest in its field; crème de la crème; cream of the crop" },
	{ "question": "横線", "answers": [ "よこせん", "おうせん" ], "comment": "horizontal line; abscissa" },
	{ "question": "横行", "answers": [ "おうこう" ], "comment": "walking sideways; staggering; striding\nbeing rampant; being widespread; being prevalent" },
	{ "question": "横転", "answers": [ "おうてん" ], "comment": "toppling sideways; turning sideways; falling over sideways\nbarrel roll" },
	{ "question": "横道", "answers": [ "よこみち" ], "comment": "byway; side street; cross street\nwrong way; digression" },
	{ "question": "横領", "answers": [ "おうりょう" ], "comment": "embezzlement; misappropriation; usurpation" },
	{ "question": "横顔", "answers": [ "よこがお" ], "comment": "face in profile; profile; face seen from the side" },
	{ "question": "樹脂", "answers": [ "じゅし" ], "comment": "resin; rosin" },
	{ "question": "樹齢", "answers": [ "じゅれい" ], "comment": "age of a tree" },
	{ "question": "樽", "answers": [ "たる" ], "comment": "cask; barrel" },
	{ "question": "橋渡し", "answers": [ "はしわたし" ], "comment": "bridge building; mediation; go-between; intermediary; (through the) good offices (of someone)" },
	{ "question": "橋脚", "answers": [ "きょうきゃく" ], "comment": "bridge pier; pontoon bridge" },
	{ "question": "橘", "answers": [ "たちばな" ], "comment": "tachibana (inedible citrus, Citrus tachibana)" },
	{ "question": "橙色", "answers": [ "とうしょく", "だいだいいろ" ], "comment": "orange color; orange colour" },
	{ "question": "機体", "answers": [ "きたい" ], "comment": "fuselage; airframe" },
	{ "question": "機密", "answers": [ "きみつ" ], "comment": "secrecy; highly classified information" },
	{ "question": "機敏", "answers": [ "きびん" ], "comment": "clever; shrewd; canny; smart; quick; prompt" },
	{ "question": "機材", "answers": [ "きざい" ], "comment": "machine parts; machinery; equipment" },
	{ "question": "機運", "answers": [ "きうん" ], "comment": "opportunity; chance; good time (to do)\ntrend; tendency; momentum" },
	{ "question": "機長", "answers": [ "きちょう" ], "comment": "captain (of an aircraft)" },
	{ "question": "機雷", "answers": [ "きらい" ], "comment": "(sea) mine" },
	{ "question": "機首", "answers": [ "きしゅ" ], "comment": "nose (of plane)" },
	{ "question": "檻", "answers": [ "おり" ], "comment": "cage; pen; jail cell; gaol cell" },
	{ "question": "欠かす", "answers": [ "かかす" ], "comment": "to miss (doing); to fail (to do)" },
	{ "question": "欠乏", "answers": [ "けつぼう" ], "comment": "want; shortage; famine" },
	{ "question": "欠員", "answers": [ "けついん" ], "comment": "vacancy; vacant position" },
	{ "question": "欠場", "answers": [ "けつじょう" ], "comment": "absence; not taking part" },
	{ "question": "欠損", "answers": [ "けっそん" ], "comment": "deficit; shortage; loss; damage" },
	{ "question": "次代", "answers": [ "じだい" ], "comment": "the next era" },
	{ "question": "次女", "answers": [ "じじょ" ], "comment": "second daughter" },
	{ "question": "次官", "answers": [ "じかん" ], "comment": "vice-minister; undersecretary" },
	{ "question": "次席", "answers": [ "じせき" ], "comment": "associate; junior; assistant; runner-up" },
	{ "question": "次期", "answers": [ "じき" ], "comment": "next term; next period\nnext version; next release" },
	{ "question": "次点", "answers": [ "じてん" ], "comment": "runner-up" },
	{ "question": "次長", "answers": [ "じちょう" ], "comment": "vice-chief; vice-director; assistant director; deputy manager" },
	{ "question": "欲張る", "answers": [ "よくばる" ], "comment": "to covet; to lust for" },
	{ "question": "欲深", "answers": [ "よくぶか", "よくふか" ], "comment": "avarice; covetousness; greed" },
	{ "question": "欺く", "answers": [ "あざむく" ], "comment": "to deceive; to delude; to trick; to fool\nto be as ... as ... (e.g. \"as bright as day\", \"as beautiful as a rose\")" },
	{ "question": "歌人", "answers": [ "かじん" ], "comment": "poet (of tanka poems)" },
	{ "question": "歌劇", "answers": [ "かげき" ], "comment": "opera" },
	{ "question": "歌合", "answers": [ "うたあわせ" ], "comment": "poetry contest" },
	{ "question": "歌唱", "answers": [ "かしょう" ], "comment": "song; singing" },
	{ "question": "歌声", "answers": [ "かせい", "うたごえ" ], "comment": "singing voice; (sound of) singing" },
	{ "question": "歌曲", "answers": [ "かきょく" ], "comment": "melody; tune; song" },
	{ "question": "歌舞伎", "answers": [ "かぶき" ], "comment": "kabuki; Japanese classical drama" },
	{ "question": "歌集", "answers": [ "かしゅう" ], "comment": "anthology; book of poetry" },
	{ "question": "歓喜", "answers": [ "かんき" ], "comment": "delight; great joy" },
	{ "question": "歓声", "answers": [ "かんせい" ], "comment": "cheer; shout of joy" },
	{ "question": "止め金", "answers": [ "とめがね" ], "comment": "clasp; snap fastener" },
	{ "question": "正則", "answers": [ "せいそく" ], "comment": "correct; proper; formal; regular; systematic; normal" },
	{ "question": "正座", "answers": [ "せいざ" ], "comment": "seiza; kneeling with the tops of the feet flat on the floor, and sitting on the soles" },
	{ "question": "正教", "answers": [ "せいきょう" ], "comment": "orthodoxy; (Greek) orthodox church" },
	{ "question": "正装", "answers": [ "せいそう" ], "comment": "full dress; formal dress; uniform" },
	{ "question": "正論", "answers": [ "せいろん" ], "comment": "sound argument; fair argument; just reasoning" },
	{ "question": "正道", "answers": [ "せいどう", "しょうどう" ], "comment": "path of righteousness; path of duty; right track; correct path" },
	{ "question": "武道", "answers": [ "ぶどう" ], "comment": "martial arts; military arts; Bushido" },
	{ "question": "歩", "answers": [ "ほ" ], "comment": "step; stride\ncounter for steps" },
	{ "question": "歩き回る", "answers": [ "あるきまわる" ], "comment": "to walk about; to walk to and fro; to pace around" },
	{ "question": "歩み寄り", "answers": [ "あゆみより" ], "comment": "compromise; concession" },
	{ "question": "歩み寄る", "answers": [ "あゆみよる" ], "comment": "to compromise; to meet halfway\nto step up to; to walk up to; to approach" },
	{ "question": "歩兵", "answers": [ "ほへい" ], "comment": "infantry; infantryman; foot soldier" },
	{ "question": "歩合", "answers": [ "ぶあい" ], "comment": "rate; ratio; percentage\ncommission; poundage; percentage" },
	{ "question": "歩調", "answers": [ "ほちょう" ], "comment": "pace; step; cadence" },
	{ "question": "歯ごたえ", "answers": [ "はごたえ" ], "comment": "feel (consistency) of food while being chewed" },
	{ "question": "歯切れ", "answers": [ "はぎれ" ], "comment": "feel when biting\nmanner of enunciation" },
	{ "question": "歯止め", "answers": [ "はどめ" ], "comment": "brake; skid; pawl\nrestraint; curtailment; self-imposed limit; check" },
	{ "question": "歯痒い", "answers": [ "はがゆい" ], "comment": "impatient; tantalized; tantalised; irritated; chagrined; chagrinned; vexed" },
	{ "question": "歳入", "answers": [ "さいにゅう" ], "comment": "annual revenue (government); annual income (government); budget receipts" },
	{ "question": "歳出", "answers": [ "さいしゅつ" ], "comment": "annual expenditure" },
	{ "question": "歳暮", "answers": [ "せいぼ" ], "comment": "year-end gift\nend of the year; year end" },
	{ "question": "歳末", "answers": [ "さいまつ" ], "comment": "year end" },
	{ "question": "歴然", "answers": [ "れきぜん" ], "comment": "evident; plain; distinct; clear" },
	{ "question": "歴訪", "answers": [ "れきほう" ], "comment": "round of calls; tour of visitation" },
	{ "question": "死に体", "answers": [ "しにたい" ], "comment": "losing posture; falling position from which it is impossible to recover\nlame duck\nhopeless situation" },
	{ "question": "死人", "answers": [ "しびと", "しにん" ], "comment": "corpse; dead person" },
	{ "question": "死因", "answers": [ "しいん" ], "comment": "cause of death" },
	{ "question": "死活", "answers": [ "しかつ" ], "comment": "life and death; life or death" },
	{ "question": "死球", "answers": [ "しきゅう" ], "comment": "pitch that hits the batter" },
	{ "question": "殊勲", "answers": [ "しゅくん" ], "comment": "meritorious deeds" },
	{ "question": "残存", "answers": [ "ざんぞん", "ざんそん" ], "comment": "remaining; survival; residual" },
	{ "question": "残暑", "answers": [ "ざんしょ" ], "comment": "late summer heat; lingering summer heat" },
	{ "question": "残留", "answers": [ "ざんりゅう" ], "comment": "staying behind; remaining; residual" },
	{ "question": "残虐", "answers": [ "ざんぎゃく" ], "comment": "cruelty; brutality" },
	{ "question": "残高", "answers": [ "ざんだか" ], "comment": "(bank) balance; remainder" },
	{ "question": "殴打", "answers": [ "おうだ" ], "comment": "hit; strike; blow" },
	{ "question": "段取り", "answers": [ "だんどり" ], "comment": "programme; program; plans; arrangements" },
	{ "question": "殺傷", "answers": [ "さっしょう" ], "comment": "killing and wounding; casualties; bloodshed" },
	{ "question": "殺到", "answers": [ "さっとう" ], "comment": "rush; flood; deluge" },
	{ "question": "殺意", "answers": [ "さつい" ], "comment": "intent to kill; intent to murder; urge to kill; murderous impulse" },
	{ "question": "殺気", "answers": [ "さっき" ], "comment": "thirst for blood; bloodlust; determination to kill" },
	{ "question": "殺菌", "answers": [ "さっきん" ], "comment": "sterilization; sterilisation; disinfection" },
	{ "question": "殿下", "answers": [ "でんか" ], "comment": "your Highness; his Highness; her Highness" },
	{ "question": "殿堂", "answers": [ "でんどう" ], "comment": "palace; hall; shrine; temple; sanctuary\nhall of fame" },
	{ "question": "母体", "answers": [ "ぼたい" ], "comment": "mother's body, esp. when pregnant or after giving birth\nparent body; parent organization; heartland" },
	{ "question": "母国", "answers": [ "ぼこく" ], "comment": "one's homeland" },
	{ "question": "母性", "answers": [ "ぼせい" ], "comment": "motherhood; maternity" },
	{ "question": "母校", "answers": [ "ぼこう" ], "comment": "alma mater" },
	{ "question": "毒性", "answers": [ "どくせい" ], "comment": "toxicity; virulence\ntoxic; virulent; poisonous" },
	{ "question": "毒薬", "answers": [ "どくやく" ], "comment": "poison" },
	{ "question": "比喩", "answers": [ "ひゆ" ], "comment": "simile; metaphor; allegory; parable" },
	{ "question": "氏族", "answers": [ "しぞく" ], "comment": "clan; family" },
	{ "question": "民事", "answers": [ "みんじ" ], "comment": "civil affairs; civil case" },
	{ "question": "民兵", "answers": [ "みんぺい" ], "comment": "militia; militiaman" },
	{ "question": "民宿", "answers": [ "みんしゅく" ], "comment": "pension; guesthouse; bed and breakfast; private home providing lodging for travelers (travellers)" },
	{ "question": "民意", "answers": [ "みんい" ], "comment": "popular will" },
	{ "question": "民放", "answers": [ "みんぽう" ], "comment": "commercial broadcast" },
	{ "question": "民政", "answers": [ "みんせい" ], "comment": "democracy; civil government" },
	{ "question": "民生", "answers": [ "みんせい" ], "comment": "consumer\ncivilian\npeople's welfare or livelihood" },
	{ "question": "民芸", "answers": [ "みんげい" ], "comment": "folk craft; folk art" },
	{ "question": "民話", "answers": [ "みんわ" ], "comment": "folk tale; folktale; folk story; folklore" },
	{ "question": "民需", "answers": [ "みんじゅ" ], "comment": "private demand" },
	{ "question": "気づかれ", "answers": [ "きづかれ" ], "comment": "mental fatigue; worry; boredom" },
	{ "question": "気まぐれ", "answers": [ "きまぐれ" ], "comment": "whim; caprice; whimsy; fickle; moody; uneven temper" },
	{ "question": "気まま", "answers": [ "きまま" ], "comment": "willful; wilful; selfish; self-centered; egoistic\ncarefree; do-as-you-please; freewheeling; free spirited" },
	{ "question": "気兼ね", "answers": [ "きがね" ], "comment": "constraint; reserve; feeling hesitant; being afraid of troubling someone" },
	{ "question": "気前", "answers": [ "きまえ" ], "comment": "generosity" },
	{ "question": "気勢", "answers": [ "きせい" ], "comment": "fervour; fervor; vigour; vigor; ardour; ardor; spirit" },
	{ "question": "気心", "answers": [ "きごころ" ], "comment": "temper; disposition" },
	{ "question": "気性", "answers": [ "きしょう" ], "comment": "disposition; temperament" },
	{ "question": "気掛かり", "answers": [ "きがかり" ], "comment": "anxiety; concern; worry" },
	{ "question": "気概", "answers": [ "きがい" ], "comment": "strong spirit; mettle; backbone; guts; fighting spirit" },
	{ "question": "気球", "answers": [ "ききゅう" ], "comment": "balloon; blimp" },
	{ "question": "気筒", "answers": [ "きとう" ], "comment": "cylinder" },
	{ "question": "気絶", "answers": [ "きぜつ" ], "comment": "faint; swoon" },
	{ "question": "気象", "answers": [ "きしょう" ], "comment": "weather; climate\ndisposition; temperament" },
	{ "question": "気負い", "answers": [ "きおい" ], "comment": "eagerness; enthusiasm; fervor; excitement; fighting spirit; fighting mood" },
	{ "question": "気軽", "answers": [ "きがる" ], "comment": "carefree; buoyant; lighthearted; sprightly\nease" },
	{ "question": "気迫", "answers": [ "きはく" ], "comment": "spirit; soul; drive; vigor; vigour" },
	{ "question": "気遣い", "answers": [ "きづかい" ], "comment": "consideration; concern; fear; worry; solicitude" },
	{ "question": "気配り", "answers": [ "きくばり" ], "comment": "care; attentiveness; attention; consideration (for others); solicitude" },
	{ "question": "気鋭", "answers": [ "きえい" ], "comment": "spirited; energetic" },
	{ "question": "気難しい", "answers": [ "きむづかしい", "きむずかしい" ], "comment": "hard to please; moody; crusty; fastidious" },
	{ "question": "水上", "answers": [ "すいじょう" ], "comment": "aquatic; on the water" },
	{ "question": "水位", "answers": [ "すいい" ], "comment": "water level" },
	{ "question": "水利", "answers": [ "すいり" ], "comment": "water supply; irrigation; water transportation" },
	{ "question": "水割り", "answers": [ "みずわり" ], "comment": "alcohol (usu. whiskey or shochu) diluted with water\nwatered" },
	{ "question": "水力", "answers": [ "すいりょく" ], "comment": "hydraulic power; water power" },
	{ "question": "水域", "answers": [ "すいいき" ], "comment": "waters; water area" },
	{ "question": "水増し", "answers": [ "みずまし" ], "comment": "dilution; watering down\ninflation (of budget, claim, etc.); padding" },
	{ "question": "水害", "answers": [ "すいがい" ], "comment": "water damage; flood disaster" },
	{ "question": "水揚げ", "answers": [ "みずあげ" ], "comment": "landing; unloading (e.g. a ship)\ncatch (of fish); takings\nsales (of a shop)\ndefloration (e.g. of a geisha)\npreservation (of cut flowers, in ikebana)" },
	{ "question": "水死", "answers": [ "すいし" ], "comment": "death by drowning" },
	{ "question": "水気", "answers": [ "すいき", "みずけ" ], "comment": "moisture; dampness; vapor; vapour\ndropsy; edema; oedema" },
	{ "question": "水洗", "answers": [ "すいせん" ], "comment": "rinsing with water; flushing" },
	{ "question": "水深", "answers": [ "すいしん" ], "comment": "depth of water" },
	{ "question": "水温", "answers": [ "すいおん" ], "comment": "water temperature" },
	{ "question": "水源", "answers": [ "すいげん" ], "comment": "source of river; fountainhead" },
	{ "question": "水爆", "answers": [ "すいばく" ], "comment": "hydrogen bomb" },
	{ "question": "水稲", "answers": [ "すいとう" ], "comment": "wet-land rice" },
	{ "question": "水系", "answers": [ "すいけい" ], "comment": "water system; river system; drainage system" },
	{ "question": "水臭い", "answers": [ "みずくさい" ], "comment": "stand-offish; distant; not frank; reserved\nwatery (alcohol, coffee, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "水色", "answers": [ "みずいろ" ], "comment": "light blue; pale blue; aqua" },
	{ "question": "水質", "answers": [ "すいしつ" ], "comment": "water quality" },
	{ "question": "水路", "answers": [ "すいろ" ], "comment": "waterway; canal; channel; watercourse; aqueduct\nswimming pool lane" },
	{ "question": "水辺", "answers": [ "すいへん", "みずべ" ], "comment": "waterside; waterfront" },
	{ "question": "水量", "answers": [ "すいりょう" ], "comment": "quantity or volume of water" },
	{ "question": "水銀", "answers": [ "すいぎん" ], "comment": "mercury (Hg)" },
	{ "question": "水鳥", "answers": [ "みずとり", "すいちょう", "みずどり" ], "comment": "waterfowl; water bird; shorebird" },
	{ "question": "氷山", "answers": [ "ひょうざん" ], "comment": "iceberg" },
	{ "question": "氷河", "answers": [ "ひょうが" ], "comment": "glacier" },
	{ "question": "永代", "answers": [ "えいたい" ], "comment": "permanence; eternity" },
	{ "question": "永住", "answers": [ "えいじゅう" ], "comment": "permanent residence" },
	{ "question": "永続", "answers": [ "えいぞく" ], "comment": "permanence; continuation" },
	{ "question": "氾濫", "answers": [ "はんらん" ], "comment": "overflowing; flood; inundation; deluge\noversupply; plethora" },
	{ "question": "求刑", "answers": [ "きゅうけい" ], "comment": "recommended sentence; prosecution's demand for punishment" },
	{ "question": "求職", "answers": [ "きゅうしょく" ], "comment": "job hunting; seeking employment" },
	{ "question": "汎", "answers": [ "はん" ], "comment": "pan-" },
	{ "question": "汎用", "answers": [ "はんよう" ], "comment": "generic; general purpose; all-purpose" },
	{ "question": "汚名", "answers": [ "おめい" ], "comment": "stigma; dishonour; dishonor; infamy" },
	{ "question": "汚水", "answers": [ "おすい" ], "comment": "filthy water; sewage" },
	{ "question": "汚濁", "answers": [ "おだく" ], "comment": "pollution; contamination; corruption; graft" },
	{ "question": "汚職", "answers": [ "おしょく" ], "comment": "corruption" },
	{ "question": "汲み取る", "answers": [ "くみとる" ], "comment": "to scoop out; to pump out\nto understand; to surmise" },
	{ "question": "決", "answers": [ "けつ" ], "comment": "decision; vote" },
	{ "question": "決する", "answers": [ "けっする" ], "comment": "to decide; to determine" },
	{ "question": "決め", "answers": [ "きめ" ], "comment": "agreement; rule" },
	{ "question": "決め手", "answers": [ "きめて" ], "comment": "decider; person who decides\ndeciding factor; clincher; trump card; winning move" },
	{ "question": "決別", "answers": [ "けつべつ" ], "comment": "separation; farewell; parting" },
	{ "question": "決勝", "answers": [ "けっしょう" ], "comment": "decision of a contest; finals (in sports)" },
	{ "question": "決裁", "answers": [ "けっさい" ], "comment": "sanction; approval" },
	{ "question": "決裂", "answers": [ "けつれつ" ], "comment": "breakdown; rupture" },
	{ "question": "決起", "answers": [ "けっき" ], "comment": "rising to action; standing up against; jumping to one's feet" },
	{ "question": "汽笛", "answers": [ "きてき" ], "comment": "steam whistle" },
	{ "question": "汽船", "answers": [ "きせん" ], "comment": "steamship; steamboat; steamer" },
	{ "question": "沈下", "answers": [ "ちんか" ], "comment": "sinking; subsidence" },
	{ "question": "沈没", "answers": [ "ちんぼつ" ], "comment": "sinking; foundering; going down; submersion\ngetting dead drunk\nhaving too much fun (esp. in a red-light district, etc.) and missing work or neglecting one's duties\nstaying in one place for a long time" },
	{ "question": "沈着", "answers": [ "ちんちゃく" ], "comment": "settling or depositing (at the bottom of something); deposition; pigmentation\ncomposure; calmness" },
	{ "question": "沖合", "answers": [ "おきあい" ], "comment": "coast; offing; offshore" },
	{ "question": "沖合い", "answers": [ "おきあい" ], "comment": "coast; offing; offshore" },
	{ "question": "没収", "answers": [ "ぼっしゅう" ], "comment": "forfeiture; seizure; confiscation; impounding" },
	{ "question": "没後", "answers": [ "ぼつご" ], "comment": "after death; posthumously" },
	{ "question": "没落", "answers": [ "ぼつらく" ], "comment": "ruin; fall; collapse" },
	{ "question": "没頭", "answers": [ "ぼっとう" ], "comment": "immersing oneself; devoting oneself; giving oneself up entirely to" },
	{ "question": "河口", "answers": [ "かこう", "かわぐち" ], "comment": "mouth of river; estuary" },
	{ "question": "河岸", "answers": [ "かがん", "かし", "かわぎし" ], "comment": "riverbank; riverside\nfish market" },
	{ "question": "油井", "answers": [ "ゆせい" ], "comment": "oil well" },
	{ "question": "油彩", "answers": [ "ゆさい" ], "comment": "oil painting" },
	{ "question": "油田", "answers": [ "ゆでん" ], "comment": "oil field" },
	{ "question": "油絵", "answers": [ "あぶらえ" ], "comment": "oil painting" },
	{ "question": "治水", "answers": [ "ちすい" ], "comment": "flood control" },
	{ "question": "治癒", "answers": [ "ちゆ" ], "comment": "healing; cure; recovery" },
	{ "question": "治験", "answers": [ "ちけん" ], "comment": "clinical trial" },
	{ "question": "沿い", "answers": [ "ぞい" ], "comment": "along" },
	{ "question": "沿海", "answers": [ "えんかい" ], "comment": "coast; shore; inshore; coastal waters" },
	{ "question": "沿線", "answers": [ "えんせん" ], "comment": "along railway line" },
	{ "question": "沿道", "answers": [ "えんどう" ], "comment": "route; course; roadside" },
	{ "question": "泊まり", "answers": [ "とまり" ], "comment": "overnight stay; stopover\ninn; hotel\nanchorage\nnight duty" },
	{ "question": "法制", "answers": [ "ほうせい" ], "comment": "legislation; laws" },
	{ "question": "法務", "answers": [ "ほうむ" ], "comment": "judicial affairs\nclerical duty (in a temple)" },
	{ "question": "法外", "answers": [ "ほうがい" ], "comment": "exorbitant; outrageous; ridiculous; absurd; excessive; inordinate; extravagant; immoderate" },
	{ "question": "法文", "answers": [ "ほうぶん" ], "comment": "text of the law" },
	{ "question": "法王", "answers": [ "ほうおう" ], "comment": "Pope" },
	{ "question": "法相", "answers": [ "ほうしょう" ], "comment": "Minister of Justice" },
	{ "question": "法要", "answers": [ "ほうよう" ], "comment": "Buddhist memorial service" },
	{ "question": "法規", "answers": [ "ほうき" ], "comment": "the law; laws and regulations" },
	{ "question": "波乱", "answers": [ "はらん" ], "comment": "disturbance; trouble; ups and downs" },
	{ "question": "波及", "answers": [ "はきゅう" ], "comment": "spread; extension; influence; aftereffect; ripple" },
	{ "question": "波紋", "answers": [ "はもん" ], "comment": "ripple; ring on the water\nrepercussions\nJapanese slit drum; instrument made of iron with slits on top; makes a rippling sound" },
	{ "question": "波長", "answers": [ "はちょう" ], "comment": "wavelength" },
	{ "question": "泣き顔", "answers": [ "なきがお" ], "comment": "tear-stained face" },
	{ "question": "泥沼", "answers": [ "どろぬま", "ドロぬま", "でいしょう" ], "comment": "bog; marsh; swamp; quagmire; morass\nquandary; dire situation from which one cannot extricate oneself; imbroglio" },
	{ "question": "洋上", "answers": [ "ようじょう" ], "comment": "on the sea or ocean" },
	{ "question": "洋室", "answers": [ "ようしつ" ], "comment": "Western-style room" },
	{ "question": "洋式", "answers": [ "ようしき" ], "comment": "Western style; foreign style" },
	{ "question": "洋書", "answers": [ "ようしょ" ], "comment": "Western book" },
	{ "question": "洋楽", "answers": [ "ようがく" ], "comment": "Western music; European music" },
	{ "question": "洋画", "answers": [ "ようが" ], "comment": "Western painting\nWestern film; Western movie" },
	{ "question": "洋裁", "answers": [ "ようさい" ], "comment": "(Western) dressmaking" },
	{ "question": "洋酒", "answers": [ "ようしゅ" ], "comment": "Western wine and spirits; Western liquor" },
	{ "question": "洋間", "answers": [ "ようま" ], "comment": "Western-style room" },
	{ "question": "洋風", "answers": [ "ようふう" ], "comment": "Western style" },
	{ "question": "洋食", "answers": [ "ようしょく" ], "comment": "Western cooking; Western-style meal; Western-style food\nJapanized Western cuisine" },
	{ "question": "洒落", "answers": [ "しゃれ" ], "comment": "joke; pun; witticism\nsmartly dressed; stylish; fashion-conscious; refined" },
	{ "question": "洒落る", "answers": [ "しゃれる" ], "comment": "to dress stylishly\nto joke; to play on words" },
	{ "question": "洗い上げる", "answers": [ "あらいあげる" ], "comment": "to finish washing; to wash well; to investigate thoroughly" },
	{ "question": "洗い物", "answers": [ "あらいもの" ], "comment": "washing (esp. dishes and laundry)" },
	{ "question": "洗浄", "answers": [ "せんじょう" ], "comment": "washing; cleaning; laundering" },
	{ "question": "洗礼", "answers": [ "せんれい" ], "comment": "baptism" },
	{ "question": "洞", "answers": [ "ほら" ], "comment": "cave; den; grotto" },
	{ "question": "洞察", "answers": [ "どうさつ" ], "comment": "discernment; insight" },
	{ "question": "津波", "answers": [ "つなみ" ], "comment": "tsunami; tidal wave" },
	{ "question": "活況", "answers": [ "かっきょう" ], "comment": "activity; briskness; prosperity" },
	{ "question": "活路", "answers": [ "かつろ" ], "comment": "means of survival; means of escape" },
	{ "question": "派兵", "answers": [ "はへい" ], "comment": "dispatch of troops; despatch of troops" },
	{ "question": "派生", "answers": [ "はせい" ], "comment": "derivation" },
	{ "question": "派閥", "answers": [ "はばつ" ], "comment": "clique; faction" },
	{ "question": "流", "answers": [ "りゅう" ], "comment": "fashion; way; style; manner\nschool (of thought)\nclass; rank; rate\ncurrent (electrical, water, etc.); flow; stream" },
	{ "question": "流し", "answers": [ "ながし" ], "comment": "sink (e.g. kitchen)\ncruising (e.g. taxi); strolling (entertainer, musician, etc.)\nwashing area in a Japanese-style bath\nback-washing service (in a public bath)\nfloating (something on water); setting adrift; washing away" },
	{ "question": "流暢", "answers": [ "りゅうちょう" ], "comment": "fluent (language skill); flowing" },
	{ "question": "流派", "answers": [ "りゅうは" ], "comment": "school (e.g. of ikebana)" },
	{ "question": "流用", "answers": [ "りゅうよう" ], "comment": "diversion; appropriation (e.g. of funds); misappropriation\nre-use (e.g. old computer parts); recycling" },
	{ "question": "流血", "answers": [ "りゅうけつ" ], "comment": "bloodshed" },
	{ "question": "流行歌", "answers": [ "りゅうこうか" ], "comment": "popular song; hit song" },
	{ "question": "浄水", "answers": [ "じょうすい" ], "comment": "clean water" },
	{ "question": "浅はか", "answers": [ "あさはか" ], "comment": "shallow; superficial; thoughtless; short-sighted; foolish; silly" },
	{ "question": "浜辺", "answers": [ "はまべ" ], "comment": "beach; foreshore" },
	{ "question": "浪費", "answers": [ "ろうひ" ], "comment": "waste; extravagance" },
	{ "question": "浮かれる", "answers": [ "うかれる" ], "comment": "to make merry; to be festive" },
	{ "question": "浮き", "answers": [ "うき" ], "comment": "floating; buoyancy\nfishing float; bobber\nbuoy\nlifebuoy; life belt; float; rubber ring" },
	{ "question": "浮き彫り", "answers": [ "うきぼり" ], "comment": "relief; embossed carving\nbringing to the fore; throwing something into relief" },
	{ "question": "浮揚", "answers": [ "ふよう" ], "comment": "floating (in the air)" },
	{ "question": "浮沈", "answers": [ "ふちん" ], "comment": "floating and sinking; rise and fall; ebb and flow; ups and downs" },
	{ "question": "浮遊", "answers": [ "ふゆう" ], "comment": "floating; wandering; suspension" },
	{ "question": "浴場", "answers": [ "よくじょう" ], "comment": "bath; bathhouse; bathroom" },
	{ "question": "浴室", "answers": [ "よくしつ" ], "comment": "bathroom" },
	{ "question": "浴槽", "answers": [ "よくそう" ], "comment": "bathtub" },
	{ "question": "海中", "answers": [ "かいちゅう" ], "comment": "in the sea" },
	{ "question": "海域", "answers": [ "かいいき" ], "comment": "area of ocean" },
	{ "question": "海峡", "answers": [ "かいきょう" ], "comment": "channel (e.g. between two land masses); strait" },
	{ "question": "海底", "answers": [ "かいてい", "うなぞこ" ], "comment": "bottom of the ocean\nundersea; submarine" },
	{ "question": "海戦", "answers": [ "かいせん" ], "comment": "naval battle" },
	{ "question": "海抜", "answers": [ "かいばつ" ], "comment": "height above sea level" },
	{ "question": "海流", "answers": [ "かいりゅう" ], "comment": "ocean current" },
	{ "question": "海浜", "answers": [ "かいひん" ], "comment": "seaside; beachside" },
	{ "question": "海藻", "answers": [ "かいそう" ], "comment": "seaweed" },
	{ "question": "海辺", "answers": [ "かいへん", "うみべ" ], "comment": "beach; seashore; seaside; coast" },
	{ "question": "海運", "answers": [ "かいうん" ], "comment": "maritime; marine transportation" },
	{ "question": "海道", "answers": [ "かいどう" ], "comment": "sea route" },
	{ "question": "海難", "answers": [ "かいなん" ], "comment": "accident at sea; sea disaster; shipwreck" },
	{ "question": "浸水", "answers": [ "しんすい" ], "comment": "inundation; submersion; flood" },
	{ "question": "消印", "answers": [ "けしいん" ], "comment": "postmark; (postal) cancellation mark" },
	{ "question": "消火", "answers": [ "しょうか" ], "comment": "fire fighting; extinguishing a fire" },
	{ "question": "消灯", "answers": [ "しょうとう" ], "comment": "putting out the light; switching off the light" },
	{ "question": "液化", "answers": [ "えきか" ], "comment": "liquefaction" },
	{ "question": "涼風", "answers": [ "すずかぜ", "りょうふう" ], "comment": "cool breeze; refreshing breeze" },
	{ "question": "深み", "answers": [ "ふかみ" ], "comment": "depth; deep place" },
	{ "question": "深層", "answers": [ "しんそう" ], "comment": "depths; deep level" },
	{ "question": "深山", "answers": [ "しんざん", "みやま" ], "comment": "mountain recess; deep in the mountains" },
	{ "question": "深海", "answers": [ "しんかい" ], "comment": "deep sea; depths of the sea; ocean depths" },
	{ "question": "混ぜ合わす", "answers": [ "まぜあわす" ], "comment": "to mix together; to blend; to compound" },
	{ "question": "混入", "answers": [ "こんにゅう" ], "comment": "mixing; adding; adulteration" },
	{ "question": "混成", "answers": [ "こんせい" ], "comment": "mixed (e.g. team, chorus)" },
	{ "question": "混戦", "answers": [ "こんせん" ], "comment": "free-for-all fight" },
	{ "question": "混血", "answers": [ "こんけつ" ], "comment": "mixed race; mixed parentage" },
	{ "question": "混迷", "answers": [ "こんめい" ], "comment": "turmoil; chaos; confusion" },
	{ "question": "添乗", "answers": [ "てんじょう" ], "comment": "accompanying; escorting" },
	{ "question": "添付", "answers": [ "てんぷ" ], "comment": "attachment (e.g. email); appendix (e.g. of a report, document, etc); annex; appendage; annexure" },
	{ "question": "添削", "answers": [ "てんさく" ], "comment": "correction; looking over; touching up" },
	{ "question": "添加", "answers": [ "てんか" ], "comment": "addition; annexing" },
	{ "question": "清らか", "answers": [ "きよらか" ], "comment": "clean; pure; chaste" },
	{ "question": "清新", "answers": [ "せいしん" ], "comment": "fresh; new" },
	{ "question": "清流", "answers": [ "せいりゅう" ], "comment": "clear stream" },
	{ "question": "清浄", "answers": [ "せいじょう", "しょうじょう" ], "comment": "pure; clean; purity" },
	{ "question": "清涼", "answers": [ "せいりょう" ], "comment": "cool; refreshing" },
	{ "question": "清算", "answers": [ "せいさん" ], "comment": "settlement (financial); squaring accounts; clearing debts\nliquidation\nending (a relationship); breaking up (with); burying (the past); redeeming (one's faults)" },
	{ "question": "清貧", "answers": [ "せいひん" ], "comment": "honourable poverty; honorable poverty" },
	{ "question": "清酒", "answers": [ "せいしゅ" ], "comment": "refined sake" },
	{ "question": "渇き", "answers": [ "かわき" ], "comment": "thirst" },
	{ "question": "渇水", "answers": [ "かっすい" ], "comment": "water shortage" },
	{ "question": "渉外", "answers": [ "しょうがい" ], "comment": "public relations; client liaison; client relations" },
	{ "question": "渋い", "answers": [ "しぶい" ], "comment": "astringent; bitter; puckery; rough; harsh; tart\naustere; elegant (and unobtrusive); refined; quiet (and simple); sober; sombre; subdued; tasteful (in a quiet way); understated\nsour (look); glum; grim; sullen; sulky\nstingy; tight-fisted" },
	{ "question": "渋る", "answers": [ "しぶる" ], "comment": "to hesitate; to hold back; to balk; to falter\nto be reluctant; to be unwilling; to begrudge\nto have loose painful bowel movement; to suffer from tenesmus" },
	{ "question": "渋面", "answers": [ "じゅうめん", "しぶづら", "しぶつら" ], "comment": "grimace; sullen face" },
	{ "question": "渓谷", "answers": [ "けいこく" ], "comment": "valley; ravine; canyon" },
	{ "question": "渚", "answers": [ "なぎさ" ], "comment": "water's edge; beach; shore" },
	{ "question": "減免", "answers": [ "げんめん" ], "comment": "reduction and exemption (e.g. taxes); mitigation and remission (e.g. in criminal law)" },
	{ "question": "減反", "answers": [ "げんたん" ], "comment": "reduction (of crop size); reduction of acreage (under cultivation)" },
	{ "question": "減収", "answers": [ "げんしゅう" ], "comment": "fall; decrease (in income)" },
	{ "question": "減員", "answers": [ "げんいん" ], "comment": "reduction of staff" },
	{ "question": "減点", "answers": [ "げんてん" ], "comment": "subtract; give a demerit" },
	{ "question": "減産", "answers": [ "げんさん" ], "comment": "reduction in production" },
	{ "question": "減益", "answers": [ "げんえき" ], "comment": "decrease in profits" },
	{ "question": "減税", "answers": [ "げんぜい" ], "comment": "tax reduction" },
	{ "question": "減給", "answers": [ "げんきゅう" ], "comment": "pay cut; salary cut" },
	{ "question": "減退", "answers": [ "げんたい" ], "comment": "decline; ebb; failure; decay; decrease; loss" },
	{ "question": "減速", "answers": [ "げんそく" ], "comment": "deceleration" },
	{ "question": "減量", "answers": [ "げんりょう" ], "comment": "loss in weight, esp. body weight\nloss in quantity; reducing quantity; reducing doses" },
	{ "question": "減額", "answers": [ "げんがく" ], "comment": "reduction; diminution; abatement" },
	{ "question": "渡し", "answers": [ "わたし" ], "comment": "ferry (crossing); ferry(boat)\ndelivery" },
	{ "question": "渡り", "answers": [ "わたり" ], "comment": "ferry" },
	{ "question": "渡り鳥", "answers": [ "わたりどり" ], "comment": "migratory bird; bird of passage" },
	{ "question": "渡航", "answers": [ "とこう" ], "comment": "voyage" },
	{ "question": "渦中", "answers": [ "かちゅう" ], "comment": "vortex; maelstrom; whirlpool; convulsions; upheaval" },
	{ "question": "渦巻き", "answers": [ "うずまき" ], "comment": "whirlpool; eddy; coil" },
	{ "question": "温まる", "answers": [ "あたたまる", "ぬくまる", "あったまる" ], "comment": "to warm oneself; to sun oneself; to warm up; to get warm" },
	{ "question": "温厚", "answers": [ "おんこう" ], "comment": "gentle" },
	{ "question": "温和", "answers": [ "おんわ" ], "comment": "gentle; mild; moderate" },
	{ "question": "温存", "answers": [ "おんぞん" ], "comment": "preservation; retainment; keeping" },
	{ "question": "温床", "answers": [ "おんしょう" ], "comment": "hotbed; breeding ground" },
	{ "question": "港内", "answers": [ "こうない" ], "comment": "inside the harbour; inside the harbor" },
	{ "question": "港湾", "answers": [ "こうわん" ], "comment": "harbours; harbors" },
	{ "question": "湖沼", "answers": [ "こしょう" ], "comment": "lakes and marshes" },
	{ "question": "湖畔", "answers": [ "こはん" ], "comment": "lake shore" },
	{ "question": "湧水", "answers": [ "ゆうすい" ], "comment": "spring; welling of water" },
	{ "question": "湾岸", "answers": [ "わんがん" ], "comment": "gulf coast; bay coast" },
	{ "question": "湿原", "answers": [ "しつげん" ], "comment": "marshy grassland; wetlands" },
	{ "question": "湿地", "answers": [ "しっち" ], "comment": "wetland; wetlands" },
	{ "question": "湿疹", "answers": [ "しっしん" ], "comment": "eczema; rash" },
	{ "question": "満々", "answers": [ "まんまん" ], "comment": "full of; brimming with" },
	{ "question": "満了", "answers": [ "まんりょう" ], "comment": "expiration; termination" },
	{ "question": "満喫", "answers": [ "まんきつ" ], "comment": "having enough of (food, drink, etc.); having one's fill\nfully enjoying" },
	{ "question": "満場", "answers": [ "まんじょう" ], "comment": "whole house; whole audience" },
	{ "question": "満塁", "answers": [ "まんるい" ], "comment": "bases loaded" },
	{ "question": "満席", "answers": [ "まんせき" ], "comment": "full house; all seats occupied; fully occupied" },
	{ "question": "満月", "answers": [ "まんげつ" ], "comment": "full moon" },
	{ "question": "満期", "answers": [ "まんき" ], "comment": "expiration (of a term); maturity (e.g. investment)" },
	{ "question": "満杯", "answers": [ "まんぱい" ], "comment": "full" },
	{ "question": "満開", "answers": [ "まんかい" ], "comment": "full bloom" },
	{ "question": "満面", "answers": [ "まんめん" ], "comment": "(the) whole face" },
	{ "question": "源流", "answers": [ "げんりゅう" ], "comment": "source (e.g. of a river); headwaters\norigin of something continuous (language, culture, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "準ずる", "answers": [ "じゅんずる" ], "comment": "to apply correspondingly; to correspond to; to be proportionate to; to conform to" },
	{ "question": "準急", "answers": [ "じゅんきゅう" ], "comment": "semi-express train; local express train; sub-express train; slower than an express (more stops)" },
	{ "question": "溶接", "answers": [ "ようせつ" ], "comment": "weld; welding" },
	{ "question": "溶液", "answers": [ "ようえき" ], "comment": "solution (liquid)" },
	{ "question": "滑走", "answers": [ "かっそう" ], "comment": "gliding; sliding; skating (on ice); glide; slide\ntaxiing (aircraft); making a takeoff run" },
	{ "question": "滑降", "answers": [ "かっこう" ], "comment": "descent (esp. in skiing); sliding down" },
	{ "question": "滞納", "answers": [ "たいのう" ], "comment": "falling behind (with a payment); being in arrears; non-payment; default; delinquency" },
	{ "question": "漁", "answers": [ "りょう" ], "comment": "fishing; gathering seafood (e.g. clams, seaweed)\ncatch (e.g. of fish); haul" },
	{ "question": "漁る", "answers": [ "あさる" ], "comment": "to fish\nto look for; to search for; to hunt for; to scavenge; to scrounge; to look through; to rummage through\nto go on a spree (spending, reading, etc.); to binge" },
	{ "question": "漁場", "answers": [ "りょうば", "ぎょば", "ぎょじょう" ], "comment": "fishing grounds; permitted fishing zone" },
	{ "question": "漁村", "answers": [ "ぎょそん" ], "comment": "fishing village" },
	{ "question": "漁民", "answers": [ "ぎょみん" ], "comment": "fishermen" },
	{ "question": "漁港", "answers": [ "ぎょこう" ], "comment": "fishing harbour; fishing harbor" },
	{ "question": "漁獲", "answers": [ "ぎょかく" ], "comment": "fishing; catch; haul" },
	{ "question": "漂流", "answers": [ "ひょうりゅう" ], "comment": "drifting; drift; being adrift" },
	{ "question": "漏る", "answers": [ "もる" ], "comment": "to leak; to run out" },
	{ "question": "演壇", "answers": [ "えんだん" ], "comment": "rostrum; platform" },
	{ "question": "演歌", "answers": [ "えんか" ], "comment": "enka; traditional-style Japanese popular ballad\ntroubadour" },
	{ "question": "演目", "answers": [ "えんもく" ], "comment": "program (musical, concert, theatrical, etc.); programme" },
	{ "question": "演算", "answers": [ "えんざん" ], "comment": "operation; calculation" },
	{ "question": "演舞", "answers": [ "えんぶ" ], "comment": "dance performance" },
	{ "question": "演芸", "answers": [ "えんげい" ], "comment": "entertainment; performance" },
	{ "question": "漢文", "answers": [ "かんぶん" ], "comment": "Chinese classical literature\nliterature written entirely in kanji" },
	{ "question": "漢方", "answers": [ "かんぽう" ], "comment": "traditional Chinese medicine" },
	{ "question": "漢語", "answers": [ "かんご" ], "comment": "Chinese word; Sino-Japanese word" },
	{ "question": "漫才", "answers": [ "まんざい" ], "comment": "two-person comedy act (usu. presented as a fast-paced dialogue, occ. presented as a skit); comic dialogue" },
	{ "question": "漬け物", "answers": [ "つけもの" ], "comment": "tsukemono; Japanese pickled vegetables" },
	{ "question": "漬物", "answers": [ "つけもの" ], "comment": "tsukemono; Japanese pickled vegetables" },
	{ "question": "潔い", "answers": [ "いさぎよい" ], "comment": "manly; sportsmanlike; gracious; gallant; resolute; brave\npure (heart, actions, etc.); upright; blameless\nunsullied (e.g. scenery or object); pure; clean" },
	{ "question": "潔白", "answers": [ "けっぱく" ], "comment": "innocence (i.e. not guilty); purity; uprightness" },
	{ "question": "潤い", "answers": [ "うるおい" ], "comment": "moisture; damp; wetness\nrichness; warmth; gain; profit\nfinancial leeway" },
	{ "question": "潤う", "answers": [ "うるおう" ], "comment": "to be moist; to be damp; to get wet; to be watered\nto profit by; to receive benefits; to receive favors (favours)\nto become rich; to become at ease financially" },
	{ "question": "潤色", "answers": [ "じゅんしょく" ], "comment": "rhetorical flourishes" },
	{ "question": "潮流", "answers": [ "ちょうりゅう" ], "comment": "tide; tidal current\ntendency; drift; trend" },
	{ "question": "激励", "answers": [ "げきれい" ], "comment": "encouragement" },
	{ "question": "激動", "answers": [ "げきどう" ], "comment": "terrible shock; agitation; upheaval" },
	{ "question": "激化", "answers": [ "げきか", "げっか" ], "comment": "intensification; aggravation" },
	{ "question": "激変", "answers": [ "げきへん" ], "comment": "sudden change; upheaval" },
	{ "question": "激怒", "answers": [ "げきど" ], "comment": "rage; indignation; exasperation" },
	{ "question": "激戦", "answers": [ "げきせん" ], "comment": "fierce battle; hard-fought battle; hot contest; severe fight" },
	{ "question": "激減", "answers": [ "げきげん" ], "comment": "dropping sharply; decreasing rapidly" },
	{ "question": "激突", "answers": [ "げきとつ" ], "comment": "crash into; clash" },
	{ "question": "激論", "answers": [ "げきろん" ], "comment": "heated discussion" },
	{ "question": "濁す", "answers": [ "にごす" ], "comment": "to make muddy (a liquid); to make cloudy; to make turbid; to roil\nto prevaricate; to speak ambiguously" },
	{ "question": "濃淡", "answers": [ "のうたん" ], "comment": "light and shade; shade (of colour, color)\ndepth (of flavor); complexity; strength and weakness (of flavor)" },
	{ "question": "濃縮", "answers": [ "のうしゅく" ], "comment": "concentration (e.g. of a solution); enrichment; condensation" },
	{ "question": "瀬", "answers": [ "せ" ], "comment": "shallows; shoal\nrapids; current; torrent\nposition; place\nchance; opportunity" },
	{ "question": "瀬戸際", "answers": [ "せとぎわ" ], "comment": "brink; critical moment" },
	{ "question": "灌漑", "answers": [ "かんがい" ], "comment": "irrigation" },
	{ "question": "灘", "answers": [ "なだ" ], "comment": "open sea" },
	{ "question": "火力", "answers": [ "かりょく" ], "comment": "heating power; thermal power\nfirepower" },
	{ "question": "火器", "answers": [ "かき" ], "comment": "firearms; guns" },
	{ "question": "火星", "answers": [ "かせい" ], "comment": "Mars (planet)" },
	{ "question": "火種", "answers": [ "ひだね" ], "comment": "live coals (for firelighting); remains of fire\ncause (of disturbance, conflict, etc.); trigger" },
	{ "question": "火花", "answers": [ "ひばな" ], "comment": "spark" },
	{ "question": "火葬", "answers": [ "かそう" ], "comment": "cremation" },
	{ "question": "火薬", "answers": [ "かやく" ], "comment": "gunpowder; powder" },
	{ "question": "灯す", "answers": [ "ともす", "とぼす" ], "comment": "to light; to turn on" },
	{ "question": "炉心", "answers": [ "ろしん" ], "comment": "nuclear reactor core" },
	{ "question": "炊出し", "answers": [ "たきだし" ], "comment": "emergency rice feeding; distribution of rice after an emergency" },
	{ "question": "炎上", "answers": [ "えんじょう" ], "comment": "blazing up\ndestruction of a large building by fire\nflood of comments to a blog, exceeding what the blog's owner can answer" },
	{ "question": "炎天", "answers": [ "えんてん" ], "comment": "blazing heat; scorching sun" },
	{ "question": "炎症", "answers": [ "えんしょう" ], "comment": "inflammation; irritation" },
	{ "question": "炭田", "answers": [ "たんでん" ], "comment": "coalfield; coal field" },
	{ "question": "炭素", "answers": [ "たんそ" ], "comment": "carbon (C)" },
	{ "question": "点す", "answers": [ "ともす", "とぼす" ], "comment": "to light; to turn on" },
	{ "question": "点在", "answers": [ "てんざい" ], "comment": "being dotted with; being scattered" },
	{ "question": "点字", "answers": [ "てんじ" ], "comment": "Braille" },
	{ "question": "点差", "answers": [ "てんさ" ], "comment": "point spread" },
	{ "question": "点滅", "answers": [ "てんめつ" ], "comment": "switching on and off; flashing; blinking; flickering" },
	{ "question": "点滴", "answers": [ "てんてき" ], "comment": "raindrops; falling drop of water\nintravenous drip; IV; drip-feed" },
	{ "question": "点火", "answers": [ "てんか" ], "comment": "ignition; lighting; set fire to" },
	{ "question": "点訳", "answers": [ "てんやく" ], "comment": "translating into Braille" },
	{ "question": "無休", "answers": [ "むきゅう" ], "comment": "without a holiday; nonstop" },
	{ "question": "無傷", "answers": [ "むきず" ], "comment": "unhurt; uninjured; unwounded; flawless; spotless; sound; perfect" },
	{ "question": "無償", "answers": [ "むしょう" ], "comment": "no compensation; without payment\nfree of charge" },
	{ "question": "無口", "answers": [ "むくち" ], "comment": "reticence; taciturnity; silent person\nreticent; taciturn; silent" },
	{ "question": "無名", "answers": [ "むめい" ], "comment": "unsigned; nameless; anonymous; anonymity" },
	{ "question": "無実", "answers": [ "むじつ" ], "comment": "absence of the fact; insubstantiality; innocence; guiltlessness\ninnocent; guiltless\nfalse; untrue" },
	{ "question": "無害", "answers": [ "むがい" ], "comment": "harmless" },
	{ "question": "無形", "answers": [ "むけい" ], "comment": "abstract; immaterial; moral; spiritual; intangible" },
	{ "question": "無心", "answers": [ "むしん" ], "comment": "innocence\ninsentient (i.e. plants, inanimate objects, etc.)\nfree from obstructive thoughts\nto pester someone (for cash, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "無恥", "answers": [ "むち" ], "comment": "shameless" },
	{ "question": "無情", "answers": [ "むじょう" ], "comment": "heartlessness; hardness; cruelty; ruthless" },
	{ "question": "無断", "answers": [ "むだん" ], "comment": "without permission; without notice" },
	{ "question": "無期", "answers": [ "むき" ], "comment": "indefinite" },
	{ "question": "無欲", "answers": [ "むよく" ], "comment": "unselfish; disinterested; unavaricious; free of avarice" },
	{ "question": "無死", "answers": [ "むし" ], "comment": "no outs" },
	{ "question": "無残", "answers": [ "むざん" ], "comment": "cruel; merciless; atrocious; ruthless; cold-blooded\npitiful; tragic; horrible; miserable\nbreaking a religious precept without shame" },
	{ "question": "無法", "answers": [ "むほう" ], "comment": "lawlessness; injustice; wrong; outrage\noutrageous; lawless; disorderly; unjust; unreasonable" },
	{ "question": "無益", "answers": [ "むえき" ], "comment": "useless; futile; vain" },
	{ "question": "無策", "answers": [ "むさく" ], "comment": "lacking means or measures or policies" },
	{ "question": "無精", "answers": [ "ぶしょう" ], "comment": "indolence; laziness; sloth" },
	{ "question": "無給", "answers": [ "むきゅう" ], "comment": "unpaid; nonsalaried" },
	{ "question": "無罪", "answers": [ "むざい" ], "comment": "innocence" },
	{ "question": "無職", "answers": [ "むしょく" ], "comment": "without an occupation" },
	{ "question": "無能", "answers": [ "むのう" ], "comment": "inefficiency; incompetence\nincompetent person" },
	{ "question": "無色", "answers": [ "むしょく" ], "comment": "colourless; colorless; achromatic" },
	{ "question": "無茶", "answers": [ "むちゃ", "むっちゃ" ], "comment": "absurd; unreasonable; excessive; rash\nvery; extremely; excessively" },
	{ "question": "無謀", "answers": [ "むぼう" ], "comment": "reckless; thoughtless; rash; ill-advised; impulsive; mad (scheme, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "無邪気", "answers": [ "むじゃき" ], "comment": "innocence; simple-mindedness" },
	{ "question": "無配", "answers": [ "むはい" ], "comment": "without dividend" },
	{ "question": "無量", "answers": [ "むりょう" ], "comment": "immeasurable" },
	{ "question": "無風", "answers": [ "むふう" ], "comment": "calm; windless" },
	{ "question": "無駄遣い", "answers": [ "むだづかい" ], "comment": "wasting ... on (e.g. money); squandering; waste; frittering away" },
	{ "question": "焦り", "answers": [ "あせり" ], "comment": "impatience" },
	{ "question": "焼きそば", "answers": [ "やきそば" ], "comment": "yakisoba; fried noodles, usu. with with vegetables and meat" },
	{ "question": "焼き肉", "answers": [ "やきにく" ], "comment": "yakiniku; Japanese dish of grilled meat similar to Korean barbecue\nroasted meat; grill" },
	{ "question": "焼き芋", "answers": [ "やきいも" ], "comment": "roasted sweet potato; baked sweet potato" },
	{ "question": "焼き鳥", "answers": [ "やきとり" ], "comment": "yakitori; chicken pieces (or sometimes beef or pork offal) grilled on a skewer" },
	{ "question": "焼け跡", "answers": [ "やけあと" ], "comment": "ruins of a fire; fire-devastated area" },
	{ "question": "焼そば", "answers": [ "やきそば" ], "comment": "yakisoba; fried noodles, usu. with with vegetables and meat" },
	{ "question": "焼却", "answers": [ "しょうきゃく" ], "comment": "incineration; destroy by fire" },
	{ "question": "焼死", "answers": [ "しょうし" ], "comment": "death by fire" },
	{ "question": "焼肉", "answers": [ "やきにく" ], "comment": "yakiniku; Japanese dish of grilled meat similar to Korean barbecue\nroasted meat; grill" },
	{ "question": "焼芋", "answers": [ "やきいも" ], "comment": "roasted sweet potato; baked sweet potato" },
	{ "question": "焼酎", "answers": [ "しょうちゅう" ], "comment": "shochu; Japanese spirit distilled from sweet potatoes, rice, etc." },
	{ "question": "焼鳥", "answers": [ "やきとり" ], "comment": "yakitori; chicken pieces (or sometimes beef or pork offal) grilled on a skewer" },
	{ "question": "煎餅", "answers": [ "せんべい" ], "comment": "rice cracker; Japanese cracker; rice cookie; wafer" },
	{ "question": "煙たい", "answers": [ "けぶたい", "けむたい" ], "comment": "smoky\nawkward; ill at ease" },
	{ "question": "煙る", "answers": [ "けむる", "けぶる" ], "comment": "to smoke (e.g. fire)\nto be hazy" },
	{ "question": "照会", "answers": [ "しょうかい" ], "comment": "inquiry; enquiry; query; reference" },
	{ "question": "照射", "answers": [ "しょうしゃ" ], "comment": "radiation; beaming; irradiation" },
	{ "question": "照準", "answers": [ "しょうじゅん" ], "comment": "sight (e.g. of a gun); aim; alignment" },
	{ "question": "煩わしい", "answers": [ "わずらわしい" ], "comment": "troublesome; annoying; complicated" },
	{ "question": "煩雑", "answers": [ "はんざつ" ], "comment": "complex; intricate; complicated; confused; troublesome; vexatious; cumbersome" },
	{ "question": "煮物", "answers": [ "にもの" ], "comment": "food cooked by boiling or stewing" },
	{ "question": "煮詰める", "answers": [ "につめる" ], "comment": "to boil down; to concentrate (soup, milk, stock, etc.)\nto reach a conclusion; to conclude a discussion" },
	{ "question": "煮込む", "answers": [ "にこむ" ], "comment": "to cook together; to boil well" },
	{ "question": "熟知", "answers": [ "じゅくち" ], "comment": "being familiar with; having a thorough knowledge of; being well-informed about" },
	{ "question": "熟練", "answers": [ "じゅくれん" ], "comment": "skill; dexterity; proficiency" },
	{ "question": "熱々", "answers": [ "あつあつ" ], "comment": "piping hot; scalding\nmadly in love" },
	{ "question": "熱弁", "answers": [ "ねつべん" ], "comment": "fervent speech" },
	{ "question": "熱戦", "answers": [ "ねっせん" ], "comment": "fierce fighting; close contest" },
	{ "question": "熱気", "answers": [ "ねっき" ], "comment": "heat; hot air; enthusiasm" },
	{ "question": "熱湯", "answers": [ "ねっとう" ], "comment": "boiling water" },
	{ "question": "熱烈", "answers": [ "ねつれつ" ], "comment": "ardent; passionate; vehement" },
	{ "question": "燃焼", "answers": [ "ねんしょう" ], "comment": "burning; combustion" },
	{ "question": "燃費", "answers": [ "ねんぴ" ], "comment": "fuel consumption; gas mileage" },
	{ "question": "爆破", "answers": [ "ばくは" ], "comment": "destructive blast; explosion; blow up" },
	{ "question": "爆竹", "answers": [ "ばくちく" ], "comment": "firecracker" },
	{ "question": "爆笑", "answers": [ "ばくしょう" ], "comment": "roar of laughter (from several people)\nlaughing hard (single person)" },
	{ "question": "爆音", "answers": [ "ばくおん" ], "comment": "(sound of an) explosion or detonation; roar (of a machine)" },
	{ "question": "爪切り", "answers": [ "つめきり" ], "comment": "nail clippers" },
	{ "question": "父兄", "answers": [ "ふけい" ], "comment": "guardians; parents and older brothers" },
	{ "question": "片側", "answers": [ "かたがわ" ], "comment": "one side" },
	{ "question": "片思い", "answers": [ "かたおもい" ], "comment": "unrequited love" },
	{ "question": "版権", "answers": [ "はんけん" ], "comment": "copyright" },
	{ "question": "版画", "answers": [ "はんが" ], "comment": "woodcut; woodblock print; art print" },
	{ "question": "牛丼", "answers": [ "ぎゅうどん" ], "comment": "rice covered with beef and vegetables" },
	{ "question": "牛歩", "answers": [ "ぎゅうほ" ], "comment": "snail's pace; slow progress" },
	{ "question": "牧草", "answers": [ "ぼくそう" ], "comment": "pasture; grass" },
	{ "question": "牧野", "answers": [ "ぼくや" ], "comment": "pasture land; ranch" },
	{ "question": "物別れ", "answers": [ "ものわかれ" ], "comment": "failure to reach agreement" },
	{ "question": "物好き", "answers": [ "ものずき" ], "comment": "(idle) curiosity; fancifulness; whimsy; (having) strange tastes" },
	{ "question": "物干し", "answers": [ "ものほし" ], "comment": "frame for drying clothes; clotheshorse" },
	{ "question": "物心", "answers": [ "ものごころ" ], "comment": "awareness of things around one; ability to understand what is going on around oneself; judgment; judgement; discretion" },
	{ "question": "物流", "answers": [ "ぶつりゅう" ], "comment": "(physical) distribution; distribution of goods; logistics" },
	{ "question": "物産", "answers": [ "ぶっさん" ], "comment": "product" },
	{ "question": "物的", "answers": [ "ぶってき" ], "comment": "material; physical" },
	{ "question": "物覚え", "answers": [ "ものおぼえ" ], "comment": "memory; ability to learn" },
	{ "question": "物言い", "answers": [ "ものいい" ], "comment": "manner of speaking\nverbal argument\nobjection; protesting a decision (esp. that of a sumo referee)\nrumor; rumour" },
	{ "question": "物証", "answers": [ "ぶっしょう" ], "comment": "evidence; exhibit" },
	{ "question": "物議", "answers": [ "ぶつぎ" ], "comment": "public discussion; public criticism; controversy" },
	{ "question": "物販", "answers": [ "ぶっぱん" ], "comment": "sale of goods (as opposed to services)" },
	{ "question": "物陰", "answers": [ "ものかげ" ], "comment": "cover; under cover; shelter; hiding" },
	{ "question": "特使", "answers": [ "とくし" ], "comment": "special envoy" },
	{ "question": "特典", "answers": [ "とくてん" ], "comment": "privilege; special favor; special favour; benefit; prerogative; perk; amenity" },
	{ "question": "特大", "answers": [ "とくだい" ], "comment": "extra-large" },
	{ "question": "特技", "answers": [ "とくぎ" ], "comment": "special skill" },
	{ "question": "特捜", "answers": [ "とくそう" ], "comment": "special investigation" },
	{ "question": "特段", "answers": [ "とくだん" ], "comment": "special" },
	{ "question": "特産", "answers": [ "とくさん" ], "comment": "specialty; special product" },
	{ "question": "特筆", "answers": [ "とくひつ" ], "comment": "special mention" },
	{ "question": "特約", "answers": [ "とくやく" ], "comment": "special contract; special agreement; rider (insurance)" },
	{ "question": "特製", "answers": [ "とくせい" ], "comment": "special make; deluxe" },
	{ "question": "特訓", "answers": [ "とっくん" ], "comment": "special training; intensive training; crash course" },
	{ "question": "特設", "answers": [ "とくせつ" ], "comment": "setting up specially; special installation" },
	{ "question": "特選", "answers": [ "とくせん" ], "comment": "specially selection; special approval; special prize; high honour" },
	{ "question": "狂乱", "answers": [ "きょうらん" ], "comment": "fury; frenzy; madness" },
	{ "question": "狂気", "answers": [ "きょうき" ], "comment": "madness; insanity" },
	{ "question": "狂言", "answers": [ "きょうげん" ], "comment": "kyogen; farce presented between noh plays or during the interlude of a noh play\nkabuki play; kabuki performance\nmake-believe; ruse; trick" },
	{ "question": "狩り", "answers": [ "かり" ], "comment": "hunting\nharvesting (e.g. berries, fruit); picking; gathering" },
	{ "question": "独り占め", "answers": [ "ひとりじめ" ], "comment": "monopolising; monopolizing; hogging; having all to oneself" },
	{ "question": "独り歩き", "answers": [ "ひとりあるき" ], "comment": "walking alone; walking unaided; going alone; standing on one's own" },
	{ "question": "独創", "answers": [ "どくそう" ], "comment": "originality" },
	{ "question": "独学", "answers": [ "どくがく" ], "comment": "self-education; self-instruction; self-study" },
	{ "question": "独断", "answers": [ "どくだん" ], "comment": "one's own judgement (judgment); dogmatic; arbitrary" },
	{ "question": "独走", "answers": [ "どくそう" ], "comment": "running alone; running solo\nhaving a large lead (over the others); being far ahead (of everyone else)\nhaving one's own way; ignoring others' opinions and acting as one wishes; arbitrary action" },
	{ "question": "狭まる", "answers": [ "せばまる" ], "comment": "to narrow; to contract" },
	{ "question": "狭める", "answers": [ "せばめる" ], "comment": "to narrow; to reduce; to contract" },
	{ "question": "猛威", "answers": [ "もうい" ], "comment": "fury; power; menace" },
	{ "question": "猛攻", "answers": [ "もうこう" ], "comment": "fierce attack" },
	{ "question": "猛暑", "answers": [ "もうしょ" ], "comment": "heat wave; fierce heat" },
	{ "question": "猟", "answers": [ "りょう" ], "comment": "hunting; game" },
	{ "question": "猫背", "answers": [ "ねこぜ" ], "comment": "bent back; hunchback; stoop" },
	{ "question": "猫舌", "answers": [ "ねこじた" ], "comment": "dislike of very hot food or drink; inability to take hot food" },
	{ "question": "献上", "answers": [ "けんじょう" ], "comment": "presenting to" },
	{ "question": "献花", "answers": [ "けんか" ], "comment": "flower offering" },
	{ "question": "献血", "answers": [ "けんけつ" ], "comment": "blood donation" },
	{ "question": "献金", "answers": [ "けんきん" ], "comment": "donation; contribution; offering" },
	{ "question": "猶予", "answers": [ "ゆうよ" ], "comment": "postponement; deferment; extension (of time)" },
	{ "question": "獄中", "answers": [ "ごくちゅう" ], "comment": "during imprisonment; while in jail (gaol)" },
	{ "question": "獣医", "answers": [ "じゅうい" ], "comment": "veterinarian" },
	{ "question": "玄人", "answers": [ "くろと", "くろうと" ], "comment": "expert; professional; master\nwoman in the nightlife business; demimondaine; geisha and prostitutes" },
	{ "question": "玄米", "answers": [ "げんまい" ], "comment": "unpolished rice; unmilled rice; brown rice" },
	{ "question": "率先", "answers": [ "そっせん" ], "comment": "taking the initiative" },
	{ "question": "王位", "answers": [ "おうい" ], "comment": "the throne; the crown" },
	{ "question": "王妃", "answers": [ "おうひ" ], "comment": "queen" },
	{ "question": "王室", "answers": [ "おうしつ" ], "comment": "royal family" },
	{ "question": "王宮", "answers": [ "おうきゅう" ], "comment": "royal palace" },
	{ "question": "王将", "answers": [ "おうしょう" ], "comment": "king (of the senior player)" },
	{ "question": "王座", "answers": [ "おうざ" ], "comment": "throne" },
	{ "question": "王手", "answers": [ "おうて" ], "comment": "check" },
	{ "question": "王族", "answers": [ "おうぞく" ], "comment": "royalty" },
	{ "question": "王立", "answers": [ "おうりつ" ], "comment": "royal" },
	{ "question": "王者", "answers": [ "おうしゃ", "おうじゃ" ], "comment": "king; monarch; ruler\nreigning champion" },
	{ "question": "珍", "answers": [ "ちん" ], "comment": "rare; curious; strange" },
	{ "question": "現像", "answers": [ "げんぞう" ], "comment": "developing (film)" },
	{ "question": "現有", "answers": [ "げんゆう" ], "comment": "present; existing" },
	{ "question": "現況", "answers": [ "げんきょう" ], "comment": "present condition" },
	{ "question": "現物", "answers": [ "げんぶつ" ], "comment": "actual article or goods\nspots (stocks, foreign exchange, commodities, etc.)\n(in) kind (income, benefit, rent, taxes, investment, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "現職", "answers": [ "げんしょく" ], "comment": "present post; current office; (an) incumbent" },
	{ "question": "球威", "answers": [ "きゅうい" ], "comment": "(pitcher's) stuff" },
	{ "question": "球技", "answers": [ "きゅうぎ" ], "comment": "ball game (e.g. baseball, tennis, soccer)" },
	{ "question": "球界", "answers": [ "きゅうかい" ], "comment": "the baseball world" },
	{ "question": "球菌", "answers": [ "きゅうきん" ], "comment": "coccus" },
	{ "question": "理学", "answers": [ "りがく" ], "comment": "physical science; natural science\nphysics\nlixue (Song-era Chinese philosophy)\nphilosophy" },
	{ "question": "理工", "answers": [ "りこう" ], "comment": "science and technology" },
	{ "question": "理念", "answers": [ "りねん" ], "comment": "(Platonic) ideal (of how things ought to be, e.g. human rights); foundational principle; idea; conception (e.g. of the university); doctrine; ideology" },
	{ "question": "理系", "answers": [ "りけい" ], "comment": "science" },
	{ "question": "理髪", "answers": [ "りはつ" ], "comment": "haircut" },
	{ "question": "琢磨", "answers": [ "たくま" ], "comment": "polish (jewels); cultivation" },
	{ "question": "琵琶", "answers": [ "びわ" ], "comment": "biwa (Japanese lute)" },
	{ "question": "環状", "answers": [ "かんじょう" ], "comment": "annulation; ring-forming" },
	{ "question": "甘え", "answers": [ "あまえ" ], "comment": "lack of self-reliance; depending on others" },
	{ "question": "甘味", "answers": [ "うまみ", "かんみ", "あまみ" ], "comment": "sweetness; sugary taste\nsweets; dessert; cake\ncharm; appeal\ntaste; flavour; flavor" },
	{ "question": "生い立ち", "answers": [ "おいたち" ], "comment": "growth; development\none's early life; upbringing; personal history" },
	{ "question": "生え抜き", "answers": [ "はえぬき" ], "comment": "native-born; trueborn" },
	{ "question": "生かす", "answers": [ "いかす" ], "comment": "to make (the best) use of; to leverage (skills, attributes, experience, etc.); to capitalise on (experience, etc)\nto let live; to keep alive\nto revive; to resuscitate" },
	{ "question": "生き埋め", "answers": [ "いきうめ" ], "comment": "burying alive" },
	{ "question": "生き残り", "answers": [ "いきのこり" ], "comment": "survival\nsurvivor; relic" },
	{ "question": "生き返る", "answers": [ "いきかえる" ], "comment": "to revive; to come to oneself; to be restored to life" },
	{ "question": "生ぬるい", "answers": [ "なまぬるい" ], "comment": "lukewarm; tepid\nhalf-hearted; vague; weak\nlenient; mild; soft" },
	{ "question": "生まれつき", "answers": [ "うまれつき" ], "comment": "by nature; by birth; naturally; natural; innate" },
	{ "question": "生まれ育つ", "answers": [ "うまれそだつ" ], "comment": "to be born and raised (in one particular place)" },
	{ "question": "生み", "answers": [ "うみ" ], "comment": "production; bringing into the world; (physical) birth" },
	{ "question": "生みの親", "answers": [ "うみのおや" ], "comment": "biological parent\nfounder; creator" },
	{ "question": "生む", "answers": [ "うむ" ], "comment": "to give birth; to bear (child); to lay (eggs)\nto produce; to yield; to give rise to; to deliver" },
	{ "question": "生やす", "answers": [ "はやす" ], "comment": "to grow; to cultivate; to wear a beard" },
	{ "question": "生体", "answers": [ "せいたい" ], "comment": "organism; living body" },
	{ "question": "生保", "answers": [ "せいほ" ], "comment": "life insurance\nlivelihood protection; public assistance; welfare" },
	{ "question": "生協", "answers": [ "せいきょう" ], "comment": "cooperative association; co-op store" },
	{ "question": "生家", "answers": [ "しょうか", "せいか" ], "comment": "house where one was born\nparents' house" },
	{ "question": "生息", "answers": [ "せいそく" ], "comment": "inhabiting; living" },
	{ "question": "生死", "answers": [ "せいし", "しょうじ", "しょうし" ], "comment": "life and death\nsamsara (cycle of death and rebirth)\ndeath" },
	{ "question": "生殖", "answers": [ "せいしょく" ], "comment": "reproduction" },
	{ "question": "生育", "answers": [ "せいいく" ], "comment": "birth and growth; giving birth and raising; development; breeding" },
	{ "question": "生臭い", "answers": [ "なまぐさい" ], "comment": "smelling of fish; fishy; smelling of blood; bloody\ndegenerate (of a monk); depraved; corrupt; fallen\nworldly; mundane; secular; common; ordinary\nfishy; suspicious; questionable" },
	{ "question": "生誕", "answers": [ "せいたん" ], "comment": "birth; nativity" },
	{ "question": "生返る", "answers": [ "いきかえる" ], "comment": "to revive; to come to oneself; to be restored to life" },
	{ "question": "生還", "answers": [ "せいかん" ], "comment": "returning alive\nreaching the home plate" },
	{ "question": "生鮮", "answers": [ "せいせん" ], "comment": "fresh" },
	{ "question": "産別", "answers": [ "さんべつ" ], "comment": "industrial union" },
	{ "question": "産卵", "answers": [ "さんらん" ], "comment": "egg-laying; spawning" },
	{ "question": "産品", "answers": [ "さんぴん" ], "comment": "products" },
	{ "question": "産科", "answers": [ "さんか" ], "comment": "obstetrics" },
	{ "question": "用件", "answers": [ "ようけん" ], "comment": "business; thing to be done; something that should be performed; information that should be conveyed" },
	{ "question": "用例", "answers": [ "ようれい" ], "comment": "example; illustration" },
	{ "question": "用具", "answers": [ "ようぐ" ], "comment": "tools; implements" },
	{ "question": "用品", "answers": [ "ようひん" ], "comment": "articles; supplies; parts" },
	{ "question": "用地", "answers": [ "ようち" ], "comment": "site" },
	{ "question": "用水", "answers": [ "ようすい" ], "comment": "irrigation water; water for fire; city water; cistern water" },
	{ "question": "田園", "answers": [ "でんえん" ], "comment": "the country; countryside; rural districts\ncultivated land; fields" },
	{ "question": "田畑", "answers": [ "たはた", "でんぱた", "たはたけ" ], "comment": "fields (of rice and other crops)" },
	{ "question": "由緒", "answers": [ "ゆいしょ" ], "comment": "history; pedigree; lineage" },
	{ "question": "申", "answers": [ "さる" ], "comment": "ninth sign of Chinese zodiac (The Monkey, 3pm-5pm, west-southwest, July)" },
	{ "question": "申し入れ", "answers": [ "もうしいれ" ], "comment": "proposal; offer; report; proposition; notice; request" },
	{ "question": "申し入れる", "answers": [ "もうしいれる" ], "comment": "to propose; to suggest" },
	{ "question": "申し合わせ", "answers": [ "もうしあわせ" ], "comment": "arrangement; appointment" },
	{ "question": "申し立て", "answers": [ "もうしたて" ], "comment": "statement; account (of something); declaration; allegation" },
	{ "question": "男優", "answers": [ "だんゆう" ], "comment": "actor (male)" },
	{ "question": "男児", "answers": [ "だんじ" ], "comment": "boy; son; man" },
	{ "question": "男前", "answers": [ "おとこまえ" ], "comment": "handsome man" },
	{ "question": "町外れ", "answers": [ "まちはずれ" ], "comment": "outskirts (of a town)" },
	{ "question": "町民", "answers": [ "ちょうみん" ], "comment": "townspeople" },
	{ "question": "町角", "answers": [ "まちかど" ], "comment": "street corner" },
	{ "question": "町長", "answers": [ "ちょうちょう" ], "comment": "town headman; town mayor" },
	{ "question": "画する", "answers": [ "かくする" ], "comment": "to draw (a line)\nto demarcate; to mark; to divide; to map out\nto plan" },
	{ "question": "画一", "answers": [ "かくいつ" ], "comment": "uniformity; standardization; standardisation" },
	{ "question": "画商", "answers": [ "がしょう" ], "comment": "picture dealer; commercial art gallery" },
	{ "question": "画廊", "answers": [ "がろう" ], "comment": "art gallery (esp. artworks for sale); picture gallery" },
	{ "question": "画数", "answers": [ "かくすう" ], "comment": "stroke count" },
	{ "question": "留め金", "answers": [ "とめがね" ], "comment": "clasp; snap fastener" },
	{ "question": "留任", "answers": [ "りゅうにん" ], "comment": "remaining (staying) in office; remaining at one's post" },
	{ "question": "留保", "answers": [ "りゅうほ" ], "comment": "reserving; withholding" },
	{ "question": "留年", "answers": [ "りゅうねん" ], "comment": "repeating a year (at school); staying in the same class for another year" },
	{ "question": "留置", "answers": [ "りゅうち" ], "comment": "detention (usu. during investigation); imprisonment; poundage; custody" },
	{ "question": "畜生", "answers": [ "ちくしょう", "ちきしょう" ], "comment": "beast (i.e. any animal other than man)\nperson reborn into the animal realm\nbrute (i.e. a contemptible human being)\nson of a bitch; for Christ's sake; damn it" },
	{ "question": "畜産", "answers": [ "ちくさん" ], "comment": "animal husbandry" },
	{ "question": "略奪", "answers": [ "りゃくだつ" ], "comment": "pillage; plunder; looting; robbery" },
	{ "question": "略式", "answers": [ "りゃくしき" ], "comment": "informal; simplified" },
	{ "question": "略歴", "answers": [ "りゃくれき" ], "comment": "brief personal record; short curriculum vitae; short CV" },
	{ "question": "略称", "answers": [ "りゃくしょう" ], "comment": "abbreviation" },
	{ "question": "略語", "answers": [ "りゃくご" ], "comment": "abbreviation; acronym" },
	{ "question": "番付", "answers": [ "ばんづけ" ], "comment": "ranked list (entertainers, sumo wrestlers, millionaires, etc.)\nprogram (e.g. theatre)" },
	{ "question": "異例", "answers": [ "いれい" ], "comment": "exceptional; unusual; extraordinary; unprecedented; singular" },
	{ "question": "異名", "answers": [ "いみょう", "いめい" ], "comment": "another name; nickname; alias" },
	{ "question": "異変", "answers": [ "いへん" ], "comment": "unusual phenomenon; unusual event; abnormal event; accident" },
	{ "question": "異物", "answers": [ "いぶつ" ], "comment": "foreign substance; foreign body; foreign contamination\nstrange object; unusual object\ndead body; corpse; remains" },
	{ "question": "異状", "answers": [ "いじょう" ], "comment": "something wrong; accident; change; abnormality; aberration" },
	{ "question": "異端", "answers": [ "いたん" ], "comment": "heresy" },
	{ "question": "異色", "answers": [ "いしょく" ], "comment": "unique; distinctive; novel; singular; unusual; special\ndifferent color (colour)" },
	{ "question": "異論", "answers": [ "いろん" ], "comment": "different opinion; objection" },
	{ "question": "疎外", "answers": [ "そがい" ], "comment": "estrangement; neglect; alienation; casting out" },
	{ "question": "疎通", "answers": [ "そつう" ], "comment": "(mutual) understanding; communication\nremoval of blockage (esp. medical); drainage" },
	{ "question": "疎遠", "answers": [ "そえん" ], "comment": "estrangement; neglect; silence" },
	{ "question": "疑似", "answers": [ "ぎじ" ], "comment": "suspected; pseudo; sham; quasi; false; mock" },
	{ "question": "疑心", "answers": [ "ぎしん" ], "comment": "doubt; suspicion; fear; apprehension" },
	{ "question": "疑念", "answers": [ "ぎねん" ], "comment": "doubt; suspicion; misgivings; scruples" },
	{ "question": "疑獄", "answers": [ "ぎごく" ], "comment": "scandal; graft case" },
	{ "question": "疑義", "answers": [ "ぎぎ" ], "comment": "doubt" },
	{ "question": "疲弊", "answers": [ "ひへい" ], "comment": "exhaustion; fatigue\nimpoverishment; (financial) exhaustion; ruin" },
	{ "question": "疾病", "answers": [ "しっぺい" ], "comment": "illness; disease" },
	{ "question": "病名", "answers": [ "びょうめい" ], "comment": "name of a disease" },
	{ "question": "病床", "answers": [ "びょうしょう" ], "comment": "sickbed" },
	{ "question": "病弱", "answers": [ "びょうじゃく" ], "comment": "weak (constitution); sickly; feeble; in poor health" },
	{ "question": "病死", "answers": [ "びょうし" ], "comment": "death from disease; death from illness" },
	{ "question": "病理", "answers": [ "びょうり" ], "comment": "pathology" },
	{ "question": "症例", "answers": [ "しょうれい" ], "comment": "case" },
	{ "question": "痛ましい", "answers": [ "いたましい" ], "comment": "pitiful; heartbreaking; tragical" },
	{ "question": "痛恨", "answers": [ "つうこん" ], "comment": "regretful; sorrowful; bitter\ncontrition" },
	{ "question": "痛手", "answers": [ "いたで" ], "comment": "serious wound\nhard blow" },
	{ "question": "痛烈", "answers": [ "つうれつ" ], "comment": "severe; bitter; scathing" },
	{ "question": "痴漢", "answers": [ "ちかん" ], "comment": "masher; molester; pervert" },
	{ "question": "癒着", "answers": [ "ゆちゃく" ], "comment": "adhesion; conglutination\ncollusion; collusive relationship" },
	{ "question": "発する", "answers": [ "はっする" ], "comment": "to fire (a gun); to emit; to give forth" },
	{ "question": "発令", "answers": [ "はつれい" ], "comment": "official announcement; proclamation" },
	{ "question": "発光", "answers": [ "はっこう" ], "comment": "luminescence; radiation" },
	{ "question": "発刊", "answers": [ "はっかん" ], "comment": "publish; start (new) publication" },
	{ "question": "発効", "answers": [ "はっこう" ], "comment": "coming into effect" },
	{ "question": "発動", "answers": [ "はつどう" ], "comment": "putting into operation\ninvocation" },
	{ "question": "発声", "answers": [ "はっせい" ], "comment": "utterance; speaking; vocalization; vocalisation; enunciation; pronouncing\nleading a group of people (in cheering, singing, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "発案", "answers": [ "はつあん" ], "comment": "idea; suggestion; initiation of a proposal" },
	{ "question": "発注", "answers": [ "はっちゅう" ], "comment": "ordering (materials); placing an order; order" },
	{ "question": "発火", "answers": [ "はっか" ], "comment": "ignition; catching fire\nfiring (e.g. gun); discharging" },
	{ "question": "発熱", "answers": [ "はつねつ" ], "comment": "generation of heat\n(attack of) fever; pyrexia" },
	{ "question": "発病", "answers": [ "はつびょう" ], "comment": "attack (disease)" },
	{ "question": "発症", "answers": [ "はっしょう" ], "comment": "outbreak of an illness; onset of an illness; appearance of symptoms" },
	{ "question": "発着", "answers": [ "はっちゃく" ], "comment": "arrival and departure" },
	{ "question": "発砲", "answers": [ "はっぽう" ], "comment": "firing; discharge of gun" },
	{ "question": "発祥", "answers": [ "はっしょう" ], "comment": "origin\nappearance of auspicious omen" },
	{ "question": "発給", "answers": [ "はっきゅう" ], "comment": "issuance (e.g. of a passport); issuing" },
	{ "question": "発育", "answers": [ "はついく" ], "comment": "(physical) growth; development" },
	{ "question": "発芽", "answers": [ "はつが" ], "comment": "germination; sprouting; budding" },
	{ "question": "発酵", "answers": [ "はっこう" ], "comment": "fermentation; zymosis" },
	{ "question": "登板", "answers": [ "とうばん" ], "comment": "taking the mound; pitching a game" },
	{ "question": "登用", "answers": [ "とうよう" ], "comment": "appointment; assignment; promotion" },
	{ "question": "登載", "answers": [ "とうさい" ], "comment": "register; record; printing" },
	{ "question": "登頂", "answers": [ "とうちょう" ], "comment": "climbing to the summit; summiting" },
	{ "question": "白バイ", "answers": [ "しろバイ" ], "comment": "motorcycle police\nwhite-colored police motorcycle" },
	{ "question": "白地", "answers": [ "しろじ", "しらじ" ], "comment": "white background\nblank\nfemale virgin" },
	{ "question": "白星", "answers": [ "しろぼし" ], "comment": "white circle; white star\nvictory mark" },
	{ "question": "白書", "answers": [ "はくしょ" ], "comment": "white paper" },
	{ "question": "白樺", "answers": [ "しらかば", "しらかんば" ], "comment": "Japanese white birch (Betula platyphylla var. japonica)" },
	{ "question": "白熱", "answers": [ "はくねつ" ], "comment": "white heat; incandescence\nclimax" },
	{ "question": "白状", "answers": [ "はくじょう" ], "comment": "confession" },
	{ "question": "白粉", "answers": [ "おしろい" ], "comment": "(face) powder" },
	{ "question": "白紙", "answers": [ "はくし", "しらかみ" ], "comment": "white paper; flyleaf\nblank paper\nclean slate; lack of prior opinion, positions, etc.\nscratch; beginning" },
	{ "question": "白線", "answers": [ "はくせん" ], "comment": "white line\nlinea alba (anot.)" },
	{ "question": "白羽", "answers": [ "しらは" ], "comment": "white feather" },
	{ "question": "白色", "answers": [ "はくしょく" ], "comment": "white" },
	{ "question": "白菜", "answers": [ "はくさい", "パクチョイ" ], "comment": "Chinese cabbage (Brassica campestris var. amplexicaulis); white rape; bok choy; pak choi" },
	{ "question": "白衣", "answers": [ "はくい", "びゃくい", "びゃくえ" ], "comment": "white robe; (doctor's) white gown" },
	{ "question": "白馬", "answers": [ "しろうま", "はくば" ], "comment": "white horse\nunrefined sake" },
	{ "question": "白骨", "answers": [ "はっこつ" ], "comment": "white (bleached) bone; skeleton" },
	{ "question": "白鳥", "answers": [ "しらとり", "はくちょう", "しろとり" ], "comment": "swan (Cygnus spp.)\nwhite-feathered bird" },
	{ "question": "百合", "answers": [ "ゆり" ], "comment": "lily (Lilium spp.)\ncomics and novels about female homosexuality" },
	{ "question": "的中", "answers": [ "てきちゅう" ], "comment": "striking home; hitting the mark\ncoming true; proving to be right; becoming realized" },
	{ "question": "皇太后", "answers": [ "こうたいごう", "こうたいこう" ], "comment": "Queen Mother; Empress Dowager" },
	{ "question": "皇居", "answers": [ "こうきょ" ], "comment": "Imperial Palace (of Japan); imperial residence" },
	{ "question": "皇族", "answers": [ "こうぞく" ], "comment": "imperial family; royalty" },
	{ "question": "皮切り", "answers": [ "かわきり" ], "comment": "beginning; start" },
	{ "question": "皮革", "answers": [ "ひかく" ], "comment": "leather; hide" },
	{ "question": "盆栽", "answers": [ "ぼんさい" ], "comment": "bonsai; miniature potted plant" },
	{ "question": "盆踊り", "answers": [ "ぼんおどり" ], "comment": "Bon Festival dance; Lantern Festival dance" },
	{ "question": "益", "answers": [ "やく", "よう", "えき" ], "comment": "benefit; use; good; advantage; gain\nprofit; gains" },
	{ "question": "盗み", "answers": [ "ぬすみ" ], "comment": "stealing" },
	{ "question": "盗塁", "answers": [ "とうるい" ], "comment": "base stealing; steal; stolen base" },
	{ "question": "盗聴", "answers": [ "とうちょう" ], "comment": "interception (email); wiretap; bug" },
	{ "question": "盗賊", "answers": [ "とうぞく" ], "comment": "thief; robber; burglar; bandit" },
	{ "question": "盛り上がり", "answers": [ "もりあがり" ], "comment": "climax; uprush\nbulge" },
	{ "question": "盛り付け", "answers": [ "もりつけ" ], "comment": "arrangement of food (on a dish); serving of (arranged) food" },
	{ "question": "盛大", "answers": [ "せいだい" ], "comment": "grand; magnificent; lavish; large scale; prosperous; thriving; lively\nforceful; powerful; vigorous" },
	{ "question": "盛況", "answers": [ "せいきょう" ], "comment": "success; prosperity; boom" },
	{ "question": "盟主", "answers": [ "めいしゅ" ], "comment": "leader; leading power" },
	{ "question": "盟友", "answers": [ "めいゆう" ], "comment": "sworn friend" },
	{ "question": "監修", "answers": [ "かんしゅう" ], "comment": "(editorial) supervision; general editorship\nsupervising director (of anime, TV series etc.)" },
	{ "question": "監察", "answers": [ "かんさつ" ], "comment": "inspection; inspector" },
	{ "question": "監獄", "answers": [ "かんごく" ], "comment": "prison" },
	{ "question": "監理", "answers": [ "かんり" ], "comment": "superintendence; supervision; administration" },
	{ "question": "監禁", "answers": [ "かんきん" ], "comment": "confinement" },
	{ "question": "目先", "answers": [ "めさき" ], "comment": "before one's eyes; under one's nose\nimmediate (e.g. interests); present; at hand; short-run\nforesight; near future\nappearance" },
	{ "question": "目抜き", "answers": [ "めぬき" ], "comment": "principal; main; important; fashionable" },
	{ "question": "目方", "answers": [ "めかた" ], "comment": "weight" },
	{ "question": "目減り", "answers": [ "めべり" ], "comment": "loss (of weight or volume); decrease; reduction; diminishment; erosion; shrinkage; ullage" },
	{ "question": "目白押し", "answers": [ "めじろおし" ], "comment": "jostling; milling about; crush; being jammed together\npacked with (activities, products, etc.); teeming with" },
	{ "question": "目盛り", "answers": [ "めもり" ], "comment": "scale; gradations" },
	{ "question": "目薬", "answers": [ "めぐすり" ], "comment": "eye drops; eyewash" },
	{ "question": "目覚ましい", "answers": [ "めざましい" ], "comment": "brilliant; splendid; striking; remarkable" },
	{ "question": "目録", "answers": [ "もくろく" ], "comment": "catalogue; catalog; inventory; index; list\ncertificate indicating an impending gift" },
	{ "question": "目頭", "answers": [ "めがしら" ], "comment": "inner canthus; inner corner of the eye" },
	{ "question": "盲人", "answers": [ "もうじん" ], "comment": "blind person" },
	{ "question": "盲点", "answers": [ "もうてん" ], "comment": "blind spot" },
	{ "question": "盲目", "answers": [ "もうもく" ], "comment": "blindness" },
	{ "question": "盲腸", "answers": [ "もうちょう" ], "comment": "cecum; caecum; blind gut\n(vermiform) appendix\nappendicitis" },
	{ "question": "直し", "answers": [ "なおし" ], "comment": "correction; rectification\nmending; repair" },
	{ "question": "直下", "answers": [ "ちょっか" ], "comment": "directly under\nfalling perpendicularly" },
	{ "question": "直列", "answers": [ "ちょくれつ" ], "comment": "series (e.g. electrical)\nserial" },
	{ "question": "直営", "answers": [ "ちょくえい" ], "comment": "direct management" },
	{ "question": "直属", "answers": [ "ちょくぞく" ], "comment": "direct control; direct supervision" },
	{ "question": "直撃", "answers": [ "ちょくげき" ], "comment": "direct hit" },
	{ "question": "直球", "answers": [ "ちょくきゅう", "ちょっきゅう" ], "comment": "straight ball (pitch)\nstraight; frank" },
	{ "question": "直系", "answers": [ "ちょっけい" ], "comment": "direct descent; direct line" },
	{ "question": "直行", "answers": [ "ちょっこう" ], "comment": "through; non-stop; direct" },
	{ "question": "直視", "answers": [ "ちょくし" ], "comment": "looking someone in the eyes; taking a straight look at something" },
	{ "question": "直観", "answers": [ "ちょっかん" ], "comment": "intuition; instinct; insight; hunch; immediacy" },
	{ "question": "直轄", "answers": [ "ちょっかつ" ], "comment": "direct control" },
	{ "question": "直進", "answers": [ "ちょくしん" ], "comment": "going right on; going straight ahead" },
	{ "question": "相乗", "answers": [ "そうじょう" ], "comment": "multiplication; synergism" },
	{ "question": "相乗り", "answers": [ "あいのり" ], "comment": "riding together" },
	{ "question": "相槌", "answers": [ "あいづち" ], "comment": "aizuchi; back-channeling; interjections indicating that one is paying attention\ntwo smiths hammering at an object in turn" },
	{ "question": "相殺", "answers": [ "そうさい", "そうさつ" ], "comment": "offset; offsetting each other; cancelling each other out; counterbalancing\nset-off; setoff" },
	{ "question": "盾", "answers": [ "たて" ], "comment": "shield; buckler; escutcheon; pretext" },
	{ "question": "省みる", "answers": [ "かえりみる" ], "comment": "to look back (e.g. over shoulder or at the past); to turn around\nto reflect on the past; to reconsider; to review\nto reflect on oneself; to introspect; to contemplate oneself\nto consider (usu. used in negative); to concern oneself about; to pay attention to; to take into consideration" },
	{ "question": "省令", "answers": [ "しょうれい" ], "comment": "ministerial ordinance" },
	{ "question": "省力", "answers": [ "しょうりょく" ], "comment": "labor saving; labour saving" },
	{ "question": "省庁", "answers": [ "しょうちょう" ], "comment": "ministries and government offices; the authorities" },
	{ "question": "眉毛", "answers": [ "まゆげ" ], "comment": "eyebrows" },
	{ "question": "看過", "answers": [ "かんか" ], "comment": "overlooking; turning a blind eye" },
	{ "question": "県下", "answers": [ "けんか" ], "comment": "in the prefecture; prefectural" },
	{ "question": "県内", "answers": [ "けんない" ], "comment": "within the prefecture" },
	{ "question": "県営", "answers": [ "けんえい" ], "comment": "prefectural; under prefectural management" },
	{ "question": "県外", "answers": [ "けんがい" ], "comment": "outside the prefecture" },
	{ "question": "県警", "answers": [ "けんけい" ], "comment": "prefectural police" },
	{ "question": "県議", "answers": [ "けんぎ" ], "comment": "prefectural assembly" },
	{ "question": "県道", "answers": [ "けんどう" ], "comment": "prefectural road" },
	{ "question": "真っ向", "answers": [ "まっこう" ], "comment": "directly opposite; right in front\nmiddle of the forehead\nhelmet front" },
	{ "question": "真ん丸", "answers": [ "まんまる" ], "comment": "perfect circle\ncute" },
	{ "question": "真上", "answers": [ "まうえ" ], "comment": "just above; right overhead" },
	{ "question": "真価", "answers": [ "しんか" ], "comment": "true value; real worth" },
	{ "question": "真偽", "answers": [ "しんぎ" ], "comment": "truth or error; authenticity; veracity" },
	{ "question": "真夏", "answers": [ "まなつ" ], "comment": "midsummer" },
	{ "question": "真心", "answers": [ "まこころ", "まごころ" ], "comment": "sincerity; devotion" },
	{ "question": "真摯", "answers": [ "しんし" ], "comment": "sincere; earnest" },
	{ "question": "真新しい", "answers": [ "まあたらしい" ], "comment": "brand new" },
	{ "question": "真珠", "answers": [ "しんじゅ" ], "comment": "pearl" },
	{ "question": "真顔", "answers": [ "まがお" ], "comment": "serious look" },
	{ "question": "真髄", "answers": [ "しんずい" ], "comment": "essence; quintessence; spirit; soul; heart; pith; pith and marrow" },
	{ "question": "眠たい", "answers": [ "ねぶたい", "ねむたい" ], "comment": "sleepy; drowsy" },
	{ "question": "眠気", "answers": [ "ねむけ" ], "comment": "sleepiness; drowsiness" },
	{ "question": "眼", "answers": [ "め", "まなこ" ], "comment": "eye; eyeball\neyesight; sight; vision\nlook; stare; glance\nan experience\nviewpoint\nstitch; texture; weave\nordinal number suffix\nsomewhat; -ish /\n eye; eyeball\npupil and (dark) iris of the eye\ninsight; perceptivity; power of observation\nlook; field of vision\ncore; center; centre; essence" },
	{ "question": "眼科", "answers": [ "がんか" ], "comment": "ophthalmology" },
	{ "question": "着地", "answers": [ "ちゃくち" ], "comment": "landing" },
	{ "question": "着工", "answers": [ "ちゃっこう" ], "comment": "start of (construction) work" },
	{ "question": "着席", "answers": [ "ちゃくせき" ], "comment": "sit down; seat" },
	{ "question": "着色", "answers": [ "ちゃくしょく" ], "comment": "colouring; coloring; colorant" },
	{ "question": "着衣", "answers": [ "ちゃくい" ], "comment": "one's clothes; wearing clothes" },
	{ "question": "着陸", "answers": [ "ちゃくりく" ], "comment": "landing; alighting; touch down" },
	{ "question": "着飾る", "answers": [ "きかざる" ], "comment": "to dress up" },
	{ "question": "督促", "answers": [ "とくそく" ], "comment": "urge; demand; importunity" },
	{ "question": "矛先", "answers": [ "ほこさき" ], "comment": "point of spear; spearhead\nbrunt; aim of attack; force of argument" },
	{ "question": "矢先", "answers": [ "やさき" ], "comment": "arrowhead; brunt; target\nbeing about to; being on the point of" },
	{ "question": "知名", "answers": [ "ちめい" ], "comment": "well-known" },
	{ "question": "短め", "answers": [ "みじかめ" ], "comment": "rather short; somewhat short" },
	{ "question": "短命", "answers": [ "たんめい" ], "comment": "short life; short lived" },
	{ "question": "短大", "answers": [ "たんだい" ], "comment": "junior college; vocationally oriented two or three year post-secondary education institution" },
	{ "question": "短歌", "answers": [ "たんか", "みじかうた" ], "comment": "tanka; 31-mora Japanese poem" },
	{ "question": "短気", "answers": [ "たんき" ], "comment": "quick temper; short temper" },
	{ "question": "短絡", "answers": [ "たんらく" ], "comment": "electric short-circuit\ndrawing a hasty inference between two events; jumping to a quick conclusion; dealing with matters quickly and carelessly" },
	{ "question": "短調", "answers": [ "たんちょう" ], "comment": "minor key" },
	{ "question": "短銃", "answers": [ "たんじゅう" ], "comment": "pistol; revolver" },
	{ "question": "石器", "answers": [ "せっき" ], "comment": "stone implement (e.g. stone age arrowheads); stone tool" },
	{ "question": "石垣", "answers": [ "いしがけ", "いしがき" ], "comment": "stone wall" },
	{ "question": "石室", "answers": [ "せきしつ", "いしむろ" ], "comment": "stone hut; rock chamber\ntomb; stone burial chamber" },
	{ "question": "石材", "answers": [ "せきざい" ], "comment": "(building) stone" },
	{ "question": "石橋", "answers": [ "いしばし", "せっきょう" ], "comment": "stone bridge" },
	{ "question": "石灰", "answers": [ "いしばい", "せっかい" ], "comment": "lime; quicklime; caustic lime" },
	{ "question": "石神", "answers": [ "しゃくじん", "いしがみ" ], "comment": "stone which is worshipped; image of a god in stone" },
	{ "question": "石頭", "answers": [ "いしあたま" ], "comment": "inflexible person" },
	{ "question": "砂利", "answers": [ "じゃり", "ざり" ], "comment": "gravel; ballast; pebbles\nchild; rugrat; ankle-biter" },
	{ "question": "砂浜", "answers": [ "すなはま" ], "comment": "sandy beach" },
	{ "question": "砂防", "answers": [ "さぼう" ], "comment": "erosion control" },
	{ "question": "研ぐ", "answers": [ "とぐ" ], "comment": "to sharpen; to hone; to whet; to grind\nto wash (rice)\nto scour; to polish; to burnish" },
	{ "question": "砲弾", "answers": [ "ほうだん" ], "comment": "shell; cannonball" },
	{ "question": "砲撃", "answers": [ "ほうげき" ], "comment": "bombarding; shelling; bombardment" },
	{ "question": "砲火", "answers": [ "ほうか" ], "comment": "gunfire; fire" },
	{ "question": "破り", "answers": [ "やぶり" ], "comment": "getting away from; escaping; defying" },
	{ "question": "破局", "answers": [ "はきょく" ], "comment": "catastrophe; cataclysm; collapse (of a relationship); breakup; split (friends, lovers, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "破格", "answers": [ "はかく" ], "comment": "extraordinary; special; exceptional; abnormal; unprecedented\nnon-standard grammatical construction; ungrammatical usage; solecism" },
	{ "question": "破棄", "answers": [ "はき" ], "comment": "tearing up and discarding (e.g. documents); disposal (e.g. weaponry); destruction\nannulment; cancellation; abrogation; voiding; breaking (e.g. treaty)\nreversal (of an original ruling)" },
	{ "question": "破裂", "answers": [ "はれつ" ], "comment": "explosion; rupture; break off" },
	{ "question": "硫黄", "answers": [ "いおう", "ゆおう" ], "comment": "sulfur (S); sulphur" },
	{ "question": "硬化", "answers": [ "こうか" ], "comment": "hardening; vulcanization; vulcanisation; sclerosis; curing" },
	{ "question": "硬式", "answers": [ "こうしき" ], "comment": "hard (esp. of hardball, tennis, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "硬派", "answers": [ "こうは" ], "comment": "tough elements; hard-liners; stalwarts; diehards; hawks\nconsidering association with women and interest in fashion as weakness and focusing on strength and manliness; young tough; young rowdy\nhard (news); hard news reporter\nstrait-laced (person); straight-laced; overly serious regarding relations between men and women\nbullish traders" },
	{ "question": "碑文", "answers": [ "ひぶん" ], "comment": "inscription; epitaph; epigraph" },
	{ "question": "確固", "answers": [ "かっこ" ], "comment": "firm; unshakeable; resolute" },
	{ "question": "確執", "answers": [ "かくしつ" ], "comment": "discord; antagonism" },
	{ "question": "確約", "answers": [ "かくやく" ], "comment": "firm promise; definite promise" },
	{ "question": "磁場", "answers": [ "じば", "じじょう" ], "comment": "magnetic field\nambience; atmosphere; focal point" },
	{ "question": "磁気", "answers": [ "じき" ], "comment": "magnetism" },
	{ "question": "磨き", "answers": [ "みがき" ], "comment": "polish; improvement; burnishing" },
	{ "question": "磯", "answers": [ "いそ" ], "comment": "(rocky) beach; seashore" },
	{ "question": "礎", "answers": [ "いしずえ" ], "comment": "foundation stone; cornerstone" },
	{ "question": "示し", "answers": [ "しめし" ], "comment": "discipline; revelation" },
	{ "question": "示談", "answers": [ "じだん" ], "comment": "settlement out of court" },
	{ "question": "礼服", "answers": [ "れいふく" ], "comment": "ceremonial dress; evening dress; dress suit; morning suit" },
	{ "question": "礼状", "answers": [ "れいじょう" ], "comment": "acknowledgment; acknowledgement; letter of thanks" },
	{ "question": "礼金", "answers": [ "れいきん" ], "comment": "finder's fee; reward; honorarium\nkey money" },
	{ "question": "社名", "answers": [ "しゃめい" ], "comment": "name of company" },
	{ "question": "社外", "answers": [ "しゃがい" ], "comment": "outside the company" },
	{ "question": "社宅", "answers": [ "しゃたく" ], "comment": "company owned house" },
	{ "question": "社屋", "answers": [ "しゃおく" ], "comment": "company office building" },
	{ "question": "社葬", "answers": [ "しゃそう" ], "comment": "company funeral" },
	{ "question": "祈念", "answers": [ "きねん" ], "comment": "prayer" },
	{ "question": "祈願", "answers": [ "きがん" ], "comment": "prayer; supplication" },
	{ "question": "祖", "answers": [ "そ" ], "comment": "ancestor; forefather; progenitor" },
	{ "question": "祝福", "answers": [ "しゅくふく" ], "comment": "blessing" },
	{ "question": "祝賀", "answers": [ "しゅくが" ], "comment": "celebration; congratulations" },
	{ "question": "祝辞", "answers": [ "しゅくじ" ], "comment": "congratulatory address" },
	{ "question": "祝電", "answers": [ "しゅくでん" ], "comment": "congratulatory telegram" },
	{ "question": "神主", "answers": [ "かんぬし", "かむぬし" ], "comment": "Shinto priest\nchief Shinto priest (of a shrine)\nWelsh onion; pun in Buddhist monk jargon" },
	{ "question": "神妙", "answers": [ "しんみょう" ], "comment": "meek; quiet; docile; humble; faithful; obedient\nmysterious; marvelous; marvellous" },
	{ "question": "神学", "answers": [ "しんがく" ], "comment": "theology" },
	{ "question": "神業", "answers": [ "かみわざ" ], "comment": "divine work; miracle; superhuman feat\nShinto ritual" },
	{ "question": "神楽", "answers": [ "かぐら" ], "comment": "ancient Shinto music and dancing" },
	{ "question": "神殿", "answers": [ "しんでん" ], "comment": "temple; sacred place; shrine; sanctuary; tabernacle" },
	{ "question": "票田", "answers": [ "ひょうでん" ], "comment": "(favorable voting) constituency (favourable)" },
	{ "question": "祭典", "answers": [ "さいてん" ], "comment": "festival" },
	{ "question": "祭壇", "answers": [ "さいだん" ], "comment": "altar" },
	{ "question": "禁句", "answers": [ "きんく" ], "comment": "taboo word" },
	{ "question": "禁固", "answers": [ "きんこ" ], "comment": "imprisonment; confinement" },
	{ "question": "禁物", "answers": [ "きんもつ" ], "comment": "taboo; forbidden thing" },
	{ "question": "禁輸", "answers": [ "きんゆ" ], "comment": "embargo" },
	{ "question": "禁酒", "answers": [ "きんしゅ" ], "comment": "prohibition; temperance; abstinence" },
	{ "question": "禅寺", "answers": [ "ぜんでら" ], "comment": "Zen temple" },
	{ "question": "福", "answers": [ "ふく" ], "comment": "good fortune" },
	{ "question": "福助", "answers": [ "ふくすけ" ], "comment": "large-headed dwarf statue, bringer of good luck" },
	{ "question": "秀作", "answers": [ "しゅうさく" ], "comment": "splendid (excellent) work" },
	{ "question": "秀才", "answers": [ "しゅうさい" ], "comment": "bright person; talented student; prodigy" },
	{ "question": "私大", "answers": [ "しだい" ], "comment": "private university or college" },
	{ "question": "私学", "answers": [ "しがく" ], "comment": "private (non-governmental) school (college, university)" },
	{ "question": "私有", "answers": [ "しゆう" ], "comment": "private ownership" },
	{ "question": "私服", "answers": [ "しふく" ], "comment": "civilian clothes; plain clothes; mufti\nplainclothes police officer" },
	{ "question": "私案", "answers": [ "しあん" ], "comment": "private plan; one's own plan" },
	{ "question": "私用", "answers": [ "しよう" ], "comment": "personal use\nprivate business" },
	{ "question": "私見", "answers": [ "しけん" ], "comment": "personal opinion" },
	{ "question": "私設", "answers": [ "しせつ" ], "comment": "private" },
	{ "question": "私語", "answers": [ "しご" ], "comment": "whispering; whisper; secret talk; murmur" },
	{ "question": "私費", "answers": [ "しひ" ], "comment": "private expense" },
	{ "question": "私邸", "answers": [ "してい" ], "comment": "private residence" },
	{ "question": "秋分", "answers": [ "しゅうぶん" ], "comment": "autumnal equinox; autumn equinox; fall equinox" },
	{ "question": "秋口", "answers": [ "あきぐち" ], "comment": "beginning of autumn; beginning of fall" },
	{ "question": "秋季", "answers": [ "しゅうき" ], "comment": "fall season; autumn season" },
	{ "question": "秋風", "answers": [ "しゅうふう", "あきかぜ" ], "comment": "autumn breeze; fall breeze" },
	{ "question": "科する", "answers": [ "かする" ], "comment": "to inflict; to impose (a fine, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "秒読み", "answers": [ "びょうよみ" ], "comment": "countdown" },
	{ "question": "秒速", "answers": [ "びょうそく" ], "comment": "per second" },
	{ "question": "秘訣", "answers": [ "ひけつ" ], "comment": "secret (method, trick, etc.); mysteries (of an art, trade, etc.); key (e.g. to success); recipe" },
	{ "question": "秘話", "answers": [ "ひわ" ], "comment": "secret story; unknown episode" },
	{ "question": "租税", "answers": [ "そぜい" ], "comment": "taxes; taxation" },
	{ "question": "秤", "answers": [ "はかり" ], "comment": "scales; weighing machine" },
	{ "question": "称する", "answers": [ "しょうする" ], "comment": "to take the name of; to call oneself\nto pretend; to feign; to purport" },
	{ "question": "称号", "answers": [ "しょうごう" ], "comment": "title; name; degree" },
	{ "question": "移り変わり", "answers": [ "うつりかわり" ], "comment": "change (e.g. season)" },
	{ "question": "移管", "answers": [ "いかん" ], "comment": "transfer of control" },
	{ "question": "移籍", "answers": [ "いせき" ], "comment": "changing household registry; transfer (e.g. of one's name in the register)\ntransferring to a different team" },
	{ "question": "移譲", "answers": [ "いじょう" ], "comment": "transfer; assignment" },
	{ "question": "移送", "answers": [ "いそう" ], "comment": "transfer; transport; removal" },
	{ "question": "税制", "answers": [ "ぜいせい" ], "comment": "tax system" },
	{ "question": "税収", "answers": [ "ぜいしゅう" ], "comment": "tax yields; revenue" },
	{ "question": "税引き", "answers": [ "ぜいびき" ], "comment": "tax excluded" },
	{ "question": "税込み", "answers": [ "ぜいこみ" ], "comment": "tax included (e.g. price); before tax (e.g. salary)" },
	{ "question": "税額", "answers": [ "ぜいがく" ], "comment": "amount of tax" },
	{ "question": "稚魚", "answers": [ "ちぎょ" ], "comment": "fry; juvenile fish; fingerling" },
	{ "question": "種別", "answers": [ "しゅべつ" ], "comment": "classification; assortment" },
	{ "question": "種子", "answers": [ "しゅし" ], "comment": "seed; pit" },
	{ "question": "種目", "answers": [ "しゅもく" ], "comment": "event; item of business" },
	{ "question": "稲作", "answers": [ "いなさく" ], "comment": "rice cultivation; rice crop" },
	{ "question": "稲妻", "answers": [ "いなずま", "いなづま" ], "comment": "lightning; flash of lightning; lightning bolt" },
	{ "question": "稲田", "answers": [ "いなだ" ], "comment": "paddy field; rice field" },
	{ "question": "稼働", "answers": [ "かどう" ], "comment": "operation (of machine); operating; running; working" },
	{ "question": "稿", "answers": [ "こう" ], "comment": "manuscript; version; draft" },
	{ "question": "穂", "answers": [ "ほ" ], "comment": "ear (of plant); head (of plant)\npoint; tip\nscion (in grafting); cion" },
	{ "question": "積", "answers": [ "せき" ], "comment": "product\nvolume; area" },
	{ "question": "積み立て", "answers": [ "つみたて" ], "comment": "saving; savings; accumulation; putting aside; reserving" },
	{ "question": "積み込む", "answers": [ "つみこむ" ], "comment": "to load (with goods, cargo); to put on board; to stow aboard" },
	{ "question": "積み重ね", "answers": [ "つみかさね" ], "comment": "pile; accumulation" },
	{ "question": "積立", "answers": [ "つみたて" ], "comment": "saving; savings; accumulation; putting aside; reserving" },
	{ "question": "積算", "answers": [ "せきさん" ], "comment": "addition; adding up\nintegration\nestimate; quantity survey" },
	{ "question": "積載", "answers": [ "せきさい" ], "comment": "lading; loading; carrying" },
	{ "question": "積雪", "answers": [ "せきせつ" ], "comment": "fallen snow; snow cover" },
	{ "question": "穏健", "answers": [ "おんけん" ], "comment": "quiet; dependable; uniform; (politically) moderate" },
	{ "question": "穏和", "answers": [ "おんわ" ], "comment": "gentle; mild; moderate" },
	{ "question": "穴埋め", "answers": [ "あなうめ" ], "comment": "filling in gaps; filling in blanks (in a form, etc.); stopgap; temporary measure\ncovering up a deficit; making up for something (e.g. one's mistake)" },
	{ "question": "究明", "answers": [ "きゅうめい" ], "comment": "investigation (esp. in academic and scientific contexts)" },
	{ "question": "空き地", "answers": [ "くうち", "あきち" ], "comment": "vacant land" },
	{ "question": "空き家", "answers": [ "あきや" ], "comment": "vacant house; unoccupied house" },
	{ "question": "空き缶", "answers": [ "あきかん" ], "comment": "empty can" },
	{ "question": "空前", "answers": [ "くうぜん" ], "comment": "unprecedented; record-breaking" },
	{ "question": "空地", "answers": [ "くうち", "あきち" ], "comment": "vacant land" },
	{ "question": "空域", "answers": [ "くういき" ], "comment": "airspace" },
	{ "question": "空席", "answers": [ "くうせき" ], "comment": "empty seat; unoccupied seat\nvacancy; vacant post" },
	{ "question": "空手", "answers": [ "からて" ], "comment": "karate\nempty handed" },
	{ "question": "空振り", "answers": [ "からぶり" ], "comment": "striking (at something) and missing; in vain" },
	{ "question": "空洞", "answers": [ "くうどう" ], "comment": "cave; hollow; cavity\nhollow" },
	{ "question": "空爆", "answers": [ "くうばく" ], "comment": "aerial bombing" },
	{ "question": "空砲", "answers": [ "くうほう" ], "comment": "empty gun; gun loaded with blanks; firing a blank" },
	{ "question": "空虚", "answers": [ "くうきょ" ], "comment": "emptiness; hollowness; vacancy; void\ninanity; pointlessness; meaninglessness" },
	{ "question": "空調", "answers": [ "くうちょう" ], "comment": "air conditioning" },
	{ "question": "空路", "answers": [ "くうろ" ], "comment": "air lane" },
	{ "question": "空車", "answers": [ "からぐるま", "あきぐるま", "くうしゃ" ], "comment": "empty conveyance; free taxi\nparking lot with spaces available" },
	{ "question": "空軍", "answers": [ "くうぐん" ], "comment": "Air Force" },
	{ "question": "空転", "answers": [ "くうてん" ], "comment": "racing (an engine); idling (an engine)\ngoing in circles (esp. argument, discussion, etc.); spinning one's wheels" },
	{ "question": "空輸", "answers": [ "くうゆ" ], "comment": "air transport" },
	{ "question": "突き", "answers": [ "つき" ], "comment": "thrust; stab; lunge; pass (in fencing)\ntsuki; thrust to the throat (in kendo)\ntsuki; thrust to the chest" },
	{ "question": "突き上げる", "answers": [ "つきあげる" ], "comment": "to push up; to force up; to toss\nto pressure one's superiors\nto burst out (of emotions, etc.); to fill one's heart" },
	{ "question": "突き刺す", "answers": [ "つきさす" ], "comment": "to stab; to pierce; to thrust" },
	{ "question": "突き抜ける", "answers": [ "つきぬける" ], "comment": "to pierce through; to break through" },
	{ "question": "突っ張り", "answers": [ "つっぱり" ], "comment": "prop; strut; support; bar\nbecoming taut; bracing\nthrust; slapping attacks\n(juvenile) delinquent; punk" },
	{ "question": "突っ張る", "answers": [ "つっぱる" ], "comment": "to support; to become stiff; to become taut; to thrust (one's opponent); to stick to (one's opinion); to insist on" },
	{ "question": "突出", "answers": [ "とっしゅつ" ], "comment": "projection; protrusion" },
	{ "question": "突起", "answers": [ "とっき" ], "comment": "protuberance; projection; prominence; bump; boss; process; apophysis" },
	{ "question": "突進", "answers": [ "とっしん" ], "comment": "rush; charge" },
	{ "question": "突風", "answers": [ "とっぷう" ], "comment": "squall; sudden gust" },
	{ "question": "窃盗", "answers": [ "せっとう" ], "comment": "theft; stealing; larceny" },
	{ "question": "窒息", "answers": [ "ちっそく" ], "comment": "suffocation; choking; asphyxia" },
	{ "question": "窒素", "answers": [ "ちっそ" ], "comment": "nitrogen (N)" },
	{ "question": "窓際", "answers": [ "まどぎわ" ], "comment": "(at the) window" },
	{ "question": "窪み", "answers": [ "へこみ", "くぼみ" ], "comment": "hollow; cavity; dent; depression" },
	{ "question": "窮地", "answers": [ "きゅうち" ], "comment": "dilemma; predicament" },
	{ "question": "窮状", "answers": [ "きゅうじょう" ], "comment": "distress; wretched condition" },
	{ "question": "窯", "answers": [ "かま" ], "comment": "stove; furnace; kiln" },
	{ "question": "立ち", "answers": [ "たち" ], "comment": "departure; setting off; start\nbeing used up; being consumed; being burnt out\npassage of time; lapse\nrehearsal\nleading male role in kabuki\nrising from a crouch to charge; initial charge; faceoff\nverb prefix conveying emphasis and sometimes formality" },
	{ "question": "立ち上がり", "answers": [ "たちあがり" ], "comment": "start; beginning; build up\nhow well a pitcher pitches at the start of the game" },
	{ "question": "立ち会い", "answers": [ "たちあい" ], "comment": "presence (e.g. of an observer); observation; observer; witness\ntrading session (at an exchange)" },
	{ "question": "立ち入り", "answers": [ "たちいり" ], "comment": "entering; going into" },
	{ "question": "立ち消え", "answers": [ "たちぎえ" ], "comment": "going out (e.g. of a fire); dying out\nfizzling out; falling through; coming to nothing" },
	{ "question": "立ち直り", "answers": [ "たちなおり" ], "comment": "recovery; restoration" },
	{ "question": "立ち話", "answers": [ "たちばなし" ], "comment": "talking while standing; standing around talking" },
	{ "question": "立ち読み", "answers": [ "たちよみ" ], "comment": "reading while standing (in a bookstore, etc.); browsing (i.e. reading an item but not buying it)" },
	{ "question": "立ち退き", "answers": [ "たちのき" ], "comment": "eviction" },
	{ "question": "立ち退く", "answers": [ "たちのく" ], "comment": "to evacuate; to clear out; to vacate; to withdraw; to take refuge" },
	{ "question": "立て替える", "answers": [ "たてかえる" ], "comment": "to pay an advance; to put down money on something\nto pay for another; to pay someone else's debt as a loan to him" },
	{ "question": "立て札", "answers": [ "たてふだ" ], "comment": "bulletin board; notice board; billboard; roadside sign; sign on a post, usu. wooden, esp. containing information about a sight, warning, congratulations, etc." },
	{ "question": "立て直す", "answers": [ "たてなおす" ], "comment": "to rally; to make over; to rearrange; to reorganize; to reorganise" },
	{ "question": "立て続け", "answers": [ "たてつづけ" ], "comment": "succession; continuation; series; sequence" },
	{ "question": "立て込む", "answers": [ "たてこむ" ], "comment": "to be crowded\nto be busy" },
	{ "question": "立会い", "answers": [ "たちあい" ], "comment": "presence (e.g. of an observer); observation; observer; witness\ntrading session (at an exchange)" },
	{ "question": "立国", "answers": [ "りっこく" ], "comment": "founding of a nation" },
	{ "question": "立憲", "answers": [ "りっけん" ], "comment": "constitutionalism" },
	{ "question": "立札", "answers": [ "たてふだ" ], "comment": "bulletin board; notice board; billboard; roadside sign; sign on a post, usu. wooden, esp. containing information about a sight, warning, congratulations, etc." },
	{ "question": "立案", "answers": [ "りつあん" ], "comment": "draft; draught; (rough) design" },
	{ "question": "立脚", "answers": [ "りっきゃく" ], "comment": "being based on" },
	{ "question": "竜王", "answers": [ "りゅうおう" ], "comment": "Dragon King\npromoted rook" },
	{ "question": "童謡", "answers": [ "どうよう" ], "comment": "children's song; nursery rhyme" },
	{ "question": "端緒", "answers": [ "たんちょ", "たんしょ" ], "comment": "a clue; start; beginning" },
	{ "question": "競り合い", "answers": [ "せりあい" ], "comment": "competition" },
	{ "question": "競り合う", "answers": [ "せりあう" ], "comment": "to struggle for; to compete with; to vie with" },
	{ "question": "競る", "answers": [ "せる" ], "comment": "to compete\nto bid\nto sell at auction" },
	{ "question": "競売", "answers": [ "けいばい", "きょうばい" ], "comment": "auction" },
	{ "question": "競泳", "answers": [ "きょうえい" ], "comment": "competitive swimming; swimming race" },
	{ "question": "競演", "answers": [ "きょうえん" ], "comment": "recital contest" },
	{ "question": "競艇", "answers": [ "きょうてい" ], "comment": "boat race" },
	{ "question": "競走", "answers": [ "きょうそう" ], "comment": "race" },
	{ "question": "競輪", "answers": [ "けいりん" ], "comment": "keirin; cycle racing event, usu. 2km with a paced start and sprint finish" },
	{ "question": "笑い声", "answers": [ "わらいごえ" ], "comment": "laughter" },
	{ "question": "笑み", "answers": [ "えみ" ], "comment": "smile" },
	{ "question": "笠", "answers": [ "かさ" ], "comment": "conical hat (East-Asian style); coolie hat\nsomething shaped like a conical hat or an umbrella; shade (of a lamp); mushroom cap; pileus" },
	{ "question": "第", "answers": [ "だい" ], "comment": "prefix for forming ordinal numbers" },
	{ "question": "第一", "answers": [ "だいいち" ], "comment": "first; foremost; number one" },
	{ "question": "笹", "answers": [ "ささ" ], "comment": "bamboo grass; generally smaller species of running bamboo that do not shed their sheaths (e.g. Sasa spp.)" },
	{ "question": "筆跡", "answers": [ "ふであと", "ひっせき" ], "comment": "handwriting\ncalligraphy specimen; example of penmanship; holograph" },
	{ "question": "筆順", "answers": [ "ひつじゅん" ], "comment": "stroke order" },
	{ "question": "等価", "answers": [ "とうか" ], "comment": "equivalence" },
	{ "question": "等身", "answers": [ "とうしん" ], "comment": "body proportions" },
	{ "question": "筋力", "answers": [ "きんりょく" ], "comment": "physical strength; muscle strength" },
	{ "question": "筋書き", "answers": [ "すじがき" ], "comment": "synopsis; outline; plot" },
	{ "question": "筋道", "answers": [ "すじみち" ], "comment": "reason; logic\nmethod; system; order; thread (e.g. of an argument)" },
	{ "question": "筐体", "answers": [ "きょうたい" ], "comment": "case (of a machine, computer, etc.); casing; housing; enclosure; cabinet; chassis; frame" },
	{ "question": "筒井", "answers": [ "つつい" ], "comment": "round well" },
	{ "question": "答弁", "answers": [ "とうべん" ], "comment": "response; reply; answer; defence; defense" },
	{ "question": "答申", "answers": [ "とうしん" ], "comment": "report; reply; findings" },
	{ "question": "策略", "answers": [ "さくりゃく" ], "comment": "scheme; tactic; stratagem; trick" },
	{ "question": "算出", "answers": [ "さんしゅつ" ], "comment": "calculation; computation" },
	{ "question": "管内", "answers": [ "かんない" ], "comment": "within the jurisdiction of" },
	{ "question": "管制", "answers": [ "かんせい" ], "comment": "control" },
	{ "question": "管区", "answers": [ "かんく" ], "comment": "jurisdiction" },
	{ "question": "管弦楽", "answers": [ "かんげんがく" ], "comment": "orchestral music" },
	{ "question": "管財", "answers": [ "かんざい" ], "comment": "administration of property; custodianship; receivership" },
	{ "question": "管長", "answers": [ "かんちょう" ], "comment": "superintendent priest; chief abbot" },
	{ "question": "節句", "answers": [ "せっく" ], "comment": "seasonal festival" },
	{ "question": "節度", "answers": [ "せつど" ], "comment": "moderation; standard" },
	{ "question": "節減", "answers": [ "せつげん" ], "comment": "retrenchment; curtailment; economy" },
	{ "question": "節目", "answers": [ "ふしめ", "フシめ" ], "comment": "turning point; critical juncture\nknot (in a tree, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "範", "answers": [ "はん" ], "comment": "example; model" },
	{ "question": "築き上げる", "answers": [ "きずきあげる" ], "comment": "to build up; to establish (one's reputation)" },
	{ "question": "築地", "answers": [ "ついじ", "つきじ" ], "comment": "mud wall with a roof; roofed mud wall" },
	{ "question": "簡略", "answers": [ "かんりゃく" ], "comment": "simple; simplicity; brief; brevity" },
	{ "question": "簡素", "answers": [ "かんそ" ], "comment": "simplicity; plain" },
	{ "question": "簡裁", "answers": [ "かんさい" ], "comment": "summary court; court of summary offences" },
	{ "question": "籤引", "answers": [ "くじびき" ], "comment": "lottery; drawn lot" },
	{ "question": "籤引き", "answers": [ "くじびき" ], "comment": "lottery; drawn lot" },
	{ "question": "米人", "answers": [ "べいじん" ], "comment": "an American" },
	{ "question": "米価", "answers": [ "べいか" ], "comment": "rice price" },
	{ "question": "米倉", "answers": [ "こめぐら" ], "comment": "rice granary" },
	{ "question": "米穀", "answers": [ "べいこく" ], "comment": "rice" },
	{ "question": "米飯", "answers": [ "べいはん" ], "comment": "cooked rice" },
	{ "question": "粉末", "answers": [ "ふんまつ" ], "comment": "fine powder" },
	{ "question": "粗大", "answers": [ "そだい" ], "comment": "coarse; rough; bulky" },
	{ "question": "粗鋼", "answers": [ "そこう" ], "comment": "crude steel" },
	{ "question": "粘り", "answers": [ "ねばり" ], "comment": "stickiness; viscosity\ntenacity; persistence" },
	{ "question": "粘り強い", "answers": [ "ねばりづよい" ], "comment": "tenacious; persevering; persistent; stubborn; steadfast\nsticky" },
	{ "question": "粘る", "answers": [ "ねばる" ], "comment": "to be sticky; to be adhesive\nto persevere; to persist; to stick to; to hold out; to linger" },
	{ "question": "粘土", "answers": [ "ねばつち", "ねんど" ], "comment": "clay" },
	{ "question": "粘着", "answers": [ "ねんちゃく" ], "comment": "cohesion; adhesion" },
	{ "question": "粘膜", "answers": [ "ねんまく" ], "comment": "mucous membrane" },
	{ "question": "精巧", "answers": [ "せいこう" ], "comment": "elaborate; delicate; exquisite" },
	{ "question": "精度", "answers": [ "せいど" ], "comment": "precision; accuracy" },
	{ "question": "精彩", "answers": [ "せいさい" ], "comment": "brilliance; luster; lustre; colorfulness; colourfulness\nvividness; life" },
	{ "question": "精算", "answers": [ "せいさん" ], "comment": "exact calculation; squaring of accounts; adjustment" },
	{ "question": "精米", "answers": [ "せいまい" ], "comment": "rice polishing; polished rice" },
	{ "question": "精製", "answers": [ "せいせい" ], "comment": "refining; purification" },
	{ "question": "精通", "answers": [ "せいつう" ], "comment": "acquaintance; having knowledge; being expert; being versed in; conversant\nfirst ejaculation" },
	{ "question": "精鋭", "answers": [ "せいえい" ], "comment": "elite; best; pick; cream of the crop" },
	{ "question": "糖", "answers": [ "とう" ], "comment": "sugar" },
	{ "question": "糸口", "answers": [ "いとぐち" ], "comment": "thread end\nbeginning\nclue" },
	{ "question": "紀行", "answers": [ "きこう" ], "comment": "traveller's journal; traveler's journal; travelogue" },
	{ "question": "紅潮", "answers": [ "こうちょう" ], "comment": "flush; blush" },
	{ "question": "紅白", "answers": [ "こうはく" ], "comment": "red and white; colours for festive or auspicious occasions (colors)\nRed and White singing contest; annual contest between male and female popular singers on New Year's Eve (sponsored and broadcast by NHK)" },
	{ "question": "紋", "answers": [ "もん" ], "comment": "(family) crest; coat of arms" },
	{ "question": "納まる", "answers": [ "おさまる" ], "comment": "to be in one's place; to be installed; to settle into\nto be delivered; to be obtained; to be paid\nto be settled; to be sorted out\nto lessen (e.g. of storms, pain); to calm down\nto be fit tightly into (e.g. a frame); to be sheathed (in a scabbard)" },
	{ "question": "納付", "answers": [ "のうふ" ], "comment": "payment; supply" },
	{ "question": "納入", "answers": [ "のうにゅう" ], "comment": "payment (taxes, fees, etc.)\nsupply (of goods); delivery" },
	{ "question": "納税", "answers": [ "のうぜい" ], "comment": "payment of taxes" },
	{ "question": "納金", "answers": [ "のうきん" ], "comment": "payment" },
	{ "question": "純度", "answers": [ "じゅんど" ], "comment": "purity (of a substance)" },
	{ "question": "純益", "answers": [ "じゅんえき" ], "comment": "clear profit; net income; net profit" },
	{ "question": "純金", "answers": [ "じゅんきん" ], "comment": "pure gold; solid gold; fine gold" },
	{ "question": "紙上", "answers": [ "しじょう" ], "comment": "on paper; in the newspapers; in a letter" },
	{ "question": "紙屑", "answers": [ "かみくず" ], "comment": "wastepaper; paper scraps; paper waste" },
	{ "question": "紙芝居", "answers": [ "かみしばい" ], "comment": "picture story show" },
	{ "question": "紙袋", "answers": [ "かみぶくろ", "かんぶくろ" ], "comment": "paper bag" },
	{ "question": "紙面", "answers": [ "しめん" ], "comment": "space on a page (e.g. in a newspaper)\nsurface of paper\nletter; writings; document" },
	{ "question": "紛らす", "answers": [ "まぎらす" ], "comment": "to divert (e.g. one's mind); to distract; to relieve (e.g. boredom)\nto conceal (e.g. one's sorrow with a smile); to shift (the conversation)" },
	{ "question": "紛らわしい", "answers": [ "まぎらわしい" ], "comment": "confusing; misleading; equivocal; ambiguous; easily mixed up (e.g. similar words)" },
	{ "question": "紛れる", "answers": [ "まぎれる" ], "comment": "to disappear into; to be lost in; to slip into; to get mixed in among\nto do something under the cover of (confusion, etc.)\nto be almost indistinguishable; to be confusingly similar\nto be diverted from (negative emotions, etc.); to forget about\nto be distracted by; to be too absorbed in" },
	{ "question": "紛失", "answers": [ "ふんしつ" ], "comment": "losing something" },
	{ "question": "紛糾", "answers": [ "ふんきゅう" ], "comment": "complication; confusion; disorder" },
	{ "question": "素子", "answers": [ "そし" ], "comment": "element (esp. component in electronics); elemental device; device\ndata; datum" },
	{ "question": "素案", "answers": [ "そあん" ], "comment": "draft; draught" },
	{ "question": "素顔", "answers": [ "すがお" ], "comment": "face with no make-up; unpainted face\nhonesty; frankness" },
	{ "question": "紡績", "answers": [ "ぼうせき" ], "comment": "spinning" },
	{ "question": "累積", "answers": [ "るいせき" ], "comment": "accumulation" },
	{ "question": "累計", "answers": [ "るいけい" ], "comment": "cumulative total; accumulated total; total up to now" },
	{ "question": "累進", "answers": [ "るいしん" ], "comment": "successive promotion; gradual promotion; graduated" },
	{ "question": "細々", "answers": [ "こまごま", "ほそぼそ" ], "comment": "minutely; in detail; with particular attention /\n poor (living)\nbarely continuing; just scraping along\nvery narrow" },
	{ "question": "細分", "answers": [ "さいぶん" ], "comment": "divide into small portions" },
	{ "question": "細心", "answers": [ "さいしん" ], "comment": "meticulous; careful; discreet; scrupulous; prudent" },
	{ "question": "細目", "answers": [ "さいもく" ], "comment": "particulars; details; specified items" },
	{ "question": "紺屋", "answers": [ "こんや", "こうや" ], "comment": "dyer" },
	{ "question": "終値", "answers": [ "おわりね" ], "comment": "closing price (e.g. stock exchange)" },
	{ "question": "終局", "answers": [ "しゅうきょく" ], "comment": "end; close; conclusion; denouement; finale; end of a game of go" },
	{ "question": "終息", "answers": [ "しゅうそく" ], "comment": "having ended; being resolved" },
	{ "question": "終日", "answers": [ "ひめもす", "ひねもす", "ひもすがら", "しゅうじつ" ], "comment": "all day; for a whole day" },
	{ "question": "終末", "answers": [ "しゅうまつ" ], "comment": "an end; a close" },
	{ "question": "終焉", "answers": [ "しゅうえん" ], "comment": "demise" },
	{ "question": "終盤", "answers": [ "しゅうばん" ], "comment": "endgame; final stage" },
	{ "question": "終身", "answers": [ "しゅうしん" ], "comment": "the whole life" },
	{ "question": "終電", "answers": [ "しゅうでん" ], "comment": "last train" },
	{ "question": "組み替え", "answers": [ "くみかえ" ], "comment": "rearrangement (of classes); recomposition; recombination; reclassification" },
	{ "question": "組み立て", "answers": [ "くみたて" ], "comment": "construction; framework; erection; assembly; organization; organisation" },
	{ "question": "組み込む", "answers": [ "くみこむ" ], "comment": "to insert; to include; to incorporate; to cut in (printing)" },
	{ "question": "組曲", "answers": [ "くみきょく" ], "comment": "musical suite; musical selection" },
	{ "question": "組長", "answers": [ "くみちょう" ], "comment": "boss (esp. yakuza); foreman" },
	{ "question": "組閣", "answers": [ "そかく" ], "comment": "formation of a cabinet" },
	{ "question": "経常", "answers": [ "けいつね", "けいじょう" ], "comment": "ordinary" },
	{ "question": "経路", "answers": [ "けいろ" ], "comment": "course; route; path; channel\nprocess; means" },
	{ "question": "結う", "answers": [ "いう", "ゆう" ], "comment": "to do up (hair); to braid; to fasten; to fix" },
	{ "question": "結び", "answers": [ "むすび" ], "comment": "ending; conclusion\njoin; union; connecting\nknot; knotting\nrice ball" },
	{ "question": "結党", "answers": [ "けっとう" ], "comment": "formation of a party" },
	{ "question": "結束", "answers": [ "けっそく" ], "comment": "union; unity; solidarity\nbundling; binding; tying\nputting on (clothes, armour, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "結社", "answers": [ "けっしゃ" ], "comment": "association; society" },
	{ "question": "結集", "answers": [ "けっしゅう" ], "comment": "concentration; regimentation" },
	{ "question": "絞り", "answers": [ "しぼり" ], "comment": "tye-dye; tye-dyeing\naperture (e.g. camera, iris of the eye); aperture stop; stop\ncontraction; squeezing; choke" },
	{ "question": "絞り込む", "answers": [ "しぼりこむ" ], "comment": "to squeeze; to wring out\nto narrow down; to refine" },
	{ "question": "給水", "answers": [ "きゅうすい" ], "comment": "water supply" },
	{ "question": "給油", "answers": [ "きゅうゆ" ], "comment": "refueling (car, plane, etc.)\nlubricating (a machine); oiling" },
	{ "question": "統括", "answers": [ "とうかつ" ], "comment": "unification; bringing together; generalization\ncontrol; supervision" },
	{ "question": "絵巻", "answers": [ "えまき" ], "comment": "picture scroll" },
	{ "question": "絵葉書", "answers": [ "えはがき" ], "comment": "picture postcard" },
	{ "question": "絶交", "answers": [ "ぜっこう" ], "comment": "breaking off a relationship; permanent breach of friendship; rupture" },
	{ "question": "絶句", "answers": [ "ぜっく" ], "comment": "being lost for words; becoming speechless\njueju (Chinese quatrain with lines of either five or seven syllables)" },
	{ "question": "絶大", "answers": [ "ぜつだい" ], "comment": "tremendous; immense" },
	{ "question": "絶妙", "answers": [ "ぜつみょう" ], "comment": "exquisite; superb; perfect; miraculous" },
	{ "question": "絶縁", "answers": [ "ぜつえん" ], "comment": "breaking off relations; disconnection\ninsulation (esp. electrical); isolation" },
	{ "question": "絶頂", "answers": [ "ぜっちょう" ], "comment": "top (of a mountain); summit\npeak; height; zenith; climax" },
	{ "question": "絹糸", "answers": [ "きぬいと", "けんし" ], "comment": "silk thread" },
	{ "question": "続出", "answers": [ "ぞくしゅつ" ], "comment": "appearance one after another" },
	{ "question": "続編", "answers": [ "ぞくへん" ], "comment": "continuation; sequel" },
	{ "question": "続行", "answers": [ "ぞっこう" ], "comment": "continuation; continuance; going on; resuming" },
	{ "question": "綱引き", "answers": [ "つなひき" ], "comment": "tug of war (orig. a form of divination to predict whether the year will be favourable or unfavourable)\nforward puller (of a rickshaw)" },
	{ "question": "綱渡り", "answers": [ "つなわたり" ], "comment": "tightrope walking; funambulism" },
	{ "question": "綱領", "answers": [ "こうりょう" ], "comment": "general plan; main points; summary; platform (e.g. for a campaign); mission statement" },
	{ "question": "網", "answers": [ "あみ" ], "comment": "net; netting\nweb" },
	{ "question": "網戸", "answers": [ "あみど" ], "comment": "window screen; insect screen; mosquito screen; screen; screen door" },
	{ "question": "網羅", "answers": [ "もうら" ], "comment": "comprising; including; covering; encompassing; comprehending" },
	{ "question": "網膜", "answers": [ "もうまく" ], "comment": "retina" },
	{ "question": "綴", "answers": [ "つづり" ], "comment": "spelling\northography\npatching; binding" },
	{ "question": "綴じる", "answers": [ "とじる" ], "comment": "to bind; to file\nto top with egg (e.g. donburi)" },
	{ "question": "綴り", "answers": [ "つづり" ], "comment": "spelling\northography\npatching; binding" },
	{ "question": "綿密", "answers": [ "めんみつ" ], "comment": "minute; detailed; careful; scrupulous; thorough" },
	{ "question": "緊密", "answers": [ "きんみつ" ], "comment": "rigour; rigor; closeness; compactness; tightly knit" },
	{ "question": "緊縮", "answers": [ "きんしゅく" ], "comment": "shrinkage; contraction; economy; retrenchment" },
	{ "question": "緊迫", "answers": [ "きんぱく" ], "comment": "tension; strain" },
	{ "question": "総体", "answers": [ "そうたい" ], "comment": "the whole; originally" },
	{ "question": "総力", "answers": [ "そうりょく" ], "comment": "total energy; all efforts" },
	{ "question": "総勢", "answers": [ "そうぜい" ], "comment": "all members; whole army" },
	{ "question": "総帥", "answers": [ "そうすい" ], "comment": "commander-in-chief; leader; head of a group of companies" },
	{ "question": "総意", "answers": [ "そうい" ], "comment": "consensus of opinion" },
	{ "question": "総監", "answers": [ "そうかん" ], "comment": "inspector general; commissioner" },
	{ "question": "総統", "answers": [ "そうとう" ], "comment": "supreme ruler; generalissimo\npresident (of Taiwan)\nfuhrer; fuehrer" },
	{ "question": "総評", "answers": [ "そうひょう" ], "comment": "general comment\nSohyo (General Council of Trade Unions of Japan)" },
	{ "question": "総論", "answers": [ "そうろん" ], "comment": "general remarks" },
	{ "question": "総量", "answers": [ "そうりょう" ], "comment": "aggregate amount" },
	{ "question": "総長", "answers": [ "そうちょう" ], "comment": "(college) president; secretary-general" },
	{ "question": "緑化", "answers": [ "りょくか", "りょっか" ], "comment": "greening (i.e. planting to increase greenery); tree planting; afforestation" },
	{ "question": "緑地", "answers": [ "りょくち" ], "comment": "green tract of land" },
	{ "question": "緑茶", "answers": [ "りょくちゃ" ], "comment": "green tea; Japanese tea" },
	{ "question": "緒", "answers": [ "お" ], "comment": "cord; strap; thong\nstring (of a musical instrument, bow, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "線量", "answers": [ "せんりょう" ], "comment": "dose (of radioactivity)" },
	{ "question": "締まる", "answers": [ "しまる" ], "comment": "to be shut; to close; to be closed\nto be firm (of a body, face, etc.); to be well-knit\nto be locked\nto tighten; to be tightened\nto become sober; to become tense" },
	{ "question": "締め", "answers": [ "しめ" ], "comment": "tie up; bind; fastening; tightening\nsum; total amount; total\njudo choking (strangling) techniques\nlast meal eaten when going restaurant hopping\ncompletion; conclusion; rounding off\ncounter for bundles; counter for faggots; counter for bundles of 2000 sheets of paper\nend mark; closure mark" },
	{ "question": "締め付け", "answers": [ "しめつけ" ], "comment": "pressure; clamping; tightening; fastening" },
	{ "question": "締め出す", "answers": [ "しめだす" ], "comment": "to shut out; to bar; to lock out; to exclude" },
	{ "question": "締約", "answers": [ "ていやく" ], "comment": "conclusion of a treaty" },
	{ "question": "編入", "answers": [ "へんにゅう" ], "comment": "admission; incorporation" },
	{ "question": "編者", "answers": [ "へんじゃ", "へんしゃ" ], "comment": "editor; compiler" },
	{ "question": "編著", "answers": [ "へんちょ" ], "comment": "compilation" },
	{ "question": "緩急", "answers": [ "かんきゅう" ], "comment": "pace; tempo; slow and fast\nin case of emergency" },
	{ "question": "練り", "answers": [ "ねり" ], "comment": "kneading; gloss; tempering\npaste (e.g. bean paste, mustard paste)\nparading of portable shrines and floats at festivals" },
	{ "question": "縁側", "answers": [ "えんがわ" ], "comment": "veranda; porch; balcony; open corridor\nbone at the base of a fin; meat at the base of a fin (esp. of a flatfish)" },
	{ "question": "縁談", "answers": [ "えんだん" ], "comment": "marriage proposal; marriage talks" },
	{ "question": "縁起", "answers": [ "えんぎ" ], "comment": "omen; sign of luck\norigin; causation" },
	{ "question": "縄張り", "answers": [ "なわばり" ], "comment": "stretching a rope around; roping off; cordoning off; demarcation\none's turf; domain; territory; jurisdiction; sphere of influence" },
	{ "question": "縄文", "answers": [ "じょうもん" ], "comment": "Jōmon period\nstraw-rope pattern" },
	{ "question": "縛り首", "answers": [ "しばりくび" ], "comment": "(death by) hanging" },
	{ "question": "縦断", "answers": [ "じゅうだん" ], "comment": "running through (north-south); cutting across; travelling across\ncutting vertically; sectioning longitudinally" },
	{ "question": "縦書", "answers": [ "たてがき" ], "comment": "vertical writing" },
	{ "question": "縦書き", "answers": [ "たてがき" ], "comment": "vertical writing" },
	{ "question": "縦横", "answers": [ "じゅうおう", "たてよこ" ], "comment": "length and width; length and breadth; lengthwise and crosswise; longitude and latitude; vertical and horizontal\nfour cardinal points; every direction\nas one wishes; as one pleases; at will\nwarp and weft; warp and woof" },
	{ "question": "縫目", "answers": [ "ぬいめ" ], "comment": "seam; stitch; suture" },
	{ "question": "縫製", "answers": [ "ほうせい" ], "comment": "sewing" },
	{ "question": "縮まる", "answers": [ "ちぢまる" ], "comment": "to shorten; to narrow; to close" },
	{ "question": "縮み", "answers": [ "ちぢみ" ], "comment": "shrinkage\ncotton crepe" },
	{ "question": "織り", "answers": [ "おり" ], "comment": "weave; weaving; woven item" },
	{ "question": "織る", "answers": [ "おる" ], "comment": "to weave" },
	{ "question": "織物", "answers": [ "おりもの" ], "comment": "textile; fabric" },
	{ "question": "繕う", "answers": [ "つくろう" ], "comment": "to mend; to patch up; to repair; to fix; to darn; to trim\nto fix (hair, clothes, appearance etc.); to adjust; to tidy up; to groom\nto keep up appearances; to cover up (mistakes etc.); to gloss over\nto treat (illness, injury, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "繰り上げ", "answers": [ "くりあげ" ], "comment": "upward move; advance" },
	{ "question": "繰り上げる", "answers": [ "くりあげる" ], "comment": "to move up; to advance" },
	{ "question": "繰り入れ", "answers": [ "くりいれ" ], "comment": "inward transfer (of money); carry over (money from previous period)" },
	{ "question": "繰り出す", "answers": [ "くりだす" ], "comment": "to draw (a thread); to let out (e.g. a rope)\nto sally forth\nto send out; to dispatch\nto lunge; to unleash" },
	{ "question": "繰り延べ", "answers": [ "くりのべ" ], "comment": "postponement" },
	{ "question": "繰入", "answers": [ "くりいれ" ], "comment": "inward transfer (of money); carry over (money from previous period)" },
	{ "question": "置き去り", "answers": [ "おきざり" ], "comment": "desertion; leaving behind; leaving in the lurch" },
	{ "question": "置き場", "answers": [ "おきば" ], "comment": "place for something; storehouse" },
	{ "question": "置き換える", "answers": [ "おきかえる" ], "comment": "to replace; to move; to change the position of" },
	{ "question": "置物", "answers": [ "おきもの" ], "comment": "ornament; figurehead; object placed in tokonoma" },
	{ "question": "罰則", "answers": [ "ばっそく" ], "comment": "punishment; penalty\npenal regulations; penal code" },
	{ "question": "署員", "answers": [ "しょいん" ], "comment": "staff member; station employee; official" },
	{ "question": "署長", "answers": [ "しょちょう" ], "comment": "chief (of police); head (of office)" },
	{ "question": "罷免", "answers": [ "ひめん" ], "comment": "dismissal; discharge" },
	{ "question": "美化", "answers": [ "びか" ], "comment": "beautification; glorification" },
	{ "question": "美学", "answers": [ "びがく" ], "comment": "esthetics; aesthetics" },
	{ "question": "群がる", "answers": [ "むらがる" ], "comment": "to swarm; to gather" },
	{ "question": "群れる", "answers": [ "むれる" ], "comment": "to crowd; to flock; to swarm" },
	{ "question": "群像", "answers": [ "ぐんぞう" ], "comment": "lively group (usu. young people); dynamic bunch\nsculptured group (art)" },
	{ "question": "群島", "answers": [ "ぐんとう" ], "comment": "island group; archipelago" },
	{ "question": "義勇", "answers": [ "ぎゆう" ], "comment": "heroism; loyalty and courage" },
	{ "question": "義塾", "answers": [ "ぎじゅく" ], "comment": "private school" },
	{ "question": "義太夫", "answers": [ "ぎだゆう" ], "comment": "gidayuu (type of reciting used in the puppet theater)" },
	{ "question": "羽毛", "answers": [ "うもう" ], "comment": "feathers; plumage; down" },
	{ "question": "羽織", "answers": [ "はおり" ], "comment": "haori (Japanese formal coat)" },
	{ "question": "翌月", "answers": [ "よくげつ" ], "comment": "following month" },
	{ "question": "習性", "answers": [ "しゅうせい" ], "comment": "habit\nbehavior; behaviour; trait; nature" },
	{ "question": "翔る", "answers": [ "かける" ], "comment": "to soar; to fly\nto run; to dash" },
	{ "question": "翻す", "answers": [ "ひるがえす" ], "comment": "to turn over; to turn around\nto change (one's mind); to reverse (one's decision); to take back (one's words)\nto fly (flag, etc.); to wave (skirt, cape, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "老ける", "answers": [ "ふける" ], "comment": "to age; to grow old (esp. in appearance); to show marks of age" },
	{ "question": "老化", "answers": [ "ろうか" ], "comment": "ageing; aging; senile deterioration" },
	{ "question": "老女", "answers": [ "ろうじょ" ], "comment": "elderly woman; senior lady-in-waiting" },
	{ "question": "老年", "answers": [ "ろうねん" ], "comment": "old age" },
	{ "question": "老朽", "answers": [ "ろうきゅう" ], "comment": "superannuated; decrepitude" },
	{ "question": "老眼", "answers": [ "ろうがん" ], "comment": "presbyopia; age-related longsightedness; farsightedness" },
	{ "question": "老舗", "answers": [ "しにせ", "ろうほ" ], "comment": "old shop; shop of long standing\nwell-established; first of the kind; veteran" },
	{ "question": "老若", "answers": [ "ろうにゃく", "ろうじゃく" ], "comment": "young and old; all ages" },
	{ "question": "老衰", "answers": [ "ろうすい" ], "comment": "senility; senile decay; infirmity (through age)" },
	{ "question": "老齢", "answers": [ "ろうれい" ], "comment": "advanced age; senility" },
	{ "question": "耐久", "answers": [ "たいきゅう" ], "comment": "endurance; persistence" },
	{ "question": "耐性", "answers": [ "たいせい" ], "comment": "resistance (e.g. to antibiotics); tolerance (e.g. drug tolerance)" },
	{ "question": "耕作", "answers": [ "こうさく" ], "comment": "cultivation; farming" },
	{ "question": "耳より", "answers": [ "みみより" ], "comment": "welcome (news); inviting; encouraging; tempting; hopeful" },
	{ "question": "耳元", "answers": [ "みみもと" ], "comment": "close to the ear" },
	{ "question": "耳寄り", "answers": [ "みみより" ], "comment": "welcome (news); inviting; encouraging; tempting; hopeful" },
	{ "question": "耳障り", "answers": [ "みみざわり" ], "comment": "hard (on the ears); offensive (to the ear); rasping; rough; harsh; grating; jarring; cacophonous" },
	{ "question": "聖地", "answers": [ "せいち" ], "comment": "sacred place; holy ground; the Holy Land" },
	{ "question": "聖域", "answers": [ "せいいき" ], "comment": "sacred precincts; sanctuary; consecrated ground; holy ground\nissue that is regarded as being off-limits; matter that is not up for discussion" },
	{ "question": "聖堂", "answers": [ "せいどう" ], "comment": "(Confucian) temple; church; sanctuary" },
	{ "question": "聖戦", "answers": [ "せいせん" ], "comment": "holy war; crusade" },
	{ "question": "聖火", "answers": [ "せいか" ], "comment": "sacred fire (torch)\nOlympic flame" },
	{ "question": "聞かす", "answers": [ "きかす" ], "comment": "to inform about; to read to; to sing for" },
	{ "question": "聞き取り", "answers": [ "ききとり" ], "comment": "listening comprehension; aural comprehension\nhearing what others say; gathering information, opinions, etc.; public hearing" },
	{ "question": "聞き手", "answers": [ "ききて" ], "comment": "hearer; listener; audience\ninterviewer; questioner" },
	{ "question": "聞き書き", "answers": [ "ききがき" ], "comment": "writing down what one hears; account of what one hears" },
	{ "question": "聴聞", "answers": [ "ちょうもん" ], "comment": "listening; hearing" },
	{ "question": "聴衆", "answers": [ "ちょうしゅう" ], "comment": "audience; attendance; hearers" },
	{ "question": "聴覚", "answers": [ "ちょうかく" ], "comment": "the sense of hearing" },
	{ "question": "聴講", "answers": [ "ちょうこう" ], "comment": "lecture attendance; auditing" },
	{ "question": "職権", "answers": [ "しょっけん" ], "comment": "authority; commission" },
	{ "question": "職歴", "answers": [ "しょくれき" ], "comment": "work experience; work history" },
	{ "question": "職能", "answers": [ "しょくのう" ], "comment": "occupational ability\nfunction; role" },
	{ "question": "肉声", "answers": [ "にくせい" ], "comment": "natural voice (without a microphone)" },
	{ "question": "肉眼", "answers": [ "にくがん", "にくげん" ], "comment": "naked eye\nthe physical eye" },
	{ "question": "肉薄", "answers": [ "にくはく" ], "comment": "closing in on (the enemy, first place, etc.); coming close to; pressing hard\npressing hard (e.g. with a question); taking to task; grilling" },
	{ "question": "肉親", "answers": [ "にくしん" ], "comment": "blood relationship; blood relative" },
	{ "question": "肉食", "answers": [ "にくしょく" ], "comment": "meat eating; eating of meat; meat diet\ncarnivorous" },
	{ "question": "肌色", "answers": [ "はだいろ" ], "comment": "flesh-coloured; flesh-colored; skin-coloured; skin-colored" },
	{ "question": "肝炎", "answers": [ "かんえん" ], "comment": "hepatitis" },
	{ "question": "肝臓", "answers": [ "かんぞう" ], "comment": "liver" },
	{ "question": "肝要", "answers": [ "かんよう" ], "comment": "extremely important; essential; vital; crucial" },
	{ "question": "肥", "answers": [ "こえ" ], "comment": "manure; night soil; dung; fertiliser; fertilizer" },
	{ "question": "肥える", "answers": [ "こえる" ], "comment": "to grow fat; to gain weight; to put on weight\nto grow fertile\nto be refined (palate); to be discerning (eye, ear)\nto become rich; to become successful" },
	{ "question": "肥大", "answers": [ "ひだい" ], "comment": "swelling; enlargement; becoming fat\nhypertrophy" },
	{ "question": "肥満", "answers": [ "ひまん" ], "comment": "corpulence; fatness; obesity" },
	{ "question": "肩代わり", "answers": [ "かたがわり" ], "comment": "taking over another's debt; shouldering someone else's burden; subrogation" },
	{ "question": "育英", "answers": [ "いくえい" ], "comment": "education" },
	{ "question": "肺炎", "answers": [ "はいえん" ], "comment": "pneumonia" },
	{ "question": "胃腸", "answers": [ "いちょう" ], "comment": "stomach and intestines; gastrointestinal tract; digestive organs" },
	{ "question": "胆", "answers": [ "たん", "きも" ], "comment": "liver; innards\ncourage; spirit; pluck; guts\ncrux; essential point" },
	{ "question": "胆石", "answers": [ "たんせき" ], "comment": "gallstones" },
	{ "question": "背任", "answers": [ "はいにん" ], "comment": "breach of trust; malfeasance; malpractice; misappropriation" },
	{ "question": "背信", "answers": [ "はいしん" ], "comment": "betrayal; infidelity" },
	{ "question": "背泳ぎ", "answers": [ "せおよぎ" ], "comment": "backstroke (swim.)" },
	{ "question": "背骨", "answers": [ "せぼね" ], "comment": "spine; backbone; spinal column" },
	{ "question": "胴", "answers": [ "どう" ], "comment": "trunk; torso; body; abdomen; waist\nplastron (in kendo); touching the plastron (kimari-te in kendo)\nframe (of a drum, etc.); sound box (of a shamisen, etc.); hull (of a ship)" },
	{ "question": "胴上げ", "answers": [ "どうあげ" ], "comment": "lifting a person high (in celebration); tossing someone into the air; carrying someone on shoulders" },
	{ "question": "胴体", "answers": [ "どうたい" ], "comment": "body; trunk; torso; hull (boat); fuselage (aircraft)" },
	{ "question": "胸中", "answers": [ "きょうちゅう" ], "comment": "one's heart; one's mind; one's intentions" },
	{ "question": "胸部", "answers": [ "きょうぶ" ], "comment": "chest; breast" },
	{ "question": "能動", "answers": [ "のうどう" ], "comment": "active" },
	{ "question": "能楽", "answers": [ "のうがく" ], "comment": "noh play" },
	{ "question": "脅し", "answers": [ "おどし" ], "comment": "threat" },
	{ "question": "脇役", "answers": [ "わきやく" ], "comment": "supporting role (actor); minor role" },
	{ "question": "脇見", "answers": [ "ぼうし", "わきみ" ], "comment": "looking from the side\nlooking aside" },
	{ "question": "脈拍", "answers": [ "みゃくはく" ], "comment": "pulse; pulse rate; pulsation; stroke of pulse" },
	{ "question": "脈絡", "answers": [ "みゃくらく" ], "comment": "chain of reasoning; logical connection; coherence; context" },
	{ "question": "脚光", "answers": [ "きゃっこう" ], "comment": "footlight; limelight" },
	{ "question": "脚本", "answers": [ "きゃくほん" ], "comment": "script; screenplay; scenario" },
	{ "question": "脚色", "answers": [ "きゃくしょく" ], "comment": "dramatization (e.g. of a novel); dramatisation; adaptation\ndramatization; embellishment; exaggeration; embroidery" },
	{ "question": "脱却", "answers": [ "だっきゃく" ], "comment": "ridding oneself; freeing oneself of; growing out of; overcoming; outgrowing" },
	{ "question": "脱水", "answers": [ "だっすい" ], "comment": "evaporation; dehydration; dessication" },
	{ "question": "脱皮", "answers": [ "だっぴ" ], "comment": "ecdysis; shedding (of skin); sloughing; molting; moulting; casting off\nfreeing oneself; breaking with (convention, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "脱硫", "answers": [ "だつりゅう" ], "comment": "desulfurization; desulphurisation; desulphurization" },
	{ "question": "脱税", "answers": [ "だつぜい" ], "comment": "tax evasion" },
	{ "question": "脱落", "answers": [ "だつらく" ], "comment": "loss; dropping out; falling by the wayside\nomission; lacuna; gap; hiatus\ndesertion; defection\napostasy" },
	{ "question": "脱衣", "answers": [ "だつい" ], "comment": "undressing; taking off one's clothes" },
	{ "question": "脱退", "answers": [ "だったい" ], "comment": "secession; retirement; withdrawal (e.g. from a lawsuit)" },
	{ "question": "脳死", "answers": [ "のうし" ], "comment": "brain death" },
	{ "question": "脳波", "answers": [ "のうは" ], "comment": "brain waves\nelectroencephalogram; EEG" },
	{ "question": "腎臓", "answers": [ "じんぞう" ], "comment": "kidney" },
	{ "question": "腐心", "answers": [ "ふしん" ], "comment": "taking pains to; racking one's brains; doing everything one can" },
	{ "question": "腕前", "answers": [ "うでまえ" ], "comment": "ability; skill; facility" },
	{ "question": "腕力", "answers": [ "わんりょく" ], "comment": "physical strength; brute strength; arm strength" },
	{ "question": "腰痛", "answers": [ "ようつう" ], "comment": "lower back (or hip) pain; lumbago" },
	{ "question": "腹心", "answers": [ "ふくしん" ], "comment": "one's confidant; trusted friend; trusted retainer" },
	{ "question": "腹痛", "answers": [ "はらいた", "ふくつう" ], "comment": "stomach ache; abdominal pain" },
	{ "question": "腹部", "answers": [ "ふくぶ" ], "comment": "abdomen" },
	{ "question": "膨れる", "answers": [ "ふくれる" ], "comment": "to swell (out); to expand; to be inflated; to distend; to bulge\nto get cross; to get sulky; to pout" },
	{ "question": "臓器", "answers": [ "ぞうき" ], "comment": "internal organs; viscera; intestines" },
	{ "question": "臨海", "answers": [ "りんかい" ], "comment": "coastal; seaside; oceanfront; maritime" },
	{ "question": "臨界", "answers": [ "りんかい" ], "comment": "critical (pressure, temperature, state, point)" },
	{ "question": "臨終", "answers": [ "りんじゅう" ], "comment": "deathbed; dying hour; one's death" },
	{ "question": "自他", "answers": [ "じた" ], "comment": "oneself and others\ntransitive and intransitive" },
	{ "question": "自任", "answers": [ "じにん" ], "comment": "self-appointment; pretension" },
	{ "question": "自伝", "answers": [ "じでん" ], "comment": "autobiography" },
	{ "question": "自制", "answers": [ "じせい" ], "comment": "self control; self restraint" },
	{ "question": "自前", "answers": [ "じまえ" ], "comment": "taking care of one's responsibilities by oneself; one's own efforts; one's own expense\ngoing into business for oneself (selling one's own products); entrepreneur of such a business" },
	{ "question": "自助", "answers": [ "じじょ" ], "comment": "self-help" },
	{ "question": "自問", "answers": [ "じもん" ], "comment": "asking oneself" },
	{ "question": "自室", "answers": [ "じしつ" ], "comment": "one's own room" },
	{ "question": "自明", "answers": [ "じめい" ], "comment": "obvious; self-evident; trivial; axiomatic; self-explanatory" },
	{ "question": "自棄", "answers": [ "じき", "やけ" ], "comment": "desperation; despair; self-abandonment" },
	{ "question": "自決", "answers": [ "じけつ" ], "comment": "self-determination\nsuicide" },
	{ "question": "自活", "answers": [ "じかつ" ], "comment": "self-support" },
	{ "question": "自浄", "answers": [ "じじょう" ], "comment": "self-purification; self-cleansing" },
	{ "question": "自滅", "answers": [ "じめつ" ], "comment": "ruining oneself; destroying oneself; self-destruction" },
	{ "question": "自炊", "answers": [ "じすい" ], "comment": "cooking for oneself; cooking one's own food; doing one's own cooking; making food oneself; self-catering\nscanning a book or magazine to create an ebook by oneself" },
	{ "question": "自白", "answers": [ "じはく" ], "comment": "confession; acknowledgement; acknowledgment" },
	{ "question": "自称", "answers": [ "じしょう" ], "comment": "self-alleged; self-proclaimed; calling oneself; self-styled; would-be\nfirst person" },
	{ "question": "自筆", "answers": [ "じひつ" ], "comment": "one's own handwriting; autograph; holograph" },
	{ "question": "自粛", "answers": [ "じしゅく" ], "comment": "self-restraint; self-control; self-discipline" },
	{ "question": "自給", "answers": [ "じきゅう" ], "comment": "self-support" },
	{ "question": "自販", "answers": [ "じはん" ], "comment": "automobile sales" },
	{ "question": "自費", "answers": [ "じひ" ], "comment": "one's own expense; out-of-pocket expense" },
	{ "question": "自首", "answers": [ "じしゅ" ], "comment": "surrender; give oneself up" },
	{ "question": "至上", "answers": [ "しじょう" ], "comment": "supremacy" },
	{ "question": "至難", "answers": [ "しなん" ], "comment": "most difficult; next to impossible" },
	{ "question": "致死", "answers": [ "ちし" ], "comment": "lethal; fatal" },
	{ "question": "舅", "answers": [ "しうと", "しゅうと" ], "comment": "father-in-law" },
	{ "question": "興", "answers": [ "きょう" ], "comment": "interest; entertainment; pleasure\nimplicit comparison (style of the Shi Jing)" },
	{ "question": "興す", "answers": [ "おこす" ], "comment": "to establish (e.g. company); to build up; to set up; to promote; to vitalize; to revive" },
	{ "question": "興業", "answers": [ "こうぎょう" ], "comment": "industrial enterprise" },
	{ "question": "興行", "answers": [ "こうぎょう" ], "comment": "show; performance; act\nentertainment industry; show business" },
	{ "question": "舗装", "answers": [ "ほそう" ], "comment": "pavement; road surface" },
	{ "question": "舞", "answers": [ "まい" ], "comment": "dancing; dance" },
	{ "question": "舞踊", "answers": [ "ぶよう" ], "comment": "dancing; dance" },
	{ "question": "舞踏", "answers": [ "ぶとう" ], "comment": "dancing\ncontemporary performance dance" },
	{ "question": "航法", "answers": [ "こうほう" ], "comment": "sailing; navigation" },
	{ "question": "航行", "answers": [ "こうこう" ], "comment": "cruise; navigation; sailing" },
	{ "question": "航路", "answers": [ "こうろ" ], "comment": "(air or sea) route; course; line; run" },
	{ "question": "舵", "answers": [ "かじ" ], "comment": "rudder; helm" },
	{ "question": "船主", "answers": [ "せんしゅ", "ふなぬし" ], "comment": "shipowner" },
	{ "question": "船体", "answers": [ "せんたい" ], "comment": "hull" },
	{ "question": "船出", "answers": [ "ふなで" ], "comment": "setting sail; putting out to sea" },
	{ "question": "船員", "answers": [ "せんいん" ], "comment": "sailor" },
	{ "question": "船籍", "answers": [ "せんせき" ], "comment": "ship's nationality; ship's country of registration" },
	{ "question": "艦船", "answers": [ "かんせん" ], "comment": "(ocean) vessels; warship" },
	{ "question": "艦艇", "answers": [ "かんてい" ], "comment": "military vessel; war fleet" },
	{ "question": "良", "answers": [ "りょう" ], "comment": "good\nB grade (in an A, B, C ... system)" },
	{ "question": "良識", "answers": [ "りょうしき" ], "comment": "good sense" },
	{ "question": "色合い", "answers": [ "いろあい" ], "comment": "hue; tinge; tint" },
	{ "question": "色気", "answers": [ "いろけ" ], "comment": "colouring; coloring; shade of colour; shade of color\nsex appeal (esp. women); interest in the opposite sex; sensuality; seductiveness; glamor; glamour; sexual passion\nromance; poetry; charm\ndesire; interest; inclination; ambition" },
	{ "question": "色紙", "answers": [ "しきし" ], "comment": "square fancy cardboard, used for autographs, poetry, etc." },
	{ "question": "色素", "answers": [ "しきそ" ], "comment": "pigment; coloring; colouring; colorant; colourant" },
	{ "question": "色調", "answers": [ "しきちょう" ], "comment": "color tone; colour tone" },
	{ "question": "花びら", "answers": [ "かべん", "はなびら" ], "comment": "(flower) petal" },
	{ "question": "花園", "answers": [ "はなぞの", "かえん" ], "comment": "flower garden" },
	{ "question": "花壇", "answers": [ "かだん" ], "comment": "flower bed" },
	{ "question": "花婿", "answers": [ "はなむこ" ], "comment": "bridegroom" },
	{ "question": "花弁", "answers": [ "かべん", "はなびら" ], "comment": "(flower) petal" },
	{ "question": "花形", "answers": [ "はながた", "かけい" ], "comment": "floral pattern; flourish; ornament\nstar (actor, player, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "花束", "answers": [ "はなたば" ], "comment": "bunch of flowers; bouquet" },
	{ "question": "花柳", "answers": [ "かりゅう" ], "comment": "red-light district" },
	{ "question": "花王", "answers": [ "かおう" ], "comment": "peony; king of flowers" },
	{ "question": "花盛り", "answers": [ "はなざかり" ], "comment": "flowers in full bloom; time of year in which flowers are in full bloom\nthe age at which someone (esp. a woman) is at the peak of their beauty\nbooming or peaking (in popularity)" },
	{ "question": "花輪", "answers": [ "はなわ" ], "comment": "wreath; garland" },
	{ "question": "花道", "answers": [ "はなみち" ], "comment": "passage through audience to stage" },
	{ "question": "芸名", "answers": [ "げいめい" ], "comment": "stage name" },
	{ "question": "苗", "answers": [ "なえ" ], "comment": "seedling" },
	{ "question": "苗木", "answers": [ "なえぎ" ], "comment": "seedling; sapling; young tree" },
	{ "question": "若年", "answers": [ "じゃくねん" ], "comment": "youth" },
	{ "question": "若葉", "answers": [ "わかば", "どんよう" ], "comment": "new leaves; fresh verdure" },
	{ "question": "若返り", "answers": [ "わかがえり" ], "comment": "rejuvenation; restoration of youth" },
	{ "question": "苦味", "answers": [ "くみ", "にがみ" ], "comment": "bitterness; bitter taste" },
	{ "question": "苦境", "answers": [ "くきょう" ], "comment": "trouble; crisis; predicament; squeeze; pinch" },
	{ "question": "苦慮", "answers": [ "くりょ" ], "comment": "racking one's brains; worrying oneself; being anxious" },
	{ "question": "苦戦", "answers": [ "くせん" ], "comment": "hard fight; close game; struggle; tight contest" },
	{ "question": "苦渋", "answers": [ "くじゅう" ], "comment": "bitterness; mortification; difficulty in understanding; distress; affliction" },
	{ "question": "苦笑い", "answers": [ "にがわらい" ], "comment": "bitter smile; wry smile; forced smile; strained laugh" },
	{ "question": "苦言", "answers": [ "くげん" ], "comment": "candid advice; frank advice; honest opinion; exhortation" },
	{ "question": "苦難", "answers": [ "くなん" ], "comment": "suffering; distress; hardship; trial" },
	{ "question": "英字", "answers": [ "えいじ" ], "comment": "English letter; alphabetic character" },
	{ "question": "英明", "answers": [ "えいめい" ], "comment": "intelligent; wise; bright; brilliant; clear-sighted" },
	{ "question": "英気", "answers": [ "えいき" ], "comment": "great wisdom; excellent disposition\nstrength (to face something); willpower; vigor; vigour; energy" },
	{ "question": "英知", "answers": [ "えいち" ], "comment": "wisdom; intelligence; intellect" },
	{ "question": "英訳", "answers": [ "えいやく" ], "comment": "English translation" },
	{ "question": "茎", "answers": [ "くき" ], "comment": "stalk; stem" },
	{ "question": "茶の間", "answers": [ "ちゃのま" ], "comment": "living room (Japanese-style)" },
	{ "question": "茶道", "answers": [ "さどう" ], "comment": "tea ceremony; Way of Tea" },
	{ "question": "草の根", "answers": [ "くさのね" ], "comment": "grassroots; rank and file; the roots of grass" },
	{ "question": "草分け", "answers": [ "くさわけ" ], "comment": "pathfinder; trailblazer; early settler\npioneer; founder; originator; groundbreaker" },
	{ "question": "草刈り", "answers": [ "くさかり" ], "comment": "mowing; mower" },
	{ "question": "草木", "answers": [ "そうもく", "くさき" ], "comment": "plants; vegetation" },
	{ "question": "草案", "answers": [ "そうあん" ], "comment": "draft; draught" },
	{ "question": "草花", "answers": [ "そうか", "くさばな" ], "comment": "flower; flowering plant" },
	{ "question": "草食", "answers": [ "そうしょく" ], "comment": "herbivorous; plant-eating; graminivorous" },
	{ "question": "荒々しい", "answers": [ "あらあらしい" ], "comment": "rough; wild; rude; harsh; gruff; violent" },
	{ "question": "荒っぽい", "answers": [ "あらっぽい" ], "comment": "rough; rude" },
	{ "question": "荒らげる", "answers": [ "あららげる" ], "comment": "to roughen (e.g. one's attitude); to raise (one's voice)" },
	{ "question": "荒れ", "answers": [ "あれ" ], "comment": "stormy weather; tempest; chaps (of skin)" },
	{ "question": "荒木", "answers": [ "あらき" ], "comment": "logs in bark; rough wood; unseasoned timber; new lumber" },
	{ "question": "荒波", "answers": [ "あらなみ" ], "comment": "raging waves; stormy seas\nhardships; troubles; adversities" },
	{ "question": "荒野", "answers": [ "あらの", "こうや", "あれの" ], "comment": "wasteland; wilderness; deserted land; prairie; vast plain; wilds; desert; wild land" },
	{ "question": "荷作り", "answers": [ "にづくり" ], "comment": "packing; baling; crating" },
	{ "question": "荷台", "answers": [ "にだい" ], "comment": "(truck) load-carrying tray; (bicycle) luggage carrier; roof rack" },
	{ "question": "荷札", "answers": [ "にふだ" ], "comment": "label; tag" },
	{ "question": "荷造り", "answers": [ "にづくり" ], "comment": "packing; baling; crating" },
	{ "question": "荻", "answers": [ "おぎ" ], "comment": "Amur silvergrass (Miscanthus sacchariflorus)" },
	{ "question": "菓子", "answers": [ "かし" ], "comment": "pastry; confectionery" },
	{ "question": "菜園", "answers": [ "さいえん" ], "comment": "vegetable garden" },
	{ "question": "菜食", "answers": [ "さいしょく" ], "comment": "vegetable diet" },
	{ "question": "菩薩", "answers": [ "ぼさつ" ], "comment": "bodhisattva; one who has reached enlightenment but vows to save all beings before becoming a buddha\nHigh Monk (title bestowed by the imperial court)\ntitle bestowed to Shinto kami in manifestation theory" },
	{ "question": "華々しい", "answers": [ "はなばなしい" ], "comment": "brilliant; magnificent; spectacular" },
	{ "question": "華僑", "answers": [ "かきょう" ], "comment": "overseas Chinese" },
	{ "question": "華麗", "answers": [ "かれい" ], "comment": "splendid; magnificent; gorgeous" },
	{ "question": "萌芽", "answers": [ "ほうが" ], "comment": "germination; germ; sprout; bud; sign" },
	{ "question": "萎縮", "answers": [ "いしゅく" ], "comment": "withering; atrophy; contraction; dwarf" },
	{ "question": "落ちこぼれ", "answers": [ "おちこぼれ" ], "comment": "leftovers; odds and ends; pickings\nstudent who can't keep up in school; dunce" },
	{ "question": "落ち合う", "answers": [ "おちあう" ], "comment": "to meet; to gather; to rendezvous\nto join (of roads, rivers, etc.); to flow together" },
	{ "question": "落ち度", "answers": [ "おちど" ], "comment": "mistake; error; fault; slip; blunder; omission; oversight; lapse" },
	{ "question": "落ち葉", "answers": [ "おちば" ], "comment": "fallen leaves; leaf litter\ndeciduous" },
	{ "question": "落とし穴", "answers": [ "おとしあな" ], "comment": "pitfall; trap; pit" },
	{ "question": "落差", "answers": [ "らくさ" ], "comment": "a head (of water); a difference" },
	{ "question": "落書き", "answers": [ "らくがき" ], "comment": "scrawl; scribble; graffiti" },
	{ "question": "落胆", "answers": [ "らくたん" ], "comment": "discouragement; despondency; dejection; disappointment" },
	{ "question": "落語", "answers": [ "らくご" ], "comment": "rakugo; traditional Japanese comic storytelling; comic story (told by a professional storyteller)" },
	{ "question": "落選", "answers": [ "らくせん" ], "comment": "election loss; rejection" },
	{ "question": "葛", "answers": [ "つづら", "くず" ], "comment": "kudzu (Pueraria montana); Japanese arrowroot\nChinese moonseed (Sinomenium acutum)" },
	{ "question": "葬る", "answers": [ "ほうむる", "ほうぶる" ], "comment": "to bury; to inter; to entomb\nto cover up; to hush up; to shelve" },
	{ "question": "葬祭", "answers": [ "そうさい" ], "comment": "funerals and ceremonial occasions" },
	{ "question": "葬送", "answers": [ "そうそう" ], "comment": "funeral; burial rites\nattendance at a funeral" },
	{ "question": "蒔く", "answers": [ "まく" ], "comment": "to sow; to plant; to seed\nto sprinkle (gold or silver powder on lacquerware)" },
	{ "question": "蒸かす", "answers": [ "ふかす" ], "comment": "to steam (food)" },
	{ "question": "蒸し", "answers": [ "むし" ], "comment": "steaming" },
	{ "question": "蓄財", "answers": [ "ちくざい" ], "comment": "amassing of wealth" },
	{ "question": "蔑む", "answers": [ "さげすむ" ], "comment": "to scorn; to despise; to hold in contempt; to look down on; to disdain" },
	{ "question": "蔵書", "answers": [ "ぞうしょ" ], "comment": "book collection; library" },
	{ "question": "蔵相", "answers": [ "ぞうしょう" ], "comment": "Minister of Finance" },
	{ "question": "蕎麦屋", "answers": [ "そばや" ], "comment": "buckwheat-noodle restaurant" },
	{ "question": "蕾", "answers": [ "つぼみ" ], "comment": "(flower) bud\npromising young person; budding beauty" },
	{ "question": "薄まる", "answers": [ "うすまる" ], "comment": "to become weak" },
	{ "question": "薄弱", "answers": [ "はくじゃく" ], "comment": "feebleness; weakness; weak" },
	{ "question": "薄着", "answers": [ "うすぎ" ], "comment": "being lightly dressed" },
	{ "question": "薔薇色", "answers": [ "バラいろ" ], "comment": "rose-colour; rose-color" },
	{ "question": "薬価", "answers": [ "やくか", "やっか" ], "comment": "National Health Insurance drug price; NHI drug price" },
	{ "question": "薬剤", "answers": [ "やくざい" ], "comment": "medicine; drug" },
	{ "question": "薬学", "answers": [ "やくがく" ], "comment": "(study of) pharmacy; pharmaceutics" },
	{ "question": "薬害", "answers": [ "やくがい" ], "comment": "harmful side effects of a medicine or drug" },
	{ "question": "藤", "answers": [ "ふじ" ], "comment": "wisteria (esp. Japanese wisteria, Wisteria floribunda); wistaria" },
	{ "question": "藻", "answers": [ "も" ], "comment": "algae; waterweed; seaweed; duckweed" },
	{ "question": "虚偽", "answers": [ "きょぎ", "こぎ" ], "comment": "falsehood; untruth; lie; misinformation\nfallacy (logic)" },
	{ "question": "虚構", "answers": [ "きょこう" ], "comment": "fiction; fabrication; concoction\nfictitious; fictional; imaginary" },
	{ "question": "虚無", "answers": [ "きょむ" ], "comment": "nihility; nothingness" },
	{ "question": "虫除け", "answers": [ "むしよけ" ], "comment": "insecticide; insect repellent" },
	{ "question": "蚊帳", "answers": [ "かや", "（かちょう）" ], "comment": "mosquito net" },
	{ "question": "蛇の目", "answers": [ "じゃのめ" ], "comment": "bull's-eye (pattern); double ring (pattern)\numbrella with bull's-eye pattern" },
	{ "question": "蜜", "answers": [ "みつ" ], "comment": "nectar\nhoney\nhoneydew\ntreacle; molasses\nsorbitol (when visible as dark patches inside an apple)" },
	{ "question": "蝕む", "answers": [ "むしばむ" ], "comment": "to be worm-eaten; to be eaten by worms\nto affect adversely; to spoil; to ruin; to undermine; to gnaw at (one's heart, body, etc.); to eat into; to destroy" },
	{ "question": "蝶々", "answers": [ "ちょうちょう", "ちょうちょ" ], "comment": "butterfly" },
	{ "question": "融和", "answers": [ "ゆうわ" ], "comment": "harmony; reconciliation" },
	{ "question": "融通", "answers": [ "ゆうずう", "ゆうづう" ], "comment": "lending (money); finance\nadaptability; versatility; flexibility; accommodation" },
	{ "question": "螺旋", "answers": [ "らせん" ], "comment": "spiral; helix\nscrew" },
	{ "question": "血痕", "answers": [ "けっこん" ], "comment": "bloodstain" },
	{ "question": "衆院", "answers": [ "しゅういん" ], "comment": "lower house of the Diet; House of Representatives" },
	{ "question": "行い", "answers": [ "おこない" ], "comment": "deed; act; action; conduct; behavior; behaviour; asceticism" },
	{ "question": "行き届く", "answers": [ "ゆきとどく", "いきとどく" ], "comment": "to be scrupulous; to be attentive; to be prudent; to be complete; to be thorough" },
	{ "question": "行き止まり", "answers": [ "ゆきどまり", "いきどまり" ], "comment": "dead end; no passage" },
	{ "question": "行き詰まり", "answers": [ "いきづまり", "ゆきづまり" ], "comment": "deadlock; stalemate; impasse; dead end" },
	{ "question": "行き過ぎ", "answers": [ "いきすぎ", "ゆきすぎ" ], "comment": "going too far; going to extremes" },
	{ "question": "行き過ぎる", "answers": [ "ゆきすぎる", "いきすぎる" ], "comment": "to go too far; to go past\nto go to extremes; to overdo it" },
	{ "question": "行き違い", "answers": [ "ゆきちがい", "いきちがい" ], "comment": "crossing without meeting (e.g. letters in the post, people on the road); going astray\ndifference of opinion; misunderstanding; estrangement; disagreement" },
	{ "question": "行司", "answers": [ "ぎょうじ" ], "comment": "referee (in sumo)" },
	{ "question": "行員", "answers": [ "こういん" ], "comment": "bank clerk" },
	{ "question": "行楽", "answers": [ "こうらく" ], "comment": "outing; excursion; pleasure trip; going on a picnic" },
	{ "question": "行程", "answers": [ "こうてい" ], "comment": "journey; course; distance; march; flight (airplane); drive (automobile); leg (of a journey or a relay race); itinerary; stroke (of a piston); throw (of a switch)" },
	{ "question": "行脚", "answers": [ "あんぎゃ" ], "comment": "pilgrimage; traveling on foot" },
	{ "question": "行革", "answers": [ "ぎょうかく" ], "comment": "administrative reform" },
	{ "question": "術後", "answers": [ "じゅつご" ], "comment": "postoperative" },
	{ "question": "術語", "answers": [ "じゅつご" ], "comment": "technical term; terminology; nomenclature" },
	{ "question": "街頭", "answers": [ "がいとう" ], "comment": "in the street" },
	{ "question": "衣料", "answers": [ "いりょう" ], "comment": "clothing" },
	{ "question": "衣替え", "answers": [ "ころもがえ" ], "comment": "seasonal change of clothing; changing (one's) dress for the season\nrenovation; facelift; changing appearance" },
	{ "question": "表する", "answers": [ "ひょうする" ], "comment": "to express; to show" },
	{ "question": "表向き", "answers": [ "おもてむき" ], "comment": "outward appearance; ostensible; public; official" },
	{ "question": "表彰", "answers": [ "ひょうしょう" ], "comment": "public acknowledgment; public acknowledgement; public recognition; commendation; awarding" },
	{ "question": "表札", "answers": [ "ひょうさつ" ], "comment": "nameplate; doorplate" },
	{ "question": "表決", "answers": [ "ひょうけつ" ], "comment": "vote; voting" },
	{ "question": "表立つ", "answers": [ "おもてだつ" ], "comment": "to become public; to be known" },
	{ "question": "表裏", "answers": [ "ひょうり" ], "comment": "front and back; inside and outside; two sides; both sides\nduplicity; double-dealing; being two-faced" },
	{ "question": "表通り", "answers": [ "おもてどおり" ], "comment": "main street" },
	{ "question": "表題", "answers": [ "ひょうだい" ], "comment": "title; index; heading; headline; caption" },
	{ "question": "衰え", "answers": [ "おとろえ" ], "comment": "weakening; emaciation; decline" },
	{ "question": "衰弱", "answers": [ "すいじゃく" ], "comment": "weakness; debility; breakdown; prostration" },
	{ "question": "被災", "answers": [ "ひさい" ], "comment": "being a victim of (some disaster); suffering from" },
	{ "question": "被爆", "answers": [ "ひばく" ], "comment": "being bombed\nbeing A-bombed; being nuked; being exposed to radiation (from an atomic blast)" },
	{ "question": "裁く", "answers": [ "さばく" ], "comment": "to judge" },
	{ "question": "裁つ", "answers": [ "たつ" ], "comment": "to cut (cloth)" },
	{ "question": "裁定", "answers": [ "せいてい", "さいてい" ], "comment": "decision; ruling; award; arbitration" },
	{ "question": "裁決", "answers": [ "さいけつ" ], "comment": "decision; ruling; judgement; judgment" },
	{ "question": "裁量", "answers": [ "さいりょう" ], "comment": "admeasure; discretion" },
	{ "question": "裂ける", "answers": [ "さける" ], "comment": "to split; to tear; to burst" },
	{ "question": "装い", "answers": [ "よそおい" ], "comment": "dress; outfit; equipment; makeup; adornment; guise; get-up" },
	{ "question": "装丁", "answers": [ "そうてい" ], "comment": "binding (book); format" },
	{ "question": "装甲", "answers": [ "そうこう" ], "comment": "armoring; armouring; armor; armour" },
	{ "question": "裏付け", "answers": [ "うらづけ" ], "comment": "backing; support; endorsement; collateral; security; guarantee; proof; substantiation; foundation; lining (something); something lined" },
	{ "question": "裏切り", "answers": [ "うらぎり" ], "comment": "treachery; betrayal; perfidy" },
	{ "question": "裏方", "answers": [ "うらかた" ], "comment": "someone working behind-the-scenes; scene shifter\nlady consort (to a high personage)" },
	{ "question": "裏目", "answers": [ "うらめ" ], "comment": "reverse side\nopposite (of the expected)\npurl stitch (knitting)" },
	{ "question": "裏腹", "answers": [ "うらはら" ], "comment": "opposite; reverse; contrary" },
	{ "question": "裏表", "answers": [ "うらおもて" ], "comment": "back and front; inside and outside; both sides\ninside out (e.g. clothing)\ndouble-dealing; two faces (c.f. two-faced)\noutward appearance and actual condition; inner workings" },
	{ "question": "裏返し", "answers": [ "うらがえし" ], "comment": "inside out; upside down\nflip side; opposite; contrary; reverse" },
	{ "question": "裏通り", "answers": [ "うらどおり" ], "comment": "side street (often parallel to a main street); back street; alley" },
	{ "question": "裏金", "answers": [ "うらがね" ], "comment": "bribe\nsecret fund; slush fund; money for bribery" },
	{ "question": "裏門", "answers": [ "うらもん" ], "comment": "back gate" },
	{ "question": "裏面", "answers": [ "りめん" ], "comment": "back; reverse; other side; inside; tails (of coins); background" },
	{ "question": "補修", "answers": [ "ほしゅう" ], "comment": "maintenance; mending; repair" },
	{ "question": "補完", "answers": [ "ほかん" ], "comment": "complementation; supplementation; completion" },
	{ "question": "補強", "answers": [ "ほきょう" ], "comment": "compensation; reinforcement" },
	{ "question": "補欠", "answers": [ "ほけつ" ], "comment": "filling a vacancy; supplementation\nsubstitute; deputy; alternate; spare" },
	{ "question": "補正", "answers": [ "ほせい" ], "comment": "correction; revision; compensation (e.g. to a pendulum)" },
	{ "question": "裸足", "answers": [ "せんそく", "はだし" ], "comment": "barefoot\nsuperior to (a professional, etc. in ability or achievement)" },
	{ "question": "製図", "answers": [ "せいず" ], "comment": "draughtsmanship; draftsmanship; drawing; sketching; mapmaking; cartography" },
	{ "question": "製法", "answers": [ "せいほう" ], "comment": "manufacturing method; recipe; formula" },
	{ "question": "製紙", "answers": [ "せいし" ], "comment": "papermaking; paper-making; paper making; paper manufacture" },
	{ "question": "製薬", "answers": [ "せいやく" ], "comment": "medicine manufacture; drug manufacture" },
	{ "question": "製鉄", "answers": [ "せいてつ" ], "comment": "iron manufacture" },
	{ "question": "製鋼", "answers": [ "せいこう" ], "comment": "steel manufacture" },
	{ "question": "複利", "answers": [ "ふくり" ], "comment": "compound interest" },
	{ "question": "複製", "answers": [ "ふくせい" ], "comment": "reproduction; duplication; reprinting" },
	{ "question": "褐色", "answers": [ "かっしょく" ], "comment": "dark brown; colour of tanned skin" },
	{ "question": "襟", "answers": [ "えり" ], "comment": "collar; lapel; neckband; neck\nnape of the neck; scruff of the neck" },
	{ "question": "襟巻き", "answers": [ "えりまき" ], "comment": "muffler (often fur); scarf; comforter" },
	{ "question": "襲名", "answers": [ "しゅうめい" ], "comment": "succession to another's professional name" },
	{ "question": "西南", "answers": [ "せいなん", "にしみなみ" ], "comment": "south-west" },
	{ "question": "西口", "answers": [ "にしぐち" ], "comment": "west entrance" },
	{ "question": "西方", "answers": [ "にしがた", "さいほう", "せいほう" ], "comment": "western direction\nWestern Pure Land (Amitabha's Buddhist paradise)\nwestern fighter in a match (e.g. sumo)" },
	{ "question": "西独", "answers": [ "せいどく" ], "comment": "West Germany (1949-1990)" },
	{ "question": "要する", "answers": [ "ようする" ], "comment": "to need; to demand; to take; to require" },
	{ "question": "要人", "answers": [ "ようじん" ], "comment": "important person" },
	{ "question": "要員", "answers": [ "よういん" ], "comment": "essential member; necessary person; personnel" },
	{ "question": "要所", "answers": [ "ようしょ" ], "comment": "important point; important position" },
	{ "question": "要綱", "answers": [ "ようこう" ], "comment": "main principle; gist; general plan; guidelines; outline" },
	{ "question": "要職", "answers": [ "ようしょく" ], "comment": "important office" },
	{ "question": "要衝", "answers": [ "ようしょう" ], "comment": "important point; strategic position; key point" },
	{ "question": "要項", "answers": [ "ようこう" ], "comment": "important points; main points" },
	{ "question": "覆す", "answers": [ "くつがえす" ], "comment": "to overturn; to capsize; to upset\nto overthrow (government etc.)\nto reverse (decision etc.); to disprove (an established theory etc.); to overrule" },
	{ "question": "覆面", "answers": [ "ふくめん" ], "comment": "mask; veil; disguise\nanonymous; unmarked; incognito" },
	{ "question": "覇権", "answers": [ "はけん" ], "comment": "hegemony" },
	{ "question": "覇者", "answers": [ "はしゃ" ], "comment": "supreme ruler; champion; titleholder" },
	{ "question": "見え隠れ", "answers": [ "みえがくれ" ], "comment": "appearing and disappearing" },
	{ "question": "見せびらかす", "answers": [ "みせびらかす" ], "comment": "to show off; to flaunt" },
	{ "question": "見せ場", "answers": [ "みせば" ], "comment": "highlight scene (of play)" },
	{ "question": "見せ掛け", "answers": [ "みせかけ" ], "comment": "seeming; pose; show; pretense; sham; mock" },
	{ "question": "見どころ", "answers": [ "みどころ" ], "comment": "point worthy of note; highlight (e.g. in a film); thing to note\ngood prospects for the future; promise" },
	{ "question": "見下す", "answers": [ "みくだす" ], "comment": "to despise; to look down on" },
	{ "question": "見入る", "answers": [ "みいる" ], "comment": "to gaze at; to fix one's eyes upon" },
	{ "question": "見分け", "answers": [ "みわけ" ], "comment": "distinction" },
	{ "question": "見切り", "answers": [ "みきり" ], "comment": "abandonment; giving up; forsaking\nbargain (e.g. in a sale)" },
	{ "question": "見地", "answers": [ "けんち" ], "comment": "point of view" },
	{ "question": "見届ける", "answers": [ "みとどける" ], "comment": "to make sure of; to assure oneself of; to see with one's own eyes; to ascertain" },
	{ "question": "見張り", "answers": [ "みはり" ], "comment": "watch-keeping; guard; lookout" },
	{ "question": "見惚れる", "answers": [ "みほれる", "みとれる" ], "comment": "to be fascinated (by); to be captivated by; to be enchanted by; to gaze admiringly at; to watch in fascination" },
	{ "question": "見所", "answers": [ "みどころ" ], "comment": "point worthy of note; highlight (e.g. in a film); thing to note\ngood prospects for the future; promise" },
	{ "question": "見放す", "answers": [ "みはなす" ], "comment": "to abandon; to give up on; to desert" },
	{ "question": "見晴らし", "answers": [ "みはらし" ], "comment": "view; prospect; outlook" },
	{ "question": "見晴らす", "answers": [ "みはらす" ], "comment": "to command a view" },
	{ "question": "見栄", "answers": [ "みえ" ], "comment": "airs; pretensions; show; ostentation; display; appearance; vanity; charm" },
	{ "question": "見栄え", "answers": [ "みばえ" ], "comment": "airs; pretensions; show; ostentation; display; appearance; vanity; charm" },
	{ "question": "見比べる", "answers": [ "みくらべる" ], "comment": "to compare with the eye" },
	{ "question": "見縊る", "answers": [ "みくびる" ], "comment": "to underrate; to belittle; to look down on; to despise" },
	{ "question": "見習い", "answers": [ "みならい" ], "comment": "apprenticeship; probation; learning by observation\napprentice; trainee; probationer" },
	{ "question": "見習う", "answers": [ "みならう" ], "comment": "to follow another's example" },
	{ "question": "見聞", "answers": [ "けんもん", "けんぶん" ], "comment": "information; observation" },
	{ "question": "見苦しい", "answers": [ "みぐるしい" ], "comment": "unsightly; ugly" },
	{ "question": "見落とす", "answers": [ "みおとす" ], "comment": "to overlook; to fail to notice; to miss (seeing)" },
	{ "question": "見覚え", "answers": [ "みおぼえ" ], "comment": "remembrance; recollection; recognition" },
	{ "question": "見識", "answers": [ "けんしき" ], "comment": "views; opinion; discernment\npride; self-respect" },
	{ "question": "見返り", "answers": [ "みかえり" ], "comment": "collateral; reward; compensation; security; quid pro quo" },
	{ "question": "見過ごす", "answers": [ "みすごす" ], "comment": "to let go by; to let pass; to overlook; to miss" },
	{ "question": "見違える", "answers": [ "みちがえる" ], "comment": "to hardly recognise; to mistake for something or somebody else" },
	{ "question": "見限る", "answers": [ "みかぎる" ], "comment": "to give up; to turn one's back; to abandon" },
	{ "question": "規程", "answers": [ "きてい" ], "comment": "official regulations; inner rules" },
	{ "question": "覚書", "answers": [ "おぼえがき" ], "comment": "memo; memorandum; note; memorial; protocol" },
	{ "question": "親交", "answers": [ "しんこう" ], "comment": "intimacy; friendship; friendly relations" },
	{ "question": "親善", "answers": [ "しんぜん" ], "comment": "friendship; goodwill; friendly relations; amity" },
	{ "question": "親愛", "answers": [ "しんあい" ], "comment": "deep affection\ndear; beloved" },
	{ "question": "親日", "answers": [ "しんにち" ], "comment": "pro-Japanese" },
	{ "question": "親書", "answers": [ "しんしょ" ], "comment": "handwritten or autograph letter" },
	{ "question": "親睦", "answers": [ "しんぼく" ], "comment": "friendship; amity" },
	{ "question": "親衛", "answers": [ "しんえい" ], "comment": "monarch's guards" },
	{ "question": "観劇", "answers": [ "かんげき" ], "comment": "theatre-going; theater-going" },
	{ "question": "観戦", "answers": [ "かんせん" ], "comment": "watching a (sports) game; spectating; observing (military operations)" },
	{ "question": "観衆", "answers": [ "かんしゅう" ], "comment": "spectators; onlookers; members of the audience" },
	{ "question": "観賞", "answers": [ "かんしょう" ], "comment": "admiration; enjoyment" },
	{ "question": "角界", "answers": [ "かくかい", "かっかい" ], "comment": "the world of sumo" },
	{ "question": "角膜", "answers": [ "かくまく" ], "comment": "cornea" },
	{ "question": "解きほぐす", "answers": [ "ときほぐす" ], "comment": "to disentangle; to untangle; to unravel\nto relax; to soften; to relieve (e.g. stress, tension); to remove (e.g. doubt)" },
	{ "question": "解任", "answers": [ "かいにん" ], "comment": "dismissal" },
	{ "question": "解消", "answers": [ "かいしょう" ], "comment": "cancellation; liquidation; resolution; reduction (e.g. of stress)" },
	{ "question": "解熱", "answers": [ "げねつ" ], "comment": "lowering a fever; alleviation of fever" },
	{ "question": "解禁", "answers": [ "かいきん" ], "comment": "lifting a ban" },
	{ "question": "解読", "answers": [ "かいどく" ], "comment": "deciphering; decoding" },
	{ "question": "触れ合う", "answers": [ "ふれあう" ], "comment": "to come into contact with; to touch (each other); to have a brush with" },
	{ "question": "触媒", "answers": [ "しょくばい" ], "comment": "catalyst" },
	{ "question": "触発", "answers": [ "しょくはつ" ], "comment": "detonation by contact; contact detonation\ntouching off something; triggering; provocation; inspiration" },
	{ "question": "言い回し", "answers": [ "いいまわし" ], "comment": "expression; phraseology" },
	{ "question": "言い渡し", "answers": [ "いいわたし" ], "comment": "sentence; judgment; judgement; pronouncement; order; command" },
	{ "question": "言い渡す", "answers": [ "いいわたす" ], "comment": "to announce; to tell; to sentence; to order" },
	{ "question": "言い表す", "answers": [ "いいあらわす" ], "comment": "to express (in words)\nto confess" },
	{ "question": "言い表わす", "answers": [ "いいあらわす" ], "comment": "to express (in words)\nto confess" },
	{ "question": "言論", "answers": [ "げんろん" ], "comment": "(one's) speech; expression of views; discussion" },
	{ "question": "言質", "answers": [ "げんち" ], "comment": "commitment; pledge; promise" },
	{ "question": "計器", "answers": [ "けいき" ], "comment": "meter; gauge" },
	{ "question": "計測", "answers": [ "けいそく" ], "comment": "measurement; measure; instrumentation" },
	{ "question": "計量", "answers": [ "けいりょう" ], "comment": "measurement; computation\nmetric; measure" },
	{ "question": "討議", "answers": [ "とうぎ" ], "comment": "debate; discussion" },
	{ "question": "訓示", "answers": [ "くんじ" ], "comment": "instruction; direction" },
	{ "question": "訓読み", "answers": [ "くんよみ" ], "comment": "kun-yomi (Japanese reading of character)" },
	{ "question": "記帳", "answers": [ "きちょう" ], "comment": "registry; entry; book-keeping; signature" },
	{ "question": "訪れ", "answers": [ "おとずれ" ], "comment": "visit; call\narrival (e.g. of spring); advent; coming; appearance\nnews; tidings; word" },
	{ "question": "訪中", "answers": [ "ほうちゅう" ], "comment": "visit to China" },
	{ "question": "訪日", "answers": [ "ほうにち" ], "comment": "visit to Japan" },
	{ "question": "訪欧", "answers": [ "ほうおう" ], "comment": "visit to Europe" },
	{ "question": "訪米", "answers": [ "ほうべい" ], "comment": "visit to America" },
	{ "question": "設問", "answers": [ "せつもん" ], "comment": "posing a question\nquestion" },
	{ "question": "許諾", "answers": [ "きょだく" ], "comment": "consent" },
	{ "question": "訳者", "answers": [ "やくしゃ" ], "comment": "translator" },
	{ "question": "訴状", "answers": [ "そじょう" ], "comment": "petition; complaint; (legal) brief" },
	{ "question": "訴追", "answers": [ "そつい" ], "comment": "prosecution; indictment\nimpeachment" },
	{ "question": "証書", "answers": [ "しょうしょ" ], "comment": "bond; deed; certificate" },
	{ "question": "評", "answers": [ "ひょう" ], "comment": "criticism; commentary; a council" },
	{ "question": "評伝", "answers": [ "ひょうでん" ], "comment": "a critical biography" },
	{ "question": "評決", "answers": [ "ひょうけつ" ], "comment": "decision; verdict" },
	{ "question": "評議", "answers": [ "ひょうぎ" ], "comment": "conference; discussion" },
	{ "question": "試作", "answers": [ "しさく" ], "comment": "trial manufacture; experiment; test piece; prototype" },
	{ "question": "試写", "answers": [ "ししゃ" ], "comment": "preview; private showing" },
	{ "question": "試料", "answers": [ "しりょう" ], "comment": "sample; specimen; test piece" },
	{ "question": "試案", "answers": [ "しあん" ], "comment": "tentative plan; draft plan" },
	{ "question": "試算", "answers": [ "しさん" ], "comment": "trial calculation; preliminary calculation" },
	{ "question": "試練", "answers": [ "しれん" ], "comment": "test; trial; probation; ordeal; tribulation" },
	{ "question": "試薬", "answers": [ "しやく" ], "comment": "reagent" },
	{ "question": "試食", "answers": [ "ししょく" ], "comment": "sampling food" },
	{ "question": "詩歌", "answers": [ "しいか", "しか" ], "comment": "Japanese (and Chinese) poetry" },
	{ "question": "詩集", "answers": [ "ししゅう" ], "comment": "poetry anthology; collection of poems; collected poems" },
	{ "question": "話し声", "answers": [ "はなしごえ" ], "comment": "speaking voice; talking voice" },
	{ "question": "話し言葉", "answers": [ "はなしことば" ], "comment": "spoken language; colloquial expression" },
	{ "question": "話し込む", "answers": [ "はなしこむ" ], "comment": "to be deep in talk" },
	{ "question": "話込む", "answers": [ "はなしこむ" ], "comment": "to be deep in talk" },
	{ "question": "詳報", "answers": [ "しょうほう" ], "comment": "full report; particulars" },
	{ "question": "誇張", "answers": [ "こちょう" ], "comment": "exaggeration" },
	{ "question": "認め", "answers": [ "みとめ" ], "comment": "approval; final seal (of approval); acceptance" },
	{ "question": "認め印", "answers": [ "みとめいん" ], "comment": "private seal; personal seal; unregistered seal; informal seal; signet" },
	{ "question": "誓い", "answers": [ "ちかい" ], "comment": "oath; vow" },
	{ "question": "誓約", "answers": [ "せいやく" ], "comment": "written vow; pledge; covenant" },
	{ "question": "誘致", "answers": [ "ゆうち" ], "comment": "attraction; lure; invitation" },
	{ "question": "語らう", "answers": [ "かたらう" ], "comment": "to talk; to tell; to recite; to pledge; to conspire with" },
	{ "question": "語り", "answers": [ "かたり" ], "comment": "talk; recital\nnarration\ntopic" },
	{ "question": "語り口", "answers": [ "かたりくち" ], "comment": "way of reciting; way of telling a story" },
	{ "question": "語彙", "answers": [ "ごい" ], "comment": "vocabulary; lexicon; lexis; terminology" },
	{ "question": "語気", "answers": [ "ごき" ], "comment": "tone; manner of speaking" },
	{ "question": "誤字", "answers": [ "ごじ" ], "comment": "misprint; misspelling; typo; typographical error; erratum" },
	{ "question": "誤差", "answers": [ "ごさ" ], "comment": "measurement error; calculation error" },
	{ "question": "誤算", "answers": [ "ごさん" ], "comment": "miscalculation" },
	{ "question": "誤認", "answers": [ "ごにん" ], "comment": "misrecognition; mistaking (x for y)" },
	{ "question": "読み上げる", "answers": [ "よみあげる" ], "comment": "to read out loud (and clearly); to call a roll" },
	{ "question": "読み取り", "answers": [ "よみとり" ], "comment": "reading (e.g. by a scanner)" },
	{ "question": "読み書き", "answers": [ "よみかき" ], "comment": "reading and writing" },
	{ "question": "読み物", "answers": [ "よみもの" ], "comment": "reading matter; reading material" },
	{ "question": "課する", "answers": [ "かする" ], "comment": "to levy; to charge; to assess; to impose; to assign" },
	{ "question": "課員", "answers": [ "かいん" ], "comment": "section staff" },
	{ "question": "課目", "answers": [ "かもく" ], "comment": "(school) subject; curriculum; course" },
	{ "question": "調停", "answers": [ "ちょうてい" ], "comment": "arbitration; conciliation; mediation" },
	{ "question": "調印", "answers": [ "ちょういん" ], "comment": "signature; signing; sealing" },
	{ "question": "調教", "answers": [ "ちょうきょう" ], "comment": "training (animals); breaking (animals)" },
	{ "question": "調書", "answers": [ "ちょうしょ" ], "comment": "protocol; written evidence; record (investigation, interrogation, etc.); preliminary memo; charge sheet" },
	{ "question": "談合", "answers": [ "だんごう" ], "comment": "consultation; discussion; conference\ncollusion; bid-rigging" },
	{ "question": "談話", "answers": [ "だんわ" ], "comment": "a talk; conversation" },
	{ "question": "請け負う", "answers": [ "うけおう" ], "comment": "to contract; to undertake\nto take over; to take responsibility for" },
	{ "question": "請願", "answers": [ "せいがん" ], "comment": "petition" },
	{ "question": "論告", "answers": [ "ろんこく" ], "comment": "prosecutor's closing argument" },
	{ "question": "論外", "answers": [ "ろんがい" ], "comment": "out of the question" },
	{ "question": "論客", "answers": [ "ろんきゃく", "ろんかく" ], "comment": "controversialist" },
	{ "question": "論戦", "answers": [ "ろんせん" ], "comment": "verbal dispute" },
	{ "question": "論拠", "answers": [ "ろんきょ" ], "comment": "grounds of an argument" },
	{ "question": "論者", "answers": [ "ろんしゃ" ], "comment": "advocate" },
	{ "question": "論評", "answers": [ "ろんぴょう" ], "comment": "comment; criticism" },
	{ "question": "論説", "answers": [ "ろんせつ" ], "comment": "editorial; dissertation" },
	{ "question": "論調", "answers": [ "ろんちょう" ], "comment": "tenor or drift of an argument" },
	{ "question": "諮問", "answers": [ "しもん" ], "comment": "consultation; question; enquiry; inquiry" },
	{ "question": "講ずる", "answers": [ "こうずる" ], "comment": "to take measures; to work out a plan\nto lecture; to read aloud\nto confer" },
	{ "question": "講和", "answers": [ "こうわ" ], "comment": "reconciliation (between warring nations); (making of) peace" },
	{ "question": "謝意", "answers": [ "しゃい" ], "comment": "gratitude; thanks" },
	{ "question": "謝礼", "answers": [ "しゃれい" ], "comment": "reward; honorarium; remuneration" },
	{ "question": "謹慎", "answers": [ "きんしん" ], "comment": "self restraint; moderating one's behaviour; penitence; discipline\nconfinement to one's home; house arrest" },
	{ "question": "識者", "answers": [ "しきしゃ" ], "comment": "well-informed person; thinking person; intelligent person" },
	{ "question": "警報", "answers": [ "けいほう" ], "comment": "alarm; warning" },
	{ "question": "警護", "answers": [ "けいご" ], "comment": "bodyguard; escort" },
	{ "question": "警鐘", "answers": [ "けいしょう" ], "comment": "alarm bell; fire bell\nwarning; wake-up call" },
	{ "question": "議事", "answers": [ "ぎじ" ], "comment": "proceedings (e.g. parliament, congress); business (of the day)" },
	{ "question": "議場", "answers": [ "ぎじょう" ], "comment": "assembly hall; the House" },
	{ "question": "議席", "answers": [ "ぎせき" ], "comment": "parliamentary seat" },
	{ "question": "議案", "answers": [ "ぎあん" ], "comment": "legislative bill; measure\nagenda item" },
	{ "question": "議決", "answers": [ "ぎけつ" ], "comment": "resolution; decision; vote" },
	{ "question": "議院", "answers": [ "ぎいん" ], "comment": "parliament; congress; diet\nhouse (of parliament, etc.); chamber" },
	{ "question": "議題", "answers": [ "ぎだい" ], "comment": "topic of discussion; agenda" },
	{ "question": "譲り渡す", "answers": [ "ゆずりわたす" ], "comment": "to hand over; to turn over; to cede" },
	{ "question": "譲歩", "answers": [ "じょうほ" ], "comment": "concession; conciliation; compromise" },
	{ "question": "護国", "answers": [ "ごこく" ], "comment": "defense of one's country; defence of one's country" },
	{ "question": "護岸", "answers": [ "ごがん" ], "comment": "river dike" },
	{ "question": "護憲", "answers": [ "ごけん" ], "comment": "protecting the constitution" },
	{ "question": "護送", "answers": [ "ごそう" ], "comment": "escort (e.g. under guard); convoy" },
	{ "question": "谷川", "answers": [ "たにがわ" ], "comment": "mountain stream" },
	{ "question": "豊作", "answers": [ "ほうさく" ], "comment": "abundant harvest; bumper crop" },
	{ "question": "豊胸", "answers": [ "ほうきょう" ], "comment": "full breasts; ample breasts\nbreast enlargement" },
	{ "question": "象牙", "answers": [ "ぞうげ" ], "comment": "ivory" },
	{ "question": "豪快", "answers": [ "ごうかい" ], "comment": "hearty; exciting; stirring; lively; heroic; largehearted; splendid" },
	{ "question": "豪雨", "answers": [ "ごうう" ], "comment": "torrential rain; heavy rain; cloudburst; downpour" },
	{ "question": "貝殻", "answers": [ "かいがら" ], "comment": "seashell; shell" },
	{ "question": "負い目", "answers": [ "おいめ" ], "comment": "(feeling of) indebtedness; feeling obliged" },
	{ "question": "負かす", "answers": [ "まかす" ], "comment": "to defeat" },
	{ "question": "負け越し", "answers": [ "まけこし" ], "comment": "more losses than wins (sport)" },
	{ "question": "財界", "answers": [ "ざいかい" ], "comment": "financial world" },
	{ "question": "財閥", "answers": [ "ざいばつ" ], "comment": "zaibatsu; financial conglomerate; industrial group" },
	{ "question": "貧富", "answers": [ "ひんぷ" ], "comment": "wealth and poverty; rich and poor" },
	{ "question": "貧弱", "answers": [ "ひんじゃく" ], "comment": "poor; meagre; meager; insubstantial" },
	{ "question": "貧血", "answers": [ "ひんけつ" ], "comment": "anemia; anaemia" },
	{ "question": "貨車", "answers": [ "かしゃ" ], "comment": "freight car; van" },
	{ "question": "貪欲", "answers": [ "とんよく", "どんよく", "たんよく" ], "comment": "avarice; greed; covetousness\nraga (desire)" },
	{ "question": "貫", "answers": [ "かん" ], "comment": "kan (obs. unit of weight, approx. 3.75 kg, 8.3 lb)\nkan (obs. unit of currency)\npieces of sushi" },
	{ "question": "責務", "answers": [ "せきむ" ], "comment": "duty; obligation" },
	{ "question": "貯水", "answers": [ "ちょすい" ], "comment": "storage of water" },
	{ "question": "買い上げ", "answers": [ "かいあげ" ], "comment": "buying; purchasing; procurement" },
	{ "question": "買い付け", "answers": [ "かいつけ" ], "comment": "buying; purchasing" },
	{ "question": "買い入れ", "answers": [ "かいいれ" ], "comment": "buying; purchasing; laying in" },
	{ "question": "買い出し", "answers": [ "かいだし" ], "comment": "going out to shop; going shopping\nbuying in quantity; buying wholesale; bulk purchasing" },
	{ "question": "買い占め", "answers": [ "かいしめ" ], "comment": "buying up of goods; cornering (market)" },
	{ "question": "買い占める", "answers": [ "かいしめる" ], "comment": "to buy up" },
	{ "question": "買い取り", "answers": [ "かいとり" ], "comment": "purchase; buying; buying out\nbuying used articles as a company; trade-in; buy back\npurchase on a no-return policy\nlump-sum payment; flat fee" },
	{ "question": "買い得", "answers": [ "かいどく" ], "comment": "bargain; good buy" },
	{ "question": "買い戻し", "answers": [ "かいもどし" ], "comment": "repurchase; redemption" },
	{ "question": "買い手", "answers": [ "かいて" ], "comment": "buyer" },
	{ "question": "買取", "answers": [ "かいとり" ], "comment": "purchase; buying; buying out\nbuying used articles as a company; trade-in; buy back\npurchase on a no-return policy\nlump-sum payment; flat fee" },
	{ "question": "買手", "answers": [ "かいて" ], "comment": "buyer" },
	{ "question": "貸し出す", "answers": [ "かしだす" ], "comment": "to lend; to loan; to let out on hire" },
	{ "question": "貸し切り", "answers": [ "かしきり" ], "comment": "reserving; chartering; engaging; reservation" },
	{ "question": "貸与", "answers": [ "たいよ" ], "comment": "loan; lending" },
	{ "question": "貸切り", "answers": [ "かしきり" ], "comment": "reserving; chartering; engaging; reservation" },
	{ "question": "貸金", "answers": [ "かしきん" ], "comment": "loan; advance" },
	{ "question": "賃上げ", "answers": [ "ちんあげ" ], "comment": "wage increase" },
	{ "question": "賄賂", "answers": [ "わいろ" ], "comment": "bribe; sweetener; douceur" },
	{ "question": "資する", "answers": [ "しする" ], "comment": "to contribute; to play a part in; to have a hand in; to be conducive to; to be instrumental in\nto finance" },
	{ "question": "資材", "answers": [ "しざい" ], "comment": "(raw) material" },
	{ "question": "資格", "answers": [ "しかく" ], "comment": "qualifications; requirements; capabilities" },
	{ "question": "賓客", "answers": [ "ひんきゃく", "ひんかく" ], "comment": "guest of honour; guest of honor; privileged guest; visitor" },
	{ "question": "賛同", "answers": [ "さんどう" ], "comment": "approval; endorsement" },
	{ "question": "賛否", "answers": [ "さんぴ" ], "comment": "yes and no; for and against" },
	{ "question": "賛意", "answers": [ "さんい" ], "comment": "approval; assent" },
	{ "question": "賛歌", "answers": [ "さんか" ], "comment": "song of praise; eulogy; paean; hymn" },
	{ "question": "賛美", "answers": [ "さんび" ], "comment": "praise; adoration; glorification" },
	{ "question": "賛辞", "answers": [ "さんじ" ], "comment": "eulogy; compliment" },
	{ "question": "賞与", "answers": [ "しょうよ" ], "comment": "bonus\nreward; prize" },
	{ "question": "賞状", "answers": [ "しょうじょう" ], "comment": "honorable certificate; honourable certificate" },
	{ "question": "賞罰", "answers": [ "しょうばつ" ], "comment": "rewards and punishments" },
	{ "question": "賢人", "answers": [ "けんじん" ], "comment": "wise man" },
	{ "question": "質屋", "answers": [ "しちや" ], "comment": "pawnshop" },
	{ "question": "質疑", "answers": [ "しつぎ" ], "comment": "question\ninterpellation" },
	{ "question": "質的", "answers": [ "しつてき" ], "comment": "qualitative" },
	{ "question": "質素", "answers": [ "しっそ" ], "comment": "simple; plain\nmodest; frugal; reserved" },
	{ "question": "質量", "answers": [ "しつりょう" ], "comment": "mass" },
	{ "question": "賭け", "answers": [ "かけ" ], "comment": "betting; gambling; a gamble" },
	{ "question": "購読", "answers": [ "こうどく" ], "comment": "paid subscription (e.g. magazine)" },
	{ "question": "購買", "answers": [ "こうばい" ], "comment": "procurement; purchase; buying\nschool store; co-op; school canteen; tuck shop" },
	{ "question": "贈呈", "answers": [ "ぞうてい" ], "comment": "presentation (e.g. of a gift, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "贈答", "answers": [ "ぞうとう" ], "comment": "exchange of presents" },
	{ "question": "贈賄", "answers": [ "ぞうわい" ], "comment": "bribery; corruption; graft" },
	{ "question": "赤", "answers": [ "あか" ], "comment": "red; crimson; scarlet\nred-containing colour (e.g. brown, pink, orange)\nRed (i.e. communist)\nred light\nred ink (i.e. in finance or proof-reading); (in) the red\ncomplete; total; perfect; obvious\ncopper" },
	{ "question": "赤字", "answers": [ "あかじ" ], "comment": "deficit; (being in or going into) the red\nred text; red letters\ncorrections (by a teacher or proofreader) written in red" },
	{ "question": "赤旗", "answers": [ "あかはた" ], "comment": "red flag\nRed Flag (Communist Party newspaper)" },
	{ "question": "赤松", "answers": [ "あかまつ" ], "comment": "Japanese red pine (Pinus densiflora); Japanese umbrella pine; tanyosho pine" },
	{ "question": "赤色", "answers": [ "あかいろ", "せきしょく" ], "comment": "red; red color (colour)\nred-colored; red\ncommunism; the left" },
	{ "question": "赤軍", "answers": [ "せきぐん" ], "comment": "Red Army (Soviet Union, 1918-1946); Workers' and Peasants' Red Army" },
	{ "question": "赤面", "answers": [ "せきめん" ], "comment": "blushing; getting red in the face\nembarrassment" },
	{ "question": "赤飯", "answers": [ "せきはん" ], "comment": "red rice (beans and mochi) for auspicious occasions" },
	{ "question": "走塁", "answers": [ "そうるい" ], "comment": "base running" },
	{ "question": "走者", "answers": [ "そうしゃ" ], "comment": "runner\nbase runner" },
	{ "question": "起伏", "answers": [ "きふく" ], "comment": "undulation\nups and downs; highs and lows" },
	{ "question": "起債", "answers": [ "きさい" ], "comment": "issuing of bonds" },
	{ "question": "起因", "answers": [ "きいん" ], "comment": "cause; origin" },
	{ "question": "起工", "answers": [ "きこう" ], "comment": "setting to work" },
	{ "question": "起点", "answers": [ "きてん" ], "comment": "starting point; origin" },
	{ "question": "起爆", "answers": [ "きばく" ], "comment": "exploding" },
	{ "question": "起用", "answers": [ "きよう" ], "comment": "appointment (to a position, job, etc.); being used for a role; promotion" },
	{ "question": "起立", "answers": [ "きりつ" ], "comment": "standing up" },
	{ "question": "起草", "answers": [ "きそう" ], "comment": "drafting; draughting; drawing up a bill" },
	{ "question": "超越", "answers": [ "ちょうえつ" ], "comment": "transcendence; transcendency\ntranscendental\nto transcend; to rise above" },
	{ "question": "越冬", "answers": [ "えっとう" ], "comment": "passing the winter; hibernation" },
	{ "question": "越境", "answers": [ "えっきょう" ], "comment": "border transgression" },
	{ "question": "越年", "answers": [ "えつねん" ], "comment": "ring out the old year; hibernation" },
	{ "question": "趣向", "answers": [ "しゅこう" ], "comment": "plan; idea; design; plot" },
	{ "question": "足し算", "answers": [ "たしざん" ], "comment": "addition" },
	{ "question": "足並み", "answers": [ "あしなみ" ], "comment": "pace; step" },
	{ "question": "足場", "answers": [ "あしば" ], "comment": "scaffold; scaffolding\nfoothold; footing\nfoothold (e.g. in business); foundation; base\nconvenience for transportation; convenience of access (by road or rail)" },
	{ "question": "足掛かり", "answers": [ "あしがかり" ], "comment": "foothold" },
	{ "question": "足早", "answers": [ "あしばや" ], "comment": "quick-footed; light-footed; quick pace" },
	{ "question": "足腰", "answers": [ "あしこし" ], "comment": "legs and loins" },
	{ "question": "足踏み", "answers": [ "あしぶみ" ], "comment": "stepping; stamping; marking time (for a soldier)\nstandstill; stalemate" },
	{ "question": "路面", "answers": [ "ろめん" ], "comment": "road surface" },
	{ "question": "跳躍", "answers": [ "ちょうやく" ], "comment": "jump; leap; skip; bound" },
	{ "question": "踊り子", "answers": [ "おどりこ" ], "comment": "dancer (usu. female)" },
	{ "question": "踏み絵", "answers": [ "ふみえ" ], "comment": "tablet bearing Christian images, on which Edo-period authorities forced suspected Christians to trample" },
	{ "question": "踏ん張る", "answers": [ "ふんばる" ], "comment": "to brace one's legs; to straddle; to stand firm; to plant oneself (somewhere); to hold out; to persist" },
	{ "question": "躍動", "answers": [ "やくどう" ], "comment": "lively motion; throb" },
	{ "question": "躍起", "answers": [ "やっき" ], "comment": "desperation; eagerness" },
	{ "question": "躍進", "answers": [ "やくしん" ], "comment": "making rapid progress; making great advances; rush; dash; onslaught" },
	{ "question": "身なり", "answers": [ "みなり" ], "comment": "dress; attire; clothing; getup; outfit; personal appearance" },
	{ "question": "身の上", "answers": [ "みのうえ" ], "comment": "one's future; one's welfare; one's personal history" },
	{ "question": "身の回り", "answers": [ "みのまわり" ], "comment": "one's personal belongings; one's vicinity; one's daily life; everyday necessities" },
	{ "question": "身上", "answers": [ "しんじょう", "しんしょう" ], "comment": "merit; body; social position" },
	{ "question": "身代わり", "answers": [ "みがわり" ], "comment": "substitute (for); sacrifice (of, to); scapegoat (for)" },
	{ "question": "身寄り", "answers": [ "みより" ], "comment": "relative" },
	{ "question": "身投げ", "answers": [ "みなげ" ], "comment": "throwing oneself (e.g. into the water to commit suicide)" },
	{ "question": "身振り", "answers": [ "みぶり" ], "comment": "gesture; gesticulation; motion" },
	{ "question": "身柄", "answers": [ "みがら" ], "comment": "one's person" },
	{ "question": "身軽", "answers": [ "みがる" ], "comment": "agile; nimble; light (of foot)\ncasual (clothing); light (e.g. luggage)\ncarefree; with limited responsibility" },
	{ "question": "車中", "answers": [ "しゃちゅう" ], "comment": "in a train or vehicle" },
	{ "question": "車検", "answers": [ "しゃけん" ], "comment": "vehicle inspection" },
	{ "question": "車種", "answers": [ "しゃしゅ" ], "comment": "car make; car model" },
	{ "question": "車線", "answers": [ "しゃせん" ], "comment": "traffic lane; road lane" },
	{ "question": "車道", "answers": [ "しゃどう" ], "comment": "roadway" },
	{ "question": "軌跡", "answers": [ "きせき" ], "comment": "tire track\ntraces of a person or thing; path one has taken\nlocus" },
	{ "question": "軍備", "answers": [ "ぐんび" ], "comment": "armaments; military preparations" },
	{ "question": "軍兵", "answers": [ "ぐんびょう", "ぐんぺい", "ぐんぴょう" ], "comment": "armed forces; battle troops" },
	{ "question": "軍医", "answers": [ "ぐんい" ], "comment": "military physician or surgeon" },
	{ "question": "軍属", "answers": [ "ぐんぞく" ], "comment": "civilian in military employ" },
	{ "question": "軍拡", "answers": [ "ぐんかく" ], "comment": "military expansion; expansion of armaments" },
	{ "question": "軍政", "answers": [ "ぐんせい" ], "comment": "military government" },
	{ "question": "軍服", "answers": [ "ぐんぷく" ], "comment": "military or naval uniform" },
	{ "question": "軍用", "answers": [ "ぐんよう" ], "comment": "for military use" },
	{ "question": "軍縮", "answers": [ "ぐんしゅく" ], "comment": "disarmament; limitation of arms" },
	{ "question": "軍部", "answers": [ "ぐんぶ" ], "comment": "military authorities; army circles" },
	{ "question": "軍配", "answers": [ "ぐんばい" ], "comment": "gourd-shaped war fan\nreferee's fan\nstratagem; tactics" },
	{ "question": "軍需", "answers": [ "ぐんじゅ" ], "comment": "munitions; military stores" },
	{ "question": "軒並", "answers": [ "のきなみ" ], "comment": "row of houses; every door\ntotally; altogether; across the board" },
	{ "question": "軒並み", "answers": [ "のきなみ" ], "comment": "row of houses; every door\ntotally; altogether; across the board" },
	{ "question": "軟化", "answers": [ "なんか" ], "comment": "softening; mollification\nweakening (of the market)" },
	{ "question": "軟式", "answers": [ "なんしき" ], "comment": "soft (esp. of softball, tennis, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "軟禁", "answers": [ "なんきん" ], "comment": "house arrest" },
	{ "question": "転出", "answers": [ "てんしゅつ" ], "comment": "moving out; transfer" },
	{ "question": "転向", "answers": [ "てんこう" ], "comment": "conversion; shift; about-face; switch" },
	{ "question": "転売", "answers": [ "てんばい" ], "comment": "resale" },
	{ "question": "転嫁", "answers": [ "てんか" ], "comment": "imputation; shifting (e.g. blame, costs); passing the buck\nsecond marriage; remarriage" },
	{ "question": "転居", "answers": [ "てんきょ" ], "comment": "moving; changing residence" },
	{ "question": "転戦", "answers": [ "てんせん" ], "comment": "fighting in numerous battles" },
	{ "question": "転機", "answers": [ "てんき" ], "comment": "turning point" },
	{ "question": "転用", "answers": [ "てんよう" ], "comment": "diversion; putting something to another use" },
	{ "question": "転移", "answers": [ "てんい" ], "comment": "moving (location, with the times, etc.); change; transition\nmetastasis; spread\ntransition (e.g phase transition)\ntransfer (of learning)\ntransference (in psychoanalysis)" },
	{ "question": "転覆", "answers": [ "てんぷく" ], "comment": "capsizing; overturn; turning over; upset\noverthrow (e.g. a government)" },
	{ "question": "転身", "answers": [ "てんしん" ], "comment": "(job) turnover" },
	{ "question": "軽々", "answers": [ "かるがる" ], "comment": "lightly; easily; carelessly" },
	{ "question": "軽はずみ", "answers": [ "かるはずみ", "かろはずみ" ], "comment": "thoughtless; rash; hasty; imprudent" },
	{ "question": "軽やか", "answers": [ "かるやか", "かろやか" ], "comment": "light; easy; non-serious; minor" },
	{ "question": "軽傷", "answers": [ "けいしょう" ], "comment": "minor injury" },
	{ "question": "軽妙", "answers": [ "けいみょう" ], "comment": "light and easy; lambent; facile; clever; witty; smart" },
	{ "question": "軽快", "answers": [ "けいかい" ], "comment": "light (of movements); nimble; sprightly; springy\nlight-hearted; cheerful; buoyant; jaunty; casual (e.g. clothing); rhythmical (e.g. melody)\ntaking a turn for the better (of an illness); receding of symptoms; recovery; convalescence" },
	{ "question": "軽油", "answers": [ "けいゆ" ], "comment": "diesel oil; gas oil\nlight oil" },
	{ "question": "軽率", "answers": [ "けいそつ" ], "comment": "rash; thoughtless; careless; hasty; imprudent" },
	{ "question": "軽薄", "answers": [ "けいはく" ], "comment": "frivolous; flippant; superficial; trifling" },
	{ "question": "軽視", "answers": [ "けいし" ], "comment": "making light of; slight; ignore; neglect; contempt; disdain" },
	{ "question": "軽量", "answers": [ "けいりょう" ], "comment": "light weight" },
	{ "question": "輝かしい", "answers": [ "かがやかしい" ], "comment": "brilliant; glorious; glittering; bright; splendid (e.g. achievement, success); promising (e.g. future)" },
	{ "question": "輩出", "answers": [ "はいしゅつ" ], "comment": "turning out in great numbers; appearing one after the other" },
	{ "question": "輪切り", "answers": [ "わぎり" ], "comment": "round slices" },
	{ "question": "輸出入", "answers": [ "ゆしゅつにゅう" ], "comment": "export and import" },
	{ "question": "辛口", "answers": [ "からくち" ], "comment": "dry taste (e.g. sake, wine)\na liking for sake; one who likes sake\nsalty (taste)\nharsh; scathing" },
	{ "question": "辞す", "answers": [ "じす" ], "comment": "to excuse oneself; to take one's leave\nto quit; to resign; to retire; to leave post\nto decline; to turn down\nunhesitatingly" },
	{ "question": "辞令", "answers": [ "じれい" ], "comment": "notice of personnel change (appointment, dismissal, etc.)\nwording; choice of language; phraseology" },
	{ "question": "辞任", "answers": [ "じにん" ], "comment": "resignation (from a position)" },
	{ "question": "辞意", "answers": [ "じい" ], "comment": "intention to resign" },
	{ "question": "辞職", "answers": [ "じしょく" ], "comment": "resignation" },
	{ "question": "辞表", "answers": [ "じひょう" ], "comment": "letter of resignation" },
	{ "question": "辰", "answers": [ "たつ" ], "comment": "fifth sign of Chinese zodiac (The Dragon, 7am-9am, east-southeast, March)" },
	{ "question": "農協", "answers": [ "のうきょう" ], "comment": "agricultural cooperative" },
	{ "question": "農園", "answers": [ "のうえん" ], "comment": "plantation" },
	{ "question": "農場", "answers": [ "のうじょう" ], "comment": "farm (agriculture)" },
	{ "question": "農政", "answers": [ "のうせい" ], "comment": "agricultural administration" },
	{ "question": "農林", "answers": [ "のうりん" ], "comment": "agriculture and forestry" },
	{ "question": "農法", "answers": [ "のうほう" ], "comment": "farming methods" },
	{ "question": "農産", "answers": [ "のうさん" ], "comment": "agricultural products" },
	{ "question": "農相", "answers": [ "のうしょう" ], "comment": "Minister of Agriculture" },
	{ "question": "辺境", "answers": [ "へんきょう" ], "comment": "remote region; frontier (district); border(land)" },
	{ "question": "辻", "answers": [ "つじ" ], "comment": "intersection; crossing; crossroad; street corner; street" },
	{ "question": "迎撃", "answers": [ "げいげき" ], "comment": "intercept; interception; counter attack" },
	{ "question": "近づき", "answers": [ "ちかづき" ], "comment": "acquaintance" },
	{ "question": "近作", "answers": [ "きんさく" ], "comment": "recent work" },
	{ "question": "近日", "answers": [ "きんじつ" ], "comment": "soon; in a few days" },
	{ "question": "近況", "answers": [ "きんきょう" ], "comment": "recent state; present state; present condition; current status; current circumstances" },
	{ "question": "近海", "answers": [ "きんかい" ], "comment": "coastal waters; adjacent seas" },
	{ "question": "近眼", "answers": [ "ちかめ", "きんがん" ], "comment": "nearsightedness; shortsightedness; myopia" },
	{ "question": "近著", "answers": [ "きんちょ" ], "comment": "recent work" },
	{ "question": "近衛", "answers": [ "このえ" ], "comment": "Imperial Guards" },
	{ "question": "近視", "answers": [ "きんし" ], "comment": "myopia; shortsightedness; nearsightedness" },
	{ "question": "近親", "answers": [ "きんしん" ], "comment": "near relative" },
	{ "question": "近道", "answers": [ "ちかみち" ], "comment": "short way; shortcut" },
	{ "question": "返上", "answers": [ "へんじょう" ], "comment": "give up; relinquish; serve up; let loose" },
	{ "question": "返却", "answers": [ "へんきゃく" ], "comment": "return of something; repayment" },
	{ "question": "返品", "answers": [ "へんぴん" ], "comment": "returned goods; returning purchased goods" },
	{ "question": "迫害", "answers": [ "はくがい" ], "comment": "persecution; oppression" },
	{ "question": "迫撃", "answers": [ "はくげき" ], "comment": "close attack" },
	{ "question": "迷路", "answers": [ "めいろ" ], "comment": "maze; labyrinth; blind alley" },
	{ "question": "追い上げる", "answers": [ "おいあげる" ], "comment": "to gain on; to put pressure on; to close in on" },
	{ "question": "追い打ち", "answers": [ "おいうち" ], "comment": "final blow; attacking while pursuing; attacking the routed enemy" },
	{ "question": "追い抜く", "answers": [ "おいぬく" ], "comment": "to pass (a car); to overtake\nto surpass; to outstrip; to outdistance; to outsail" },
	{ "question": "追い込み", "answers": [ "おいこみ" ], "comment": "final stage; last spurt\nlive printing area (in publishing)" },
	{ "question": "追い風", "answers": [ "おいて", "おいかぜ" ], "comment": "tailwind; fair wind; favorable wind (favourable)\nfavorable condition (favourable); advantageous situation" },
	{ "question": "追っかけ", "answers": [ "おっかけ" ], "comment": "chase scene\ngroupie; paparazzo\nsoon; by-and-by" },
	{ "question": "追伸", "answers": [ "ついしん" ], "comment": "postscript; post scriptum; PS; P.S." },
	{ "question": "追徴", "answers": [ "ついちょう" ], "comment": "supplementary charge; additional collection" },
	{ "question": "追悼", "answers": [ "ついとう" ], "comment": "mourning (dead persons); memorial" },
	{ "question": "追撃", "answers": [ "ついげき" ], "comment": "pursuit" },
	{ "question": "追究", "answers": [ "ついきゅう" ], "comment": "investigation (e.g. academically, of the unknown); close inquiry (enquiry)" },
	{ "question": "追突", "answers": [ "ついとつ" ], "comment": "rear-end collision" },
	{ "question": "追随", "answers": [ "ついずい" ], "comment": "following (in the footsteps of)\ncatching up with; coming level with" },
	{ "question": "退任", "answers": [ "たいにん" ], "comment": "retirement; resignation; stepping down" },
	{ "question": "退去", "answers": [ "たいきょ" ], "comment": "departure; leaving; going away; evacuation\nrecession" },
	{ "question": "退団", "answers": [ "たいだん" ], "comment": "leaving a group or troupe" },
	{ "question": "退場", "answers": [ "たいじょう" ], "comment": "exit (from a stage); exeunt\nleaving; exit" },
	{ "question": "退学", "answers": [ "たいがく" ], "comment": "dropping out of school; withdrawing from school\nexpulsion from school; dismissal\nleaving school (university, etc.) after completing a course" },
	{ "question": "退官", "answers": [ "たいかん" ], "comment": "retirement from office" },
	{ "question": "退廃", "answers": [ "たいはい" ], "comment": "degeneration; decadence; deterioration; laxness; corruption" },
	{ "question": "退役", "answers": [ "たいえき" ], "comment": "retiring from military service" },
	{ "question": "退社", "answers": [ "たいしゃ" ], "comment": "resignation; leaving office\nleaving work (e.g. at the end of the day)" },
	{ "question": "退避", "answers": [ "たいひ" ], "comment": "taking refuge; evacuation\nsaving (a file)" },
	{ "question": "退陣", "answers": [ "たいじん" ], "comment": "retreat; withdrawal; retirement" },
	{ "question": "送り", "answers": [ "おくり" ], "comment": "seeing off; sending off\nfuneral\nescapement" },
	{ "question": "送り先", "answers": [ "おくりさき" ], "comment": "forwarding address" },
	{ "question": "送り出し", "answers": [ "おくりだし" ], "comment": "pushing (propelling) (one's opponent) out of the ring from behind" },
	{ "question": "送検", "answers": [ "そうけん" ], "comment": "sending the person accused to the prosecutor" },
	{ "question": "送球", "answers": [ "そうきゅう" ], "comment": "throwing a ball\nhandball" },
	{ "question": "送迎", "answers": [ "そうげい" ], "comment": "seeing off and meeting on return" },
	{ "question": "送還", "answers": [ "そうかん" ], "comment": "sending home; repatriation; deportation" },
	{ "question": "送電", "answers": [ "そうでん" ], "comment": "electric supply" },
	{ "question": "逃げ", "answers": [ "にげ" ], "comment": "escape; getaway; evasion" },
	{ "question": "逃げ足", "answers": [ "にげあし" ], "comment": "running away; escaping on foot" },
	{ "question": "逃げ道", "answers": [ "にげみち" ], "comment": "way out; means to escape; escape route" },
	{ "question": "逃走", "answers": [ "とうそう" ], "comment": "flight; desertion; escape" },
	{ "question": "逃避", "answers": [ "とうひ" ], "comment": "escape; evasion; flight" },
	{ "question": "逆しま", "answers": [ "さかしま" ], "comment": "reverse; inversion; upside down\nunreasonable; absurd; wrong" },
	{ "question": "逆境", "answers": [ "ぎゃっきょう" ], "comment": "adversity" },
	{ "question": "逆手", "answers": [ "さかて", "ぎゃくて" ], "comment": "underhand grip; backhand grip (e.g. in tennis)\nunexpected twist; turning the tables (on an opponent)" },
	{ "question": "逆立ち", "answers": [ "さかだち" ], "comment": "handstand; headstand" },
	{ "question": "逆襲", "answers": [ "ぎゃくしゅう" ], "comment": "counterattack" },
	{ "question": "逆風", "answers": [ "ぎゃくふう" ], "comment": "headwind; adverse wind" },
	{ "question": "透析", "answers": [ "とうせき" ], "comment": "dialysis" },
	{ "question": "逓信", "answers": [ "ていしん" ], "comment": "communications (e.g. post, tele.)" },
	{ "question": "通い", "answers": [ "かよい" ], "comment": "coming and going; commuting" },
	{ "question": "通し", "answers": [ "とおし" ], "comment": "direct; right through; straight\nappetizer; appetiser\nperformance of an entire play" },
	{ "question": "通例", "answers": [ "つうれい" ], "comment": "custom; general rule; convention\nusually; generally; as a rule" },
	{ "question": "通商", "answers": [ "つうしょう" ], "comment": "commerce; trade" },
	{ "question": "通年", "answers": [ "つうねん" ], "comment": "all year; year round" },
	{ "question": "通念", "answers": [ "つうねん" ], "comment": "common idea; common wisdom; generally accepted idea" },
	{ "question": "通算", "answers": [ "つうさん" ], "comment": "total" },
	{ "question": "通販", "answers": [ "つうはん" ], "comment": "mail order; online shopping; e-commerce" },
	{ "question": "通達", "answers": [ "つうだつ", "つうたつ" ], "comment": "notification; official notice; directive (e.g. from higher to lower levels of the administration)\nbeing well versed (in something)" },
	{ "question": "通関", "answers": [ "つうかん" ], "comment": "customs clearance" },
	{ "question": "速める", "answers": [ "はやめる" ], "comment": "to hasten; to quicken; to expedite; to precipitate; to accelerate" },
	{ "question": "速報", "answers": [ "そくほう" ], "comment": "news flash; prompt report; bulletin; quick announcement" },
	{ "question": "速攻", "answers": [ "そっこう" ], "comment": "swift attack; quick attack; fast break\nright away; without delay; immediately" },
	{ "question": "速球", "answers": [ "そっきゅう" ], "comment": "fastball" },
	{ "question": "造反", "answers": [ "ぞうはん" ], "comment": "rebellion" },
	{ "question": "造形", "answers": [ "ぞうけい" ], "comment": "molding; moulding; shaping; modelling (i.e. plastic arts); modeling" },
	{ "question": "造成", "answers": [ "ぞうせい" ], "comment": "creation; clearing; reclamation" },
	{ "question": "造語", "answers": [ "ぞうご" ], "comment": "coined word; coinage; neologism" },
	{ "question": "連ねる", "answers": [ "つらねる" ], "comment": "to line up; to put in a row\nto add (to a group); to accept (as a member of an organization, etc.); to join (e.g. a list)\nto link; to put together; to string together (e.g. compliments); to enumerate\nto take along with; to bring with" },
	{ "question": "連れ去る", "answers": [ "つれさる" ], "comment": "to take away; to kidnap" },
	{ "question": "連作", "answers": [ "れんさく" ], "comment": "planting a field with the same crop each year; repeated cultivation\ncollaborative literary work; story made up by several writers working on it in turn\nseries (of novels); cycle (of poems, songs); sequence" },
	{ "question": "連動", "answers": [ "れんどう" ], "comment": "operating together; working together; gearing; linkage\nlinked; coupled; interlocking" },
	{ "question": "連勝", "answers": [ "れんしょう" ], "comment": "consecutive victories; series of victories" },
	{ "question": "連名", "answers": [ "れんめい" ], "comment": "joint signature" },
	{ "question": "連峰", "answers": [ "れんぽう" ], "comment": "mountain range" },
	{ "question": "連座", "answers": [ "れんざ" ], "comment": "implicated (involved) in (a crime)" },
	{ "question": "連戦", "answers": [ "れんせん" ], "comment": "series of battles" },
	{ "question": "連打", "answers": [ "れんだ" ], "comment": "repeated blows; striking repeatedly; barrage\nconsecutive hits (e.g. boxing, baseball)" },
	{ "question": "連投", "answers": [ "れんとう" ], "comment": "pitching in consecutive games\nmaking multiple posts; posting multiple comments" },
	{ "question": "連敗", "answers": [ "れんぱい" ], "comment": "consecutive defeats; series of defeats" },
	{ "question": "連用", "answers": [ "れんよう" ], "comment": "continuous use" },
	{ "question": "連発", "answers": [ "れんぱつ" ], "comment": "running continuously; firing in rapid succession" },
	{ "question": "連立", "answers": [ "れんりつ" ], "comment": "alliance; coalition" },
	{ "question": "連行", "answers": [ "れんこう" ], "comment": "taking (a suspect to the police); dragging (someone) away" },
	{ "question": "連覇", "answers": [ "れんぱ" ], "comment": "successive championships" },
	{ "question": "連関", "answers": [ "れんかん" ], "comment": "connection; relation; linkage" },
	{ "question": "連隊", "answers": [ "れんたい" ], "comment": "regiment" },
	{ "question": "週休", "answers": [ "しゅうきゅう" ], "comment": "weekly holiday" },
	{ "question": "週明け", "answers": [ "しゅうあけ" ], "comment": "beginning of the week; new week opening; Monday" },
	{ "question": "進み", "answers": [ "すすみ" ], "comment": "progress" },
	{ "question": "進入", "answers": [ "しんにゅう" ], "comment": "entry; approach; penetration" },
	{ "question": "進撃", "answers": [ "しんげき" ], "comment": "advance; charge" },
	{ "question": "進攻", "answers": [ "しんこう" ], "comment": "attack; drive; advance; invasion" },
	{ "question": "進退", "answers": [ "しんたい" ], "comment": "movement; course of action; advance or retreat" },
	{ "question": "逸脱", "answers": [ "いつだつ" ], "comment": "deviation; departure\nomission" },
	{ "question": "遅々", "answers": [ "ちち" ], "comment": "slow; lagging; tardy" },
	{ "question": "遅らす", "answers": [ "おくらす" ], "comment": "to retard; to delay" },
	{ "question": "遅延", "answers": [ "ちえん" ], "comment": "delay; latency" },
	{ "question": "遊び場", "answers": [ "あそびば" ], "comment": "playground" },
	{ "question": "遊撃", "answers": [ "ゆうげき" ], "comment": "raid; military attack by a mobile unit; hit-and-run attack; search-and-kill mission; search-and-destroy mission; military action without a predetermined target; attacking the enemy or assisting allies as the opportunity arises\nshortstop; short" },
	{ "question": "遊歩", "answers": [ "ゆうほ" ], "comment": "walk; promenade" },
	{ "question": "遊牧", "answers": [ "ゆうぼく" ], "comment": "nomadism" },
	{ "question": "遊覧", "answers": [ "ゆうらん" ], "comment": "sightseeing" },
	{ "question": "遊説", "answers": [ "ゆうぜい" ], "comment": "election tour; election campaign; stumping" },
	{ "question": "運び", "answers": [ "はこび" ], "comment": "progress; pace; carriage; step; stage" },
	{ "question": "運休", "answers": [ "うんきゅう" ], "comment": "service suspended (e.g. trains)" },
	{ "question": "運航", "answers": [ "うんこう" ], "comment": "operating (e.g. ships, aircraft)" },
	{ "question": "運輸", "answers": [ "うんゆ" ], "comment": "transportation" },
	{ "question": "過労", "answers": [ "かろう" ], "comment": "overwork; strain" },
	{ "question": "過多", "answers": [ "かた" ], "comment": "excess; superabundance" },
	{ "question": "過大", "answers": [ "かだい" ], "comment": "excessive; too much; unreasonable" },
	{ "question": "過密", "answers": [ "かみつ" ], "comment": "overcrowding; crowded; congestion" },
	{ "question": "過度", "answers": [ "かど" ], "comment": "excess; immoderation" },
	{ "question": "過当", "answers": [ "かとう" ], "comment": "excessive; exorbitant" },
	{ "question": "過敏", "answers": [ "かびん" ], "comment": "nervousness; oversensitivity" },
	{ "question": "過渡", "answers": [ "かと" ], "comment": "crossing; ferry\ntransient\nchanging old to new" },
	{ "question": "過熱", "answers": [ "かねつ" ], "comment": "superheating; overheating" },
	{ "question": "過疎", "answers": [ "かそ" ], "comment": "depopulation" },
	{ "question": "過酷", "answers": [ "かこく" ], "comment": "severe; harsh; hard; cruel; rigorous" },
	{ "question": "道義", "answers": [ "どうぎ" ], "comment": "morality; moral principles" },
	{ "question": "道草", "answers": [ "みちくさ" ], "comment": "loitering on the way\nwayside grass" },
	{ "question": "達人", "answers": [ "たつじん" ], "comment": "master; expert" },
	{ "question": "達筆", "answers": [ "たっぴつ" ], "comment": "skillful writing; speedy writing" },
	{ "question": "達者", "answers": [ "たっしゃ" ], "comment": "in good health; healthy; well; robust; strong\nskilled; clever; proficient" },
	{ "question": "違憲", "answers": [ "いけん" ], "comment": "unconstitutionality" },
	{ "question": "遠山", "answers": [ "えんざん", "とおやま" ], "comment": "distant mountain" },
	{ "question": "遠征", "answers": [ "えんせい" ], "comment": "expedition; campaign; (performer's) tour\naway series" },
	{ "question": "遠隔", "answers": [ "えんかく" ], "comment": "distant; remote; isolated" },
	{ "question": "適宜", "answers": [ "てきぎ" ], "comment": "suitable; appropriate\nappropriately" },
	{ "question": "適性", "answers": [ "てきせい" ], "comment": "aptitude" },
	{ "question": "適時", "answers": [ "てきじ" ], "comment": "timely; opportune" },
	{ "question": "適格", "answers": [ "てきかく", "てっかく" ], "comment": "eligible; qualified; competent" },
	{ "question": "適法", "answers": [ "てきほう" ], "comment": "legality" },
	{ "question": "適量", "answers": [ "てきりょう" ], "comment": "proper quantity; proper dose; optimal dose" },
	{ "question": "適齢", "answers": [ "てきれい" ], "comment": "suitable age" },
	{ "question": "遭難", "answers": [ "そうなん" ], "comment": "disaster; shipwreck; accident; being stranded" },
	{ "question": "遷都", "answers": [ "せんと" ], "comment": "relocation of the capital; transfer of the capital" },
	{ "question": "選り分ける", "answers": [ "よりわける", "えりわける" ], "comment": "to classify; to sort out; to sift through" },
	{ "question": "選る", "answers": [ "よる", "すぐる", "える" ], "comment": "to choose; to select" },
	{ "question": "選任", "answers": [ "せんにん" ], "comment": "nomination (of a person to a position); selection; election; assignment; appointment" },
	{ "question": "選出", "answers": [ "せんしゅつ" ], "comment": "election; selection; choice" },
	{ "question": "選別", "answers": [ "せんべつ" ], "comment": "selection; classification; sorting; screening; triage" },
	{ "question": "選奨", "answers": [ "せんしょう" ], "comment": "recommendation" },
	{ "question": "選抜", "answers": [ "せんばつ" ], "comment": "selection; choice; picking out" },
	{ "question": "選考", "answers": [ "せんこう" ], "comment": "selection; screening" },
	{ "question": "選者", "answers": [ "せんじゃ" ], "comment": "judge; selector" },
	{ "question": "遺作", "answers": [ "いさく" ], "comment": "posthumous works" },
	{ "question": "遺児", "answers": [ "いじ" ], "comment": "orphan" },
	{ "question": "遺品", "answers": [ "いひん" ], "comment": "articles of the deceased; article left by the deceased; things that belonged to the deceased" },
	{ "question": "遺影", "answers": [ "いえい" ], "comment": "portrait of deceased person" },
	{ "question": "遺志", "answers": [ "いし" ], "comment": "dying wish" },
	{ "question": "遺憾", "answers": [ "いかん" ], "comment": "regrettable; unsatisfactory" },
	{ "question": "遺書", "answers": [ "いしょ" ], "comment": "note left by dead person; suicide note; testamentary letter; will; testament\nposthumous work" },
	{ "question": "遺棄", "answers": [ "いき" ], "comment": "abandonment; desertion" },
	{ "question": "遺構", "answers": [ "いこう" ], "comment": "remains" },
	{ "question": "遺物", "answers": [ "いぶつ" ], "comment": "relic; remains; memento" },
	{ "question": "遺骨", "answers": [ "いこつ" ], "comment": "remains; ashes of deceased" },
	{ "question": "避暑", "answers": [ "ひしょ" ], "comment": "summering; going to a summer resort" },
	{ "question": "還付", "answers": [ "かんぷ" ], "comment": "return; restoration; refund; (duty) drawback" },
	{ "question": "還暦", "answers": [ "かんれき" ], "comment": "60th birthday" },
	{ "question": "還流", "answers": [ "かんりゅう" ], "comment": "return current; convection; reflux" },
	{ "question": "邦人", "answers": [ "ほうじん" ], "comment": "Japanese national (esp. one living overseas)\nfellow countryman" },
	{ "question": "邦楽", "answers": [ "ほうがく" ], "comment": "Japanese music (esp. traditional Japanese music)" },
	{ "question": "邦画", "answers": [ "ほうが" ], "comment": "Japanese film\nJapanese painting" },
	{ "question": "邪", "answers": [ "よこしま" ], "comment": "wicked; evil" },
	{ "question": "邸宅", "answers": [ "ていたく" ], "comment": "mansion; residence" },
	{ "question": "郡部", "answers": [ "ぐんぶ" ], "comment": "rural districts; counties" },
	{ "question": "部会", "answers": [ "ぶかい" ], "comment": "section meeting" },
	{ "question": "部位", "answers": [ "ぶい" ], "comment": "part; position (in a whole, i.e. body)" },
	{ "question": "部内", "answers": [ "ぶない" ], "comment": "the staff; inside the department" },
	{ "question": "部員", "answers": [ "ぶいん" ], "comment": "staff; member (club, society, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "部局", "answers": [ "ぶきょく" ], "comment": "department; bureau; section; part" },
	{ "question": "部数", "answers": [ "ぶすう" ], "comment": "no. of copies; circulation" },
	{ "question": "郵貯", "answers": [ "ゆうちょ" ], "comment": "postal (post-office) savings (deposit)" },
	{ "question": "郷愁", "answers": [ "きょうしゅう" ], "comment": "nostalgia; homesickness" },
	{ "question": "都営", "answers": [ "とえい" ], "comment": "operated by the metropolitan government" },
	{ "question": "都庁", "answers": [ "とちょう" ], "comment": "Tokyo Government Office" },
	{ "question": "都政", "answers": [ "とせい" ], "comment": "the metropolitan government (of Tokyo)" },
	{ "question": "都民", "answers": [ "とみん" ], "comment": "city populace; resident of Tokyo" },
	{ "question": "都立", "answers": [ "とりつ" ], "comment": "metropolitan (i.e. established by the Tokyo Metropolitan Government)" },
	{ "question": "都議", "answers": [ "とぎ" ], "comment": "Metropolitan assemblyman" },
	{ "question": "配信", "answers": [ "はいしん" ], "comment": "distribution; delivery; transmission; provision" },
	{ "question": "配備", "answers": [ "はいび" ], "comment": "deploy; deployment" },
	{ "question": "配属", "answers": [ "はいぞく" ], "comment": "assignment (of a person to somewhere); attachment (of a person to another unit, organization, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "配役", "answers": [ "はいやく" ], "comment": "cast (of a play)" },
	{ "question": "配本", "answers": [ "はいほん" ], "comment": "distribution of books" },
	{ "question": "配球", "answers": [ "はいきゅう" ], "comment": "mixing of pitches" },
	{ "question": "配管", "answers": [ "はいかん" ], "comment": "plumbing; piping" },
	{ "question": "配給", "answers": [ "はいきゅう" ], "comment": "distribution (e.g. films, rice)\nrationing (e.g. food, gasoline)\nfood ration" },
	{ "question": "配線", "answers": [ "はいせん" ], "comment": "wiring" },
	{ "question": "配送", "answers": [ "はいそう" ], "comment": "delivery" },
	{ "question": "配電", "answers": [ "はいでん" ], "comment": "distribution of electricity" },
	{ "question": "酒屋", "answers": [ "さかや" ], "comment": "liquor store; wine shop; bottle shop\nsake dealer; liquor-store owner; brewer" },
	{ "question": "酒店", "answers": [ "さかだな", "さけてん", "しゅてん", "さかみせ" ], "comment": "alcohol-selling shop" },
	{ "question": "酒税", "answers": [ "しゅぜい" ], "comment": "liquor tax; tax on alcohol" },
	{ "question": "酒造", "answers": [ "しゅぞう" ], "comment": "sake brewing" },
	{ "question": "酒類", "answers": [ "しゅるい" ], "comment": "alcoholic drinks; liquor" },
	{ "question": "酪農", "answers": [ "らくのう" ], "comment": "dairy (farm)" },
	{ "question": "酵素", "answers": [ "こうそ" ], "comment": "enzyme" },
	{ "question": "酷", "answers": [ "こく" ], "comment": "severe; harsh; stringent; rigorous; strict; unfair" },
	{ "question": "酷似", "answers": [ "こくじ" ], "comment": "resemblance; resemble" },
	{ "question": "酸っぱい", "answers": [ "すっぱい" ], "comment": "sour; acid" },
	{ "question": "醜女", "answers": [ "しこめ", "しゅうじょ", "ぶおんな" ], "comment": "homely woman; plain-looking woman\nfemale demon" },
	{ "question": "醸成", "answers": [ "じょうせい" ], "comment": "brew; foment; breed" },
	{ "question": "醸造", "answers": [ "じょうぞう" ], "comment": "brewing; distillation" },
	{ "question": "釈放", "answers": [ "しゃくほう" ], "comment": "release; liberation; acquittal" },
	{ "question": "釈明", "answers": [ "しゃくめい" ], "comment": "explanation; vindication" },
	{ "question": "里子", "answers": [ "さとご" ], "comment": "foster child" },
	{ "question": "里帰り", "answers": [ "さとがえり" ], "comment": "returning home; visiting one's parents; new bride's first visit to parents" },
	{ "question": "里親", "answers": [ "さとおや" ], "comment": "foster parent; foster parents" },
	{ "question": "重き", "answers": [ "おもき" ], "comment": "importance; emphasis; stress" },
	{ "question": "重し", "answers": [ "おもし" ], "comment": "stone weight (as used on pickle-tub covers)\nweight (as used in balances)" },
	{ "question": "重る", "answers": [ "おもる" ], "comment": "to get heavy\nto worsen (of illness); to grow serious" },
	{ "question": "重傷", "answers": [ "おもで", "じゅうしょう" ], "comment": "serious wound; serious injury" },
	{ "question": "重厚", "answers": [ "じゅうこう", "ちょうこう" ], "comment": "profound; deep; grave; solid; dignified; stately; solemn; massive; composed" },
	{ "question": "重圧", "answers": [ "じゅうあつ" ], "comment": "strong pressure; heavy pressure" },
	{ "question": "重宝", "answers": [ "じゅうほう", "ちょうほう" ], "comment": "convenient; useful; handy; helpful\npriceless treasure\nvaluing highly; prizing" },
	{ "question": "重層", "answers": [ "じゅうそう" ], "comment": "multistoried; multilayered" },
	{ "question": "重度", "answers": [ "じゅうど" ], "comment": "heavy; severe" },
	{ "question": "重心", "answers": [ "じゅうしん" ], "comment": "centre of gravity (center)\ncentroid; barycenter\n(one's) balance" },
	{ "question": "重態", "answers": [ "じゅうたい" ], "comment": "seriously ill; serious condition; critical state" },
	{ "question": "重油", "answers": [ "じゅうゆ" ], "comment": "heavy oil; fuel oil" },
	{ "question": "重症", "answers": [ "じゅうしょう" ], "comment": "serious illness" },
	{ "question": "重荷", "answers": [ "じゅうか", "おもに" ], "comment": "load; heavy burden; encumbrance; heavy freight; heavy responsibility" },
	{ "question": "重責", "answers": [ "じゅうせき" ], "comment": "heavy responsibility" },
	{ "question": "重鎮", "answers": [ "じゅうちん" ], "comment": "leader; authority; mainstay" },
	{ "question": "野中", "answers": [ "のなか" ], "comment": "in the middle of a field" },
	{ "question": "野党", "answers": [ "やとう" ], "comment": "opposition party; political opposition; opposition" },
	{ "question": "野原", "answers": [ "のはら" ], "comment": "field" },
	{ "question": "野合", "answers": [ "やごう" ], "comment": "illicit union; collusion" },
	{ "question": "野外", "answers": [ "やがい" ], "comment": "outdoors; outside; open air\nfields; outskirts; suburbs" },
	{ "question": "野山", "answers": [ "のやま" ], "comment": "hills and fields; hill and dale" },
	{ "question": "野性", "answers": [ "やせい" ], "comment": "wildness (plants, animals, etc.); uncouth; rough; unpolished" },
	{ "question": "野手", "answers": [ "やしゅ" ], "comment": "fielder" },
	{ "question": "野放し", "answers": [ "のばなし" ], "comment": "leaving something to take care of itself" },
	{ "question": "野暮", "answers": [ "やぼ" ], "comment": "boorish; unsophisticated; unrefined; uncouth; tasteless; insensitive; thoughtless; dumb" },
	{ "question": "野望", "answers": [ "やぼう" ], "comment": "ambition; aspiration" },
	{ "question": "野末", "answers": [ "のずえ" ], "comment": "corners of a field" },
	{ "question": "野蛮", "answers": [ "やばん" ], "comment": "savage; uncivilized; uncivilised; barbarian" },
	{ "question": "野鳥", "answers": [ "やちょう" ], "comment": "wild bird" },
	{ "question": "量刑", "answers": [ "りょうけい" ], "comment": "judge's sentence; assessment of a case" },
	{ "question": "量産", "answers": [ "りょうさん" ], "comment": "mass production" },
	{ "question": "量的", "answers": [ "りょうてき" ], "comment": "quantitative" },
	{ "question": "金もうけ", "answers": [ "かねもうけ" ], "comment": "money-making" },
	{ "question": "金儲け", "answers": [ "かねもうけ" ], "comment": "money-making" },
	{ "question": "金具", "answers": [ "かなぐ" ], "comment": "metal fittings; metal fixtures" },
	{ "question": "金品", "answers": [ "きんぴん" ], "comment": "money and goods" },
	{ "question": "金子", "answers": [ "きんす" ], "comment": "money; funds" },
	{ "question": "金星", "answers": [ "きんぼし", "きんせい" ], "comment": "Venus (planet) /\n dazzling victory\nwin of a rank-and-file wrestler over the grand champion" },
	{ "question": "金権", "answers": [ "きんけん" ], "comment": "power of money; financial influence" },
	{ "question": "金石", "answers": [ "きんせき" ], "comment": "minerals and rocks; metal and stone utensils\nepigraph" },
	{ "question": "金網", "answers": [ "かなあみ" ], "comment": "wire netting; wire mesh; wire screen; chain-link mesh" },
	{ "question": "金脈", "answers": [ "きんみゃく" ], "comment": "vein of gold\nfinancial connections; patron; source of money" },
	{ "question": "金貨", "answers": [ "きんか" ], "comment": "gold coin" },
	{ "question": "釣り合い", "answers": [ "つりあい" ], "comment": "balance; equilibrium" },
	{ "question": "釣合", "answers": [ "つりあい" ], "comment": "balance; equilibrium" },
	{ "question": "釣合い", "answers": [ "つりあい" ], "comment": "balance; equilibrium" },
	{ "question": "鈍化", "answers": [ "どんか" ], "comment": "becoming dull; slowing down" },
	{ "question": "鈍感", "answers": [ "どんかん" ], "comment": "thickheaded; insensitive; dull; thick-skinned" },
	{ "question": "鉄工", "answers": [ "てっこう" ], "comment": "ironworking; ironworker" },
	{ "question": "鉄板", "answers": [ "てっぱん" ], "comment": "iron plate\nsure thing" },
	{ "question": "鉄棒", "answers": [ "てつぼう" ], "comment": "iron rod; iron bar; iron club\nhorizontal bar (gymnastics)" },
	{ "question": "鉄筋", "answers": [ "てっきん" ], "comment": "rebar; (concrete) iron reinforcing bar" },
	{ "question": "鉄製", "answers": [ "てっせい", "てつせい" ], "comment": "made from iron" },
	{ "question": "鉄鋼", "answers": [ "てっこう" ], "comment": "iron and steel" },
	{ "question": "鉄骨", "answers": [ "てっこつ" ], "comment": "steel frame; steel beam; steel girder" },
	{ "question": "鉛", "answers": [ "なまり" ], "comment": "lead (Pb)" },
	{ "question": "鉢植え", "answers": [ "はちうえ" ], "comment": "potted plant" },
	{ "question": "鉱区", "answers": [ "こうく" ], "comment": "mining area; mine lot" },
	{ "question": "鉱業", "answers": [ "こうぎょう" ], "comment": "mining industry" },
	{ "question": "銀河", "answers": [ "ぎんが" ], "comment": "Milky Way\ngalaxy" },
	{ "question": "銀紙", "answers": [ "ぎんがみ" ], "comment": "aluminum foil; aluminium foil; tinfoil; silver paper\nsilver-colored paper" },
	{ "question": "銀色", "answers": [ "ぎんいろ" ], "comment": "silver (color, colour)" },
	{ "question": "銃器", "answers": [ "じゅうき" ], "comment": "small arms" },
	{ "question": "銃声", "answers": [ "じゅうせい" ], "comment": "gunshot; (gun) report" },
	{ "question": "銃弾", "answers": [ "じゅうだん" ], "comment": "bullet (from a rifle)" },
	{ "question": "銃撃", "answers": [ "じゅうげき" ], "comment": "shooting; gunning (down)" },
	{ "question": "銅像", "answers": [ "どうぞう" ], "comment": "bronze statue" },
	{ "question": "銚子", "answers": [ "ちょうし" ], "comment": "(sake) decanter" },
	{ "question": "銭湯", "answers": [ "せんとう" ], "comment": "bath-house; public bath" },
	{ "question": "鋼", "answers": [ "はがね", "こう" ], "comment": "steel" },
	{ "question": "鋼材", "answers": [ "こうざい" ], "comment": "steel material" },
	{ "question": "鋼板", "answers": [ "こうばん", "こうはん" ], "comment": "steel sheet; steel plate; steel plates" },
	{ "question": "錆びる", "answers": [ "さびる" ], "comment": "to rust; to become rusty" },
	{ "question": "錦", "answers": [ "にしき" ], "comment": "brocade\nfine dress; fine clothes" },
	{ "question": "錨", "answers": [ "いかり" ], "comment": "anchor" },
	{ "question": "鎖国", "answers": [ "さこく" ], "comment": "national isolation; closing the country (to foreigners)\nsakoku; policy of national isolation enacted by the Tokugawa shogunate" },
	{ "question": "鎮まる", "answers": [ "しずまる" ], "comment": "to quieten down; to calm down; to subside; to die down; to abate; to be suppressed" },
	{ "question": "鎮圧", "answers": [ "ちんあつ" ], "comment": "suppression; subjugation" },
	{ "question": "鎮魂", "answers": [ "ちんごん", "ちんこん" ], "comment": "repose of souls" },
	{ "question": "長らく", "answers": [ "ながらく" ], "comment": "long; (for a) long time" },
	{ "question": "長唄", "answers": [ "ながうた" ], "comment": "long epic song with shamisen accompaniment (developed in Edo in the early 17th century)" },
	{ "question": "長大", "answers": [ "ちょうだい" ], "comment": "very long; great length" },
	{ "question": "長続き", "answers": [ "ながつづき" ], "comment": "permanence; continuation; long-lasting\nto last a long time; to continue; to keep at something for a long time" },
	{ "question": "長編", "answers": [ "ちょうへん" ], "comment": "long (e.g. novel, film)" },
	{ "question": "長者", "answers": [ "ちょうざ", "ちょうじゃ", "ちょうしゃ" ], "comment": "millionaire\none's superior; one's elder; one's senior\nvirtuous and gentle person\nfemale owner of a whorehouse in a post town\nchief of a post town" },
	{ "question": "長袖", "answers": [ "ながそで" ], "comment": "long sleeves" },
	{ "question": "長話", "answers": [ "ながばなし" ], "comment": "long talk" },
	{ "question": "長調", "answers": [ "ちょうちょう" ], "comment": "major key" },
	{ "question": "長身", "answers": [ "ちょうしん" ], "comment": "tall figure; high stature" },
	{ "question": "長雨", "answers": [ "ながあめ", "ながめ" ], "comment": "long spell of rain" },
	{ "question": "門下", "answers": [ "もんか" ], "comment": "one's pupil or student or follower" },
	{ "question": "門前", "answers": [ "もんぜん" ], "comment": "before a gate" },
	{ "question": "門戸", "answers": [ "もんこ" ], "comment": "door" },
	{ "question": "門扉", "answers": [ "もんぴ" ], "comment": "door(s) of a gate" },
	{ "question": "閉口", "answers": [ "へいこう" ], "comment": "dumbfounded; stumped; at one's wits' end; nonplussed\nannoyed" },
	{ "question": "閉幕", "answers": [ "へいまく" ], "comment": "falling of the curtain; coming to an end" },
	{ "question": "閉店", "answers": [ "へいてん" ], "comment": "closing up shop (for the day)\nstopping business; going out of business" },
	{ "question": "開き直る", "answers": [ "ひらきなおる" ], "comment": "to become defiant; to turn upon; to become serious" },
	{ "question": "開口", "answers": [ "かいこう" ], "comment": "opening; aperture (e.g. camera)\nopening one's mouth; beginning to speak\nopen; broad" },
	{ "question": "開国", "answers": [ "かいこく" ], "comment": "founding a country\nopening of a country (e.g. Japan) to the world" },
	{ "question": "開場", "answers": [ "かいじょう" ], "comment": "opening (the doors to an event, etc.)\ninauguration" },
	{ "question": "開局", "answers": [ "かいきょく" ], "comment": "opening of post-office or telephone exchange" },
	{ "question": "開幕", "answers": [ "かいまく" ], "comment": "raising the curtain\nopening (of an event); start of a season" },
	{ "question": "開店", "answers": [ "かいてん" ], "comment": "opening a new shop\nopening a shop (for the day)" },
	{ "question": "開戦", "answers": [ "かいせん" ], "comment": "outbreak of war; starting a war" },
	{ "question": "開校", "answers": [ "かいこう" ], "comment": "opening a school" },
	{ "question": "開港", "answers": [ "かいこう" ], "comment": "opening a port (seaport, airport, etc.); starting operations at a port\nopening a port to foreign vessels or trade" },
	{ "question": "開演", "answers": [ "かいえん" ], "comment": "curtain raising; starting (e.g. play, concert)" },
	{ "question": "開票", "answers": [ "かいひょう" ], "comment": "counting ballots; tally (of votes)" },
	{ "question": "開花", "answers": [ "かいか" ], "comment": "flowers budding; blooming; flowering\nshowing results; becoming popular; blooming" },
	{ "question": "開閉", "answers": [ "かいへい" ], "comment": "opening and shutting" },
	{ "question": "開館", "answers": [ "かいかん" ], "comment": "opening a hall for that day's business (museum, library, etc.)\nopening of new hall (museum, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "閏年", "answers": [ "うるうどし", "じゅんねん" ], "comment": "leap year" },
	{ "question": "閑散", "answers": [ "かんさん" ], "comment": "deserted (esp. store, market, town, streets); quiet; still; hushed; empty\ninactive (business, trade, etc.); slack; flat; off-season; quiet; dull\nidle; free; unoccupied" },
	{ "question": "間伐", "answers": [ "かんばつ" ], "comment": "periodic thinning (e.g. forest)" },
	{ "question": "間借り", "answers": [ "まがり" ], "comment": "renting a room" },
	{ "question": "間取り", "answers": [ "まどり" ], "comment": "plan of a house; arrangement of rooms; list of rooms in an apartment, excluding bathroom and toilet, encoded as a string of digits and letters (e.g. \"2DK\" for a two-room apartment with a kitchen/dining area)" },
	{ "question": "間口", "answers": [ "まぐち" ], "comment": "frontage" },
	{ "question": "間際", "answers": [ "まぎわ" ], "comment": "on the verge of; just before; on the point of" },
	{ "question": "間食", "answers": [ "かんしょく" ], "comment": "eating between meals; snacking" },
	{ "question": "関取", "answers": [ "せきとり" ], "comment": "ranking wrestler in the makuuchi (senior-grade) or juryo (junior-grade) divisions" },
	{ "question": "関知", "answers": [ "かんち" ], "comment": "concern; business" },
	{ "question": "関税", "answers": [ "かんぜい" ], "comment": "tariff (import tax); duty; customs" },
	{ "question": "関脇", "answers": [ "せきわけ" ], "comment": "wrestler of the third highest rank" },
	{ "question": "関門", "answers": [ "かんもん" ], "comment": "barrier; checkpoint; gateway\nhurdle; obstacle; trial" },
	{ "question": "閣僚", "answers": [ "かくりょう" ], "comment": "cabinet ministers" },
	{ "question": "閣内", "answers": [ "かくない" ], "comment": "(inside the) Cabinet" },
	{ "question": "閣議", "answers": [ "かくぎ" ], "comment": "cabinet meeting" },
	{ "question": "閾値", "answers": [ "いきち", "しきいち" ], "comment": "threshold (amount, dose, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "闘士", "answers": [ "とうし" ], "comment": "fighter (for); militant; champion (of); boxer" },
	{ "question": "闘志", "answers": [ "とうし" ], "comment": "fighting spirit; (will to) fight" },
	{ "question": "闘病", "answers": [ "とうびょう" ], "comment": "fighting against an illness" },
	{ "question": "防弾", "answers": [ "ぼうだん" ], "comment": "bulletproof; bombproof" },
	{ "question": "防戦", "answers": [ "ぼうせん" ], "comment": "defensive fight (battle)" },
	{ "question": "防水", "answers": [ "ぼうすい" ], "comment": "waterproofing; making watertight" },
	{ "question": "防火", "answers": [ "ぼうか" ], "comment": "fire prevention; fire fighting; fire proof" },
	{ "question": "防災", "answers": [ "ぼうさい" ], "comment": "disaster prevention" },
	{ "question": "防疫", "answers": [ "ぼうえき" ], "comment": "communicable disease control (e.g. by quarantine, disinfection, etc.); prevention of epidemics" },
	{ "question": "防空", "answers": [ "ぼうくう" ], "comment": "air defense; air defence" },
	{ "question": "防護", "answers": [ "ぼうご" ], "comment": "protection" },
	{ "question": "防音", "answers": [ "ぼうおん" ], "comment": "soundproof(ing)" },
	{ "question": "阻む", "answers": [ "はばむ" ], "comment": "to keep someone from doing; to stop; to prevent; to check; to hinder; to obstruct; to oppose; to thwart" },
	{ "question": "降参", "answers": [ "こうさん" ], "comment": "surrender; submission; capitulation\nbeing defeated (e.g. by a problem); giving up; giving in" },
	{ "question": "降板", "answers": [ "こうばん" ], "comment": "leaving the mound; being knocked out\nresigning from a role or position" },
	{ "question": "降格", "answers": [ "こうかく" ], "comment": "demotion" },
	{ "question": "降水", "answers": [ "こうすい" ], "comment": "rainfall; precipitation" },
	{ "question": "降雨", "answers": [ "こうう" ], "comment": "rainfall; rain" },
	{ "question": "降雪", "answers": [ "こうせつ" ], "comment": "snowfall; snow" },
	{ "question": "院内", "answers": [ "いんない" ], "comment": "inside the House (Diet)\ninside the hospital" },
	{ "question": "陣中", "answers": [ "じんちゅう" ], "comment": "in camp; at the front" },
	{ "question": "陣営", "answers": [ "じんえい" ], "comment": "camp (group of same ideological beliefs); faction (of political party)\nmilitary camp; encampment; cantonment" },
	{ "question": "陣地", "answers": [ "じんち" ], "comment": "encampment; position" },
	{ "question": "陣容", "answers": [ "じんよう" ], "comment": "battle formation; battle array\nlineup (of a team, etc.); cast; staff; team structure" },
	{ "question": "陣痛", "answers": [ "じんつう" ], "comment": "labour pains; labor pains; birth pains; contractions" },
	{ "question": "陣頭", "answers": [ "じんとう" ], "comment": "head of an army" },
	{ "question": "除名", "answers": [ "じょめい" ], "comment": "expulsion; excommunication" },
	{ "question": "除草", "answers": [ "じょそう" ], "comment": "weeding" },
	{ "question": "除菌", "answers": [ "じょきん" ], "comment": "bacteria elimination" },
	{ "question": "陥没", "answers": [ "かんぼつ" ], "comment": "cave-in; collapse; sinking; depression (e.g. of the skull); subsidence" },
	{ "question": "陥落", "answers": [ "かんらく" ], "comment": "fall; sinking; surrender; capitulation" },
	{ "question": "陪審", "answers": [ "ばいしん" ], "comment": "jury" },
	{ "question": "陰り", "answers": [ "かげり" ], "comment": "shadow or cloud (e.g. on someone's happiness); shade; gloom" },
	{ "question": "陰口", "answers": [ "かげぐち" ], "comment": "malicious gossip; backbiting; speaking ill behind someone's back" },
	{ "question": "陰気", "answers": [ "いんき" ], "comment": "gloomy; dismal; miserable; melancholy\nspirit of yin" },
	{ "question": "陰謀", "answers": [ "いんぼう" ], "comment": "plot; intrigue; scheme\nconspiracy; agreement between two or more people to commit an unlawful act" },
	{ "question": "陳列", "answers": [ "ちんれつ" ], "comment": "exhibition; display; putting on show" },
	{ "question": "陳情", "answers": [ "ちんじょう" ], "comment": "petition; appeal" },
	{ "question": "陳腐", "answers": [ "ちんぷ" ], "comment": "stale; hackneyed; cliched" },
	{ "question": "陳謝", "answers": [ "ちんしゃ" ], "comment": "apology" },
	{ "question": "陳述", "answers": [ "ちんじゅつ" ], "comment": "statement; declaration" },
	{ "question": "陵", "answers": [ "りょう", "みささぎ", "みはか" ], "comment": "imperial mausoleum; Emperor's tomb\nbig hill" },
	{ "question": "陶器", "answers": [ "とうき" ], "comment": "porcelain (esp. soft-paste porcelain); china; chinaware; earthenware; pottery; ceramics; crockery" },
	{ "question": "陶磁器", "answers": [ "とうじき" ], "comment": "porcelain; china; chinaware; ceramics; pottery" },
	{ "question": "陶芸", "answers": [ "とうげい" ], "comment": "ceramic art; ceramics" },
	{ "question": "陶酔", "answers": [ "とうすい" ], "comment": "intoxication" },
	{ "question": "陸橋", "answers": [ "りっきょう", "りくきょう" ], "comment": "viaduct; overhead bridge; overpass\nland bridge (biogeography)" },
	{ "question": "陸海", "answers": [ "りくかい" ], "comment": "land and sea" },
	{ "question": "陸路", "answers": [ "りくろ" ], "comment": "overland route; land route" },
	{ "question": "険悪", "answers": [ "けんあく" ], "comment": "dangerous; perilous; threatening; stormy; volatile; tense; critical; serious\nstern (expression); hostile (attitude); sharp; harsh" },
	{ "question": "陽", "answers": [ "ひ", "よう" ], "comment": "day; days\nsun; sunshine\nyang (i.e. the positive)\nthe open (i.e. a visible place)" },
	{ "question": "陽光", "answers": [ "ようこう" ], "comment": "sunshine; sunlight" },
	{ "question": "陽子", "answers": [ "ようし" ], "comment": "proton" },
	{ "question": "陽性", "answers": [ "ようせい" ], "comment": "positivity" },
	{ "question": "隅々", "answers": [ "すみずみ", "くまぐま" ], "comment": "nooks; corners" },
	{ "question": "隆盛", "answers": [ "りゅうせい" ], "comment": "prosperity; flourishing; thriving" },
	{ "question": "隊員", "answers": [ "たいいん" ], "comment": "troops; group members; team members" },
	{ "question": "随一", "answers": [ "ずいいち" ], "comment": "best; greatest; first" },
	{ "question": "随員", "answers": [ "ずいいん" ], "comment": "member of an entourage or retinue or party; attendant" },
	{ "question": "随所", "answers": [ "ずいしょ" ], "comment": "everywhere; at every turn" },
	{ "question": "随時", "answers": [ "ずいじ" ], "comment": "as needed; as occasion demands\nat any time" },
	{ "question": "隔たり", "answers": [ "へだたり" ], "comment": "distance; interval; gap; difference; estrangement" },
	{ "question": "隔て", "answers": [ "へだて" ], "comment": "partition; distinction" },
	{ "question": "隔月", "answers": [ "かくげつ" ], "comment": "every second month; every other month" },
	{ "question": "隔週", "answers": [ "かくしゅう" ], "comment": "every other week" },
	{ "question": "際会", "answers": [ "さいかい" ], "comment": "meeting; facing; confronting" },
	{ "question": "際限", "answers": [ "さいげん" ], "comment": "limits; end; bounds" },
	{ "question": "障る", "answers": [ "さわる" ], "comment": "to be harmful to; to hinder; to interfere with; to irritate" },
	{ "question": "障壁", "answers": [ "しょうへき" ], "comment": "enclosing wall; boundary fence\nobstacle; barrier" },
	{ "question": "隠滅", "answers": [ "えんめつ", "いんめつ" ], "comment": "destruction (esp. of evidence); spoliation; suppression\nhiding; concealment" },
	{ "question": "隣り合う", "answers": [ "となりあう" ], "comment": "to adjoin each other; to sit side by side" },
	{ "question": "隣り合わせ", "answers": [ "となりあわせ" ], "comment": "adjoining each other" },
	{ "question": "隣合う", "answers": [ "となりあう" ], "comment": "to adjoin each other; to sit side by side" },
	{ "question": "隣合わせ", "answers": [ "となりあわせ" ], "comment": "adjoining each other" },
	{ "question": "隣国", "answers": [ "りんごく", "りんこく" ], "comment": "neighbouring country; neighboring country; neighbouring state; neighboring state" },
	{ "question": "隣室", "answers": [ "りんしつ" ], "comment": "next or adjoining room" },
	{ "question": "隣家", "answers": [ "りんか" ], "comment": "neighbouring house; neighboring house" },
	{ "question": "雀", "answers": [ "すずめ" ], "comment": "tree sparrow (Passer montanus)\ntalkative person; knowledgeable person" },
	{ "question": "雄大", "answers": [ "ゆうだい" ], "comment": "grand; magnificent; majestic; great; sublime" },
	{ "question": "雄弁", "answers": [ "ゆうべん" ], "comment": "oratory; eloquence" },
	{ "question": "集い", "answers": [ "つどい" ], "comment": "meeting; get-together (e.g. among friends)" },
	{ "question": "集大成", "answers": [ "しゅうたいせい" ], "comment": "compilation; culmination; grand sum" },
	{ "question": "集散", "answers": [ "しゅうさん" ], "comment": "collection (gathering) and distribution" },
	{ "question": "集票", "answers": [ "しゅうひょう" ], "comment": "gathering votes" },
	{ "question": "集荷", "answers": [ "しゅうか" ], "comment": "collection of cargo (esp. produce, etc.); cargo booking" },
	{ "question": "集計", "answers": [ "しゅうけい" ], "comment": "totalization; totalisation; aggregation; tally (e.g. votes)" },
	{ "question": "雑居", "answers": [ "ざっきょ" ], "comment": "living together; mixed residence; sharing living quarters\nmulti-tenant; community" },
	{ "question": "雑煮", "answers": [ "ぞうに" ], "comment": "soup containing rice cakes and vegetables (New Year's dish)" },
	{ "question": "雑草", "answers": [ "ざっそう" ], "comment": "weed" },
	{ "question": "雑談", "answers": [ "ざつだん" ], "comment": "chatting; idle talk" },
	{ "question": "雑貨", "answers": [ "ざっか" ], "comment": "miscellaneous goods; general goods; sundries" },
	{ "question": "雑踏", "answers": [ "ざっとう" ], "comment": "hustle and bustle; throng; crowd; congestion; traffic jam" },
	{ "question": "離党", "answers": [ "りとう" ], "comment": "secession from a political party" },
	{ "question": "離反", "answers": [ "りはん" ], "comment": "estrangement; alienation; disaffection" },
	{ "question": "離宮", "answers": [ "りきゅう" ], "comment": "imperial villa; royal villa; detached palace" },
	{ "question": "離島", "answers": [ "りとう" ], "comment": "isolated island; outlying island\nleaving an island" },
	{ "question": "離散", "answers": [ "りさん" ], "comment": "dispersal; scattering\ndiscrete" },
	{ "question": "離着陸", "answers": [ "りちゃくりく" ], "comment": "takeoff and landing" },
	{ "question": "離職", "answers": [ "りしょく" ], "comment": "employment separation; leaving one's job; losing one's job" },
	{ "question": "離陸", "answers": [ "りりく" ], "comment": "takeoff" },
	{ "question": "難なく", "answers": [ "なんなく" ], "comment": "easily" },
	{ "question": "難問", "answers": [ "なんもん" ], "comment": "perplexity; difficult question; difficult problem" },
	{ "question": "難局", "answers": [ "なんきょく" ], "comment": "difficult situation" },
	{ "question": "難易", "answers": [ "なんい" ], "comment": "difficulty; relative difficulty" },
	{ "question": "難点", "answers": [ "なんてん" ], "comment": "fault; weakness" },
	{ "question": "難病", "answers": [ "なんびょう" ], "comment": "incurable disease" },
	{ "question": "難聴", "answers": [ "なんちょう" ], "comment": "hardness of hearing; bradyacusia; deafness" },
	{ "question": "難航", "answers": [ "なんこう" ], "comment": "difficult voyage; hard flight\nrough going; rough passage; running into trouble; stormy passage" },
	{ "question": "難色", "answers": [ "なんしょく" ], "comment": "disapproval" },
	{ "question": "難解", "answers": [ "なんかい" ], "comment": "difficult to understand; unintelligible; abstruse" },
	{ "question": "難関", "answers": [ "なんかん" ], "comment": "barrier; obstacle; difficulty; hurdle; deadlock" },
	{ "question": "難題", "answers": [ "なんだい" ], "comment": "difficult problem; challenge" },
	{ "question": "雨具", "answers": [ "あまぐ" ], "comment": "rain gear" },
	{ "question": "雨垂れ", "answers": [ "あまだれ" ], "comment": "raindrops (dripping from eaves, branches, etc.)\nexclamation point; exclamation mark" },
	{ "question": "雨天", "answers": [ "うてん" ], "comment": "rainy weather" },
	{ "question": "雨宿り", "answers": [ "あまやどり" ], "comment": "taking shelter from rain" },
	{ "question": "雨期", "answers": [ "うき" ], "comment": "rainy season" },
	{ "question": "雨水", "answers": [ "あまみず", "うすい" ], "comment": "rain water\n\"rain water\" solar term (approx. Feb 19)" },
	{ "question": "雨漏り", "answers": [ "あまもり" ], "comment": "roof leak" },
	{ "question": "雨量", "answers": [ "うりょう" ], "comment": "rainfall" },
	{ "question": "雨降り", "answers": [ "あめふり" ], "comment": "rainfall; rainy weather" },
	{ "question": "雪国", "answers": [ "ゆきぐに" ], "comment": "snow country" },
	{ "question": "雪崩", "answers": [ "なだれ" ], "comment": "avalanche; snowslide" },
	{ "question": "雪解け", "answers": [ "ゆきどけ" ], "comment": "snow thaw; thawing" },
	{ "question": "雪辱", "answers": [ "せつじょく" ], "comment": "vindication of honour; vindication of honor; making up for loss; revenge" },
	{ "question": "雲行き", "answers": [ "くもゆき" ], "comment": "weather; look of the sky\nsituation; turn of affairs; signs; way the wind is blowing" },
	{ "question": "零下", "answers": [ "れいか" ], "comment": "below zero; sub-zero" },
	{ "question": "零細", "answers": [ "れいさい" ], "comment": "insignificant; trifling; paltry; cottage (industry); tiny (company)" },
	{ "question": "雷雨", "answers": [ "らいう" ], "comment": "thunderstorm" },
	{ "question": "電信", "answers": [ "でんしん" ], "comment": "telegraph" },
	{ "question": "電光", "answers": [ "でんこう" ], "comment": "lightning" },
	{ "question": "電動", "answers": [ "でんどう" ], "comment": "electric" },
	{ "question": "電化", "answers": [ "でんか" ], "comment": "electrification" },
	{ "question": "電卓", "answers": [ "でんたく" ], "comment": "calculator (electronic)" },
	{ "question": "電器", "answers": [ "でんき" ], "comment": "electric (goods)" },
	{ "question": "電圧", "answers": [ "でんあつ" ], "comment": "voltage" },
	{ "question": "電撃", "answers": [ "でんげき" ], "comment": "electric shock\nblitz; lightning attack\nsudden and without warning; shocking" },
	{ "question": "電極", "answers": [ "でんきょく" ], "comment": "electrode" },
	{ "question": "電機", "answers": [ "でんき" ], "comment": "electrical machinery; appliances" },
	{ "question": "電線", "answers": [ "でんせん" ], "comment": "electric line; electric cable; power cable\ntelephone line; telegraph wire" },
	{ "question": "電鉄", "answers": [ "でんてつ" ], "comment": "electric railway" },
	{ "question": "需給", "answers": [ "じゅきゅう" ], "comment": "supply and demand" },
	{ "question": "震動", "answers": [ "しんどう" ], "comment": "shock; tremor; impact; vibration" },
	{ "question": "震度", "answers": [ "しんど" ], "comment": "seismic intensity" },
	{ "question": "震源", "answers": [ "しんげん" ], "comment": "hypocentre (of an earthquake); hypocenter" },
	{ "question": "霊園", "answers": [ "れいえん" ], "comment": "cemetery" },
	{ "question": "霧雨", "answers": [ "きりさめ" ], "comment": "drizzle; light rain" },
	{ "question": "露", "answers": [ "つゆ" ], "comment": "dew\ntears\n(not) a bit; (not) at all" },
	{ "question": "露店", "answers": [ "ろてん" ], "comment": "street stall; stand; booth" },
	{ "question": "青ざめる", "answers": [ "あおざめる" ], "comment": "to become pale; to turn pale" },
	{ "question": "青木", "answers": [ "あおき" ], "comment": "Japanese laurel; spotted laurel; Aucuba japonica\nlive tree" },
	{ "question": "青果", "answers": [ "せいか" ], "comment": "fruit(s) and vegetables; produce" },
	{ "question": "青柳", "answers": [ "あおやぎ", "あおやなぎ" ], "comment": "green willow (i.e. one that has budded)\nmeat of the trough shell (Mactra chinensis)" },
	{ "question": "青梅", "answers": [ "あおうめ" ], "comment": "unripe plum" },
	{ "question": "青空", "answers": [ "あおぞら" ], "comment": "blue sky" },
	{ "question": "青葉", "answers": [ "あおば" ], "comment": "fresh leaves" },
	{ "question": "青雲", "answers": [ "せいうん" ], "comment": "blue sky\nerudition; detachment from the world; high rank" },
	{ "question": "静けさ", "answers": [ "しずけさ" ], "comment": "stillness; silence; hush; calm; serenity" },
	{ "question": "静寂", "answers": [ "せいじゃく", "しじま" ], "comment": "silence; stillness; quietness" },
	{ "question": "静止", "answers": [ "せいし" ], "comment": "stillness; repose; standing still" },
	{ "question": "静粛", "answers": [ "せいしゅく" ], "comment": "silent" },
	{ "question": "静脈", "answers": [ "じょうみゃく" ], "comment": "vein" },
	{ "question": "静観", "answers": [ "せいかん" ], "comment": "watchful waiting; careful supervision" },
	{ "question": "静養", "answers": [ "せいよう" ], "comment": "(convalescent) rest" },
	{ "question": "非", "answers": [ "ひ" ], "comment": "fault; error; mistake\ngoing poorly; being disadvantageous; being unfavorable\nun-; non-; an-" },
	{ "question": "非行", "answers": [ "ひこう" ], "comment": "delinquency; misconduct" },
	{ "question": "面々", "answers": [ "めんめん" ], "comment": "each one; all; every direction" },
	{ "question": "面子", "answers": [ "メンツ" ], "comment": "face; honour; honor\ncombination of three tiles that form a set\npersonnel; members; lineup\nmaking up a four to play mahjong" },
	{ "question": "面持ち", "answers": [ "おももち" ], "comment": "expression; look; countenance; face" },
	{ "question": "面目", "answers": [ "めんもく", "めんぼく" ], "comment": "face; honour; honor; reputation; prestige; dignity; credit\nappearance; look" },
	{ "question": "面談", "answers": [ "めんだん" ], "comment": "interview" },
	{ "question": "面識", "answers": [ "めんしき" ], "comment": "acquaintance" },
	{ "question": "音色", "answers": [ "おんしょく", "ねいろ" ], "comment": "tone color; tone colour; tone quality; timbre\nsynthesizer patch; synthesiser patch" },
	{ "question": "音読", "answers": [ "おんどく" ], "comment": "reading aloud\non'yomi (adopted Chinese reading of a kanji)" },
	{ "question": "音読み", "answers": [ "おんよみ" ], "comment": "on (Chinese) reading of kanji" },
	{ "question": "音質", "answers": [ "おんしつ" ], "comment": "tone quality; sound quality" },
	{ "question": "音量", "answers": [ "おんりょう" ], "comment": "volume (sound)" },
	{ "question": "音響", "answers": [ "おんきょう" ], "comment": "sound; noise; echo; acoustics; audio" },
	{ "question": "音頭", "answers": [ "おんど" ], "comment": "leading a group of people; someone who leads others into a song by singing the leading notes\nworkmen's songs; marching songs" },
	{ "question": "頂", "answers": [ "いただき" ], "comment": "crown (of head); summit (of mountain); spire\neasy win for one\nsomething received" },
	{ "question": "順守", "answers": [ "じゅんしゅ" ], "comment": "compliance; adherence (to a set of rules); (religious) observance" },
	{ "question": "順当", "answers": [ "じゅんとう" ], "comment": "proper; right; reasonable" },
	{ "question": "順次", "answers": [ "じゅんじ" ], "comment": "in order; sequential; seriatim" },
	{ "question": "順路", "answers": [ "じゅんろ" ], "comment": "(regular) route" },
	{ "question": "預かり", "answers": [ "あずかり" ], "comment": "under custody; under supervision\nundecided match; draw; tie" },
	{ "question": "預かり証", "answers": [ "あずかりしょう" ], "comment": "claim check; baggage check; luggage check; deposit receipt" },
	{ "question": "預け入れる", "answers": [ "あずけいれる" ], "comment": "to make a deposit" },
	{ "question": "預託", "answers": [ "よたく" ], "comment": "depositing (of money, valuables, etc.); deposition" },
	{ "question": "預貯金", "answers": [ "よちょきん" ], "comment": "deposits and savings; bank account" },
	{ "question": "頑丈", "answers": [ "がんじょう" ], "comment": "solid; firm; stout; burly; strong; sturdy" },
	{ "question": "頑張り", "answers": [ "がんばり" ], "comment": "tenacity; endurance" },
	{ "question": "領内", "answers": [ "りょうない" ], "comment": "(within a) territory; domains" },
	{ "question": "領有", "answers": [ "りょうゆう" ], "comment": "possession (esp. of a territory)" },
	{ "question": "領海", "answers": [ "りょうかい" ], "comment": "territorial waters" },
	{ "question": "領空", "answers": [ "りょうくう" ], "comment": "territorial airspace" },
	{ "question": "領袖", "answers": [ "りょうしゅう" ], "comment": "leader; chief; boss" },
	{ "question": "頭取", "answers": [ "とうどり" ], "comment": "(bank) president\ngreenroom manager (in a theater)" },
	{ "question": "頭打ち", "answers": [ "ずうち", "あたまうち" ], "comment": "reaching a peak; reaching the limit; plateauing; maxing out" },
	{ "question": "頭角", "answers": [ "とうかく" ], "comment": "distinguishing oneself; standing out; top of the head" },
	{ "question": "頭金", "answers": [ "あたまきん" ], "comment": "down payment; deposit" },
	{ "question": "頭髪", "answers": [ "とうはつ" ], "comment": "hair (of head)" },
	{ "question": "頻発", "answers": [ "ひんぱつ" ], "comment": "frequency; frequent occurrence" },
	{ "question": "題字", "answers": [ "だいじ" ], "comment": "letters in a title" },
	{ "question": "額面", "answers": [ "がくめん" ], "comment": "face value; par" },
	{ "question": "顔なじみ", "answers": [ "かおなじみ" ], "comment": "acquaintance; friend; familiar face" },
	{ "question": "顔ぶれ", "answers": [ "かおぶれ" ], "comment": "personnel; members; lineup (of a team); roster; cast (of a play)\nannouncement of next day's match-ups" },
	{ "question": "顔合わせ", "answers": [ "かおあわせ" ], "comment": "meeting together; introduction" },
	{ "question": "顔触れ", "answers": [ "かおぶれ" ], "comment": "personnel; members; lineup (of a team); roster; cast (of a play)\nannouncement of next day's match-ups" },
	{ "question": "顔負け", "answers": [ "かおまけ" ], "comment": "feeling embarrassed; being put to shame; bowing to" },
	{ "question": "顕在", "answers": [ "けんざい" ], "comment": "actual (as opposed to hidden or obscured); obvious; clear; manifest; explicit; overt; apparent; evident; actualized; actualised" },
	{ "question": "顕彰", "answers": [ "けんしょう" ], "comment": "honouring (publicly); honoring; making someone's good deeds or achievements well-known" },
	{ "question": "願", "answers": [ "がん" ], "comment": "prayer; wish; vow" },
	{ "question": "願書", "answers": [ "がんしょ" ], "comment": "written application or petition; application form" },
	{ "question": "類推", "answers": [ "るいすい" ], "comment": "analogy\nanalogical reasoning; analogical inference" },
	{ "question": "顧問", "answers": [ "こもん" ], "comment": "adviser; advisor; consultant" },
	{ "question": "風上", "answers": [ "かざかみ" ], "comment": "windward; upwind" },
	{ "question": "風下", "answers": [ "かざしも" ], "comment": "leeward; lee; downwind" },
	{ "question": "風刺", "answers": [ "ふうし" ], "comment": "satire; irony; sarcasm" },
	{ "question": "風力", "answers": [ "ふうりょく" ], "comment": "wind power\nforce (level on the Beaufort wind speed scale)" },
	{ "question": "風向き", "answers": [ "かぜむき", "かざむき" ], "comment": "wind's direction" },
	{ "question": "風呂場", "answers": [ "ふろば" ], "comment": "bathroom" },
	{ "question": "風呂屋", "answers": [ "ふろや" ], "comment": "public bathhouse\nbathhouse proprietor" },
	{ "question": "風味", "answers": [ "ふうみ" ], "comment": "taste; flavor; flavour" },
	{ "question": "風当たり", "answers": [ "かぜあたり" ], "comment": "exposure to wind\nsevere criticism" },
	{ "question": "風格", "answers": [ "ふうかく" ], "comment": "personality; style; appearance" },
	{ "question": "風流", "answers": [ "ふうりゅう" ], "comment": "elegance; taste; refinement" },
	{ "question": "風穴", "answers": [ "かぜあな", "かざあな" ], "comment": "air hole; windhole; ventilator" },
	{ "question": "風通し", "answers": [ "かざとおし", "かぜとおし" ], "comment": "ventilation\ncommunication (within an organisation); openness" },
	{ "question": "風速", "answers": [ "ふうそく" ], "comment": "wind speed" },
	{ "question": "風邪薬", "answers": [ "かぜぐすり", "かざぐすり" ], "comment": "remedy for a cold; cold medicine" },
	{ "question": "風鈴", "answers": [ "ふうりん" ], "comment": "wind chime; wind bell" },
	{ "question": "飛ばし", "answers": [ "とばし" ], "comment": "selling or divesting in unwanted stocks; hiding bad loans" },
	{ "question": "飛び交う", "answers": [ "とびかう" ], "comment": "to fly about; to flutter about; to flit about; to fly past each other" },
	{ "question": "飛び出し", "answers": [ "とびだし" ], "comment": "something that leaps or thrusts out" },
	{ "question": "飛び地", "answers": [ "とびち" ], "comment": "scattered landholdings; detached land; enclave; exclave" },
	{ "question": "飛び火", "answers": [ "とびひ" ], "comment": "leaping flames; shower of flying sparks\nspreading fire\nrepercussions in unanticipated areas; spilling over; effects of an incident spreading to those seemingly uninvolved\nimpetigo contagiosa" },
	{ "question": "飛び込み", "answers": [ "とびこみ" ], "comment": "jump; plunge; dive\nappearing without an appointment; bursting in; arriving unannounced; cropping up suddenly" },
	{ "question": "飛球", "answers": [ "ひきゅう" ], "comment": "fly (ball)" },
	{ "question": "飛車", "answers": [ "ひしゃ" ], "comment": "rook" },
	{ "question": "食い下がる", "answers": [ "くいさがる" ], "comment": "to hang on to; to hang from; to cling to\nto hound; to keep after (someone); to refuse to back down; to persist; to tenaciously face (someone); to doggedly oppose\nto grab the front of the opponent's mawashi, place one's head against their chest, and lower one's hips" },
	{ "question": "食い止める", "answers": [ "くいとめる" ], "comment": "to check; to hold back" },
	{ "question": "食い込む", "answers": [ "くいこむ" ], "comment": "to bite into (e.g. rope into skin); to cut into; to dig into (e.g. of fingernails)\nto eat into; to encroach; to make inroads; to penetrate (e.g. a market); to break into (e.g. first place); to erode; to cut into (e.g. time, savings)\nto be wedged (i.e. underwear pulled from the back, driving it between the buttocks)" },
	{ "question": "食い違い", "answers": [ "くいちがい" ], "comment": "discrepancy; different or conflicting opinions" },
	{ "question": "食い違う", "answers": [ "くいちがう" ], "comment": "to cross each other; to run counter to; to differ; to clash; to go awry" },
	{ "question": "食べ歩き", "answers": [ "たべあるき" ], "comment": "trying the food at various restaurants; eating tour\nwalking while eating; eating while walking" },
	{ "question": "食み出す", "answers": [ "はみだす" ], "comment": "to protrude; to stick out; to hang out; to jut out; to bulge out; to overflow; to be forced out; to be crowded out; to be pushed out; to exceed; to go over; to go beyond" },
	{ "question": "食後", "answers": [ "しょくご" ], "comment": "after a meal" },
	{ "question": "食止める", "answers": [ "くいとめる" ], "comment": "to check; to hold back" },
	{ "question": "食用", "answers": [ "しょくよう" ], "comment": "for use as food; edible" },
	{ "question": "食肉", "answers": [ "しょくにく" ], "comment": "meat (for consumption)" },
	{ "question": "食費", "answers": [ "しょくひ" ], "comment": "food expense" },
	{ "question": "食道", "answers": [ "しょくどう" ], "comment": "esophagus; gullet; esophageal" },
	{ "question": "食違い", "answers": [ "くいちがい" ], "comment": "discrepancy; different or conflicting opinions" },
	{ "question": "食違う", "answers": [ "くいちがう" ], "comment": "to cross each other; to run counter to; to differ; to clash; to go awry" },
	{ "question": "飢え", "answers": [ "うえ" ], "comment": "hunger; starvation" },
	{ "question": "飢え死に", "answers": [ "かつえじに", "うえじに" ], "comment": "(death from) starvation; starving to death" },
	{ "question": "飢餓", "answers": [ "きが" ], "comment": "starvation; famine; hunger" },
	{ "question": "飢饉", "answers": [ "ききん" ], "comment": "famine; drought; shortage; crop failure" },
	{ "question": "飲み水", "answers": [ "のみみず" ], "comment": "drinking water; potable water" },
	{ "question": "飲酒", "answers": [ "いんしゅ" ], "comment": "drinking alcohol (sake)" },
	{ "question": "飼料", "answers": [ "しりょう" ], "comment": "fodder; feed" },
	{ "question": "飽き", "answers": [ "あき" ], "comment": "weariness; tiresomeness" },
	{ "question": "飽和", "answers": [ "ほうわ" ], "comment": "saturation" },
	{ "question": "飽食", "answers": [ "ほうしょく" ], "comment": "gluttony; satiation; engorgement" },
	{ "question": "餃子", "answers": [ "チャオズ", "ぎょうざ", "ギョーザ" ], "comment": "gyoza; pot sticker; crescent-shaped pan-fried dumplings stuffed with minced pork and vegetables" },
	{ "question": "養殖", "answers": [ "ようしょく" ], "comment": "aquaculture (e.g. fish, shellfish, seaweed); culture (e.g. pearls); raising; cultivation" },
	{ "question": "養父", "answers": [ "ようふ" ], "comment": "foster father; adoptive father" },
	{ "question": "養父母", "answers": [ "ようふぼ" ], "comment": "adoptive parents" },
	{ "question": "養老", "answers": [ "ようろう" ], "comment": "making provision for the elderly\nYourou era (717.11.17-724.2.4)" },
	{ "question": "養護", "answers": [ "ようご" ], "comment": "nursing; (protective) care" },
	{ "question": "餓死", "answers": [ "がし" ], "comment": "(death from) starvation; starving to death" },
	{ "question": "館内", "answers": [ "かんない" ], "comment": "in the building" },
	{ "question": "館長", "answers": [ "かんちょう" ], "comment": "superintendent; director; curator; chief librarian" },
	{ "question": "首位", "answers": [ "しゅい" ], "comment": "first place; head position; leading position" },
	{ "question": "首唱", "answers": [ "しゅしょう" ], "comment": "advocacy; promotion" },
	{ "question": "首席", "answers": [ "しゅせき" ], "comment": "head; chief\nchairman; governor; president\ntop student; head of the class\ntop seat; first desk (in orchestra)" },
	{ "question": "首班", "answers": [ "しゅはん" ], "comment": "head; leader; prime minister" },
	{ "question": "首謀", "answers": [ "しゅぼう" ], "comment": "plotting; planning (crime, intrigue)\nringleader; mastermind; leader (of a plot)" },
	{ "question": "首領", "answers": [ "しゅりょう" ], "comment": "head; chief; boss; leader" },
	{ "question": "香ばしい", "answers": [ "こうばしい" ], "comment": "fragrant; aromatic; sweet-smelling\nsavory (smelling); savoury" },
	{ "question": "香る", "answers": [ "かおる" ], "comment": "to smell sweet; to be fragrant" },
	{ "question": "馬主", "answers": [ "ばぬし", "ばしゅ", "うまぬし" ], "comment": "(race)horse owner" },
	{ "question": "馬券", "answers": [ "ばけん" ], "comment": "(horse racing) betting ticket" },
	{ "question": "馬場", "answers": [ "ばば" ], "comment": "horse-riding ground" },
	{ "question": "馴れ馴れしい", "answers": [ "なれなれしい" ], "comment": "over-familiar" },
	{ "question": "駅伝", "answers": [ "えきでん" ], "comment": "long-distance relay race\nstagecoach; post horse" },
	{ "question": "駅員", "answers": [ "えきいん" ], "comment": "station attendant" },
	{ "question": "駅弁", "answers": [ "えきべん" ], "comment": "boxed lunch bought at a station (often a local specialty)\nvariety of sexual position" },
	{ "question": "駅長", "answers": [ "えきちょう" ], "comment": "station master" },
	{ "question": "駆け引き", "answers": [ "かけひき" ], "comment": "bargaining; haggling\ntactics; strategy" },
	{ "question": "駆け足", "answers": [ "かけあし" ], "comment": "running fast; double time\ncantering\ndoing things in a hurry" },
	{ "question": "駆け込み", "answers": [ "かけこみ" ], "comment": "last-minute rush; stampede" },
	{ "question": "駆動", "answers": [ "くどう" ], "comment": "driving force" },
	{ "question": "駐屯", "answers": [ "ちゅうとん" ], "comment": "stationing (troops); occupancy" },
	{ "question": "駐日", "answers": [ "ちゅうにち" ], "comment": "resident in Japan" },
	{ "question": "駐留", "answers": [ "ちゅうりゅう" ], "comment": "stationing (e.g. of troops); garrison" },
	{ "question": "騎手", "answers": [ "きしゅ" ], "comment": "horseman; rider" },
	{ "question": "騎馬", "answers": [ "きば" ], "comment": "horse riding; horseback riding; horseback rider" },
	{ "question": "騒乱", "answers": [ "そうらん" ], "comment": "disturbance; riot; mayhem" },
	{ "question": "騒然", "answers": [ "そうぜん" ], "comment": "noisy; confused; uproarious" },
	{ "question": "騰貴", "answers": [ "とうき" ], "comment": "rise (in price or value); inflation; appreciation (economic)" },
	{ "question": "驚異", "answers": [ "きょうい" ], "comment": "wonder; miracle; amazement; prodigy" },
	{ "question": "骨子", "answers": [ "こっし" ], "comment": "main point; gist; essentials; bones (e.g. of an idea); pith" },
	{ "question": "骨抜き", "answers": [ "ほねぬき" ], "comment": "boned (e.g. fish, etc.)\nwatered down (e.g. plan, bill, etc.); mutilated\nlacking integrity or moral backbone" },
	{ "question": "骨格", "answers": [ "こっかく" ], "comment": "skeleton; skeletal structure; build; frame; physique\nframework" },
	{ "question": "骨髄", "answers": [ "こつずい" ], "comment": "bone marrow; medulla\ntrue spirit; one's mind" },
	{ "question": "骸骨", "answers": [ "がいこつ" ], "comment": "skeleton" },
	{ "question": "高", "answers": [ "だか", "たか" ], "comment": "quantity; amount; volume; number; amount of money" },
	{ "question": "高まり", "answers": [ "たかまり" ], "comment": "rise; swell; elevation; upsurge" },
	{ "question": "高らか", "answers": [ "たからか" ], "comment": "loud; sonorous; ringing" },
	{ "question": "高位", "answers": [ "こうい" ], "comment": "dignity; eminent; high ranking\nhigh-order (digit, bit, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "高低", "answers": [ "こうてい", "たかひく" ], "comment": "high and low; rise and fall" },
	{ "question": "高値", "answers": [ "たかね" ], "comment": "high price" },
	{ "question": "高卒", "answers": [ "こうそつ" ], "comment": "high school graduate" },
	{ "question": "高台", "answers": [ "たかだい" ], "comment": "elevation; high ground" },
	{ "question": "高名", "answers": [ "こうみょう", "こうめい" ], "comment": "fame; renown" },
	{ "question": "高圧", "answers": [ "こうあつ" ], "comment": "high voltage; high pressure" },
	{ "question": "高地", "answers": [ "こうち" ], "comment": "high ground; plateau; heights" },
	{ "question": "高官", "answers": [ "こうかん" ], "comment": "high official" },
	{ "question": "高山", "answers": [ "こうざん" ], "comment": "high mountain; alpine" },
	{ "question": "高所", "answers": [ "こうしょ" ], "comment": "high altitude; heights; elevation\nbroad view" },
	{ "question": "高架", "answers": [ "こうか" ], "comment": "overhead structure" },
	{ "question": "高波", "answers": [ "たかなみ" ], "comment": "high waves" },
	{ "question": "高瀬", "answers": [ "たかせ" ], "comment": "shallow river; shallows\nflatboat; river boat" },
	{ "question": "高炉", "answers": [ "こうろ" ], "comment": "blast furnace" },
	{ "question": "高熱", "answers": [ "こうねつ" ], "comment": "high fever\npyro-" },
	{ "question": "高率", "answers": [ "こうりつ" ], "comment": "high rate" },
	{ "question": "高給", "answers": [ "こうきゅう" ], "comment": "high salary" },
	{ "question": "高裁", "answers": [ "こうさい" ], "comment": "High Court" },
	{ "question": "高見", "answers": [ "こうけん" ], "comment": "watching with detachment" },
	{ "question": "高音", "answers": [ "こうおん", "たかね" ], "comment": "high-pitched tone; soprano" },
	{ "question": "高騰", "answers": [ "こうとう" ], "comment": "sudden price jump; steep price rise" },
	{ "question": "鬼神", "answers": [ "きしん", "おにがみ", "きじん" ], "comment": "fierce god" },
	{ "question": "魅了", "answers": [ "みりょう" ], "comment": "fascination\nto charm; to fascinate; to mesmerize" },
	{ "question": "魅惑", "answers": [ "みわく" ], "comment": "attraction; fascination; lure; captivation; charm" },
	{ "question": "魔術", "answers": [ "まじゅつ" ], "comment": "black magic; sorcery\nmagic tricks; juggling" },
	{ "question": "魚類", "answers": [ "ぎょるい" ], "comment": "fish; fishes" },
	{ "question": "鮮度", "answers": [ "せんど" ], "comment": "(degree of) freshness" },
	{ "question": "鮮烈", "answers": [ "せんれつ" ], "comment": "vivid; striking" },
	{ "question": "鮮魚", "answers": [ "せんぎょ" ], "comment": "fresh fish" },
	{ "question": "鳥居", "answers": [ "とりい" ], "comment": "torii; Shinto shrine archway" },
	{ "question": "鳥獣", "answers": [ "ちょうじゅう" ], "comment": "birds and wild animals; wildlife" },
	{ "question": "鳥類", "answers": [ "ちょうるい" ], "comment": "birds" },
	{ "question": "鳴り", "answers": [ "なり" ], "comment": "ringing; sound" },
	{ "question": "鶏肉", "answers": [ "けいにく", "とりにく" ], "comment": "chicken meat" },
	{ "question": "鶴", "answers": [ "つる", "たず" ], "comment": "crane (any bird of the family Gruidae, esp. the red-crowned crane, Grus japonensis)" },
	{ "question": "麹", "answers": [ "こうじ" ], "comment": "mould grown on rice, barley, beans, etc. as a starter to make sake, miso, soy sauce, etc. (mold); malted rice; malt" },
	{ "question": "麻", "answers": [ "あさ" ], "comment": "cannabis (Cannabis sativa); hemp (plant)\nhemp (fiber); linen; flax; jute" },
	{ "question": "麻布", "answers": [ "あさぬの", "まふ" ], "comment": "hemp cloth; linen" },
	{ "question": "黄昏", "answers": [ "たそがれ", "こうこん" ], "comment": "dusk; twilight\ntwilight years\nmelancholia; melancholic nostalgia" },
	{ "question": "黄金", "answers": [ "こがね", "おうごん" ], "comment": "gold" },
	{ "question": "黒字", "answers": [ "くろじ" ], "comment": "balance (figure) in the black" },
	{ "question": "黒幕", "answers": [ "くろまく" ], "comment": "black curtain\nwire puller; mastermind; political fixer; power broker" },
	{ "question": "黒星", "answers": [ "くろぼし" ], "comment": "black spot; black dot; bull's-eye\nfailure mark" },
	{ "question": "黒木", "answers": [ "くろき" ], "comment": "unbarked lumber" },
	{ "question": "黒潮", "answers": [ "くろしお" ], "comment": "Japan Current; Kuroshio Current" },
	{ "question": "黒煙", "answers": [ "こくえん", "くろけむり" ], "comment": "black smoke" },
	{ "question": "黒色", "answers": [ "こくしょく" ], "comment": "black (colour, color)" },
	{ "question": "黒衣", "answers": [ "こくえ", "くろぎぬ", "こくい" ], "comment": "black clothes" },
	{ "question": "黒鉛", "answers": [ "こくえん" ], "comment": "graphite" },
	{ "question": "黙祷", "answers": [ "もくとう" ], "comment": "silent prayer" },
	{ "question": "鼻息", "answers": [ "びそく", "はないき" ], "comment": "nasal breathing\nperson's pleasure; excitement" },
	{ "question": "鼻水", "answers": [ "はなみず" ], "comment": "nasal mucus; dripping nose; snot" },
	{ "question": "鼻紙", "answers": [ "はながみ" ], "comment": "tissue paper; facial tissue; paper handkerchief" },
	{ "question": "齢", "answers": [ "よわい" ], "comment": "(one's) age" }
]
}
